the phone can't answer is provided under a Creative Commons licence your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of mit courses visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
so we have a organise three lectures and the basic idea of the lectures
to cover some of the major current issues in nuclear arms control and non-proliferation ok
we have a the first lecture today on India and Pakistan which is one of the world's apart
flashpoints meaning that this desert there's a a path to a possible nuclear war
which I won't go into the bin Nerang will certainly spell out the case but in my view intro
I said want to talk about this was a golden opportunity because phippen is here and he's an expert on these issues
send a I consider this as I say one of the possible flashpoints in the world one of the possible conceivable pets
path is super likely if you want to put it that way but the effects of a nuclear exchange a catastrophic both
the people who get hit obviously because a nuclear weapon I don't have to tell you is incredibly destructive in Hiroshima
something like 40% of the population was killed more or less instantly Burns or blas and probably another 20
percent died within a year of radiation so in addition people have realised that there are severe climate
effects of a nuclear exchange one of things that happens with all the burning that goes on is that suit is
medi into the atmosphere this is the opposite of global warming this is global cooling this is like a volcanic
explosion and in about 18 15th 1816 it was a volcanic explosion in Asia
there was a winter without there was a summer excuse me there was a summer without crops in Europe ok
actually starvation in Europe due to this explosion was a one-time thing or the climate models
even a limited nuclear war in Southeast Asia are showed that this effect would probably last 5 to 10 years
Global ok from roughly 100 nuclear weapon so there are papers I can give people references if they want
there's a paper in physics today A few years ago about this but there are many papers on the subject so one of the things
they say so the second lecture will be on on the proliferation and and uranium enrichment
the implication so these lectures will combine both technology and policy and finally the last lecture I will give an
sign of an overview of where we stand on nuclear arms control and proliferation I'll try to fill in some of the gaps I'll talk about the non-proliferation
you that's coming up at the UN next spring I've talked about the outlook for arms control as I see it ok
I want to talk a few minutes to the students because one of the things that's happened over the last few
since the collapse of the Soviet Union in about 1990 people stop worrying about the bond so
speak before that there was a lot of concern still the for ask the duck under their desks and things like that
back themselves which class was totally ridiculous wooden desk would enjoy him but she could and that nuclear war
you can well in that picture
but are the issue was kind of fallen off the table and the thing that concerns p
war on campus when if they think about Global issues is climate change and global warming ok but this is an issue with
has not gone away if anything the probability of of a nuclear exchange is higher now than a decade ago
watching it Wayne and we have not solve these problems and there are political and economic problems
I want to see a few words about some of the intellectual problems that need to be sold for example on a technical base
where there are inspection issues ok for example how do you inspect whether and
country is cheating on its 94 liberation obligations you look for weapons production or in Richmond
this is a very difficult issues OK and they're very difficult technical issues so and then there are issues in which
you have to combined technical issues with policy for example if we're going to go down to a very small number of weapons as you want to do
nuclear arms control then are cheating with a small number particularly if you're gonna go to 0
what's a small number becomes a bigger issue so verification issues a very important reinventing the bomb you know if you really want
so they're all kinds of intellectual issues that need to be worked out ok both historical Technic
and political and there are many opportunities for research in these areas ok your ups and faeces so I just
point that out and they're also positions in in government and ngo's in the last semester we had several major on
trough negotiators from the US government including Rose got me all the who was the chief Negotiator on the US side
for the new start reading said she was particularly excited to give a talk and mit because we really needed a journal
technically train people to go into nuclear arms control and she made a special plea so I want to pay us that along
so I'm going to get to today's lecture VIP in Nerang is a
in the MIT political science department and and the security studies program he's got a BS and Ms
chemical engineering he's got a degree from Bali or College where I spent it very happy semester and ask her
and he's written extensively on non-proliferation and an issues of
Iams control the tolerance in particularly with respect the Southeast Asia and he's got a a book recently pub
regional powers and international conflict so vipin great thanks thanks for the kind introduction and organise
so Sarah said I'm a person the political science department and it was primarily a nuclear Strata simple operation and so
what I thought I do today was talk about giving an overview of nuclear proliferation and the consequences of proliferation
South Asia between India and Pakistan which is Aaron mentioned an active an ongoing conflict with a thread of conventional war is persistent
are there periodic military crazies between India and Pakistan that put both countries of the risk of commercial conflict
every now and then and now they're both sides both States have nuclear weapons the question is what the likelihood of escalation the nuclear level is
just as a preview of my own thinking I'm in writing on the subject I think India and Pakistan have so far been lucky Inn
can a commercial conflict is not yet escalated to the nuclear level but that's not a foregone conclusion going for a little bit about that and it's one of the reasons where the still act
arms racing between India and Pakistan and so we'll talk a little bit about that and what the dynamics have been with the nucleus strategies and with the effects on
distance between India and Pakistan are there any questions that all electric don't hesitate to start me another diverse backgrounds 0 people from different departments undergraduate graduate
old go through some basic theoretical material first if that's if everybody is no
with that we can move that pretty quickly and talk about India and Pakistan in the process of building up their delivery systems
the nuclear arsenal this is a picture of a shaggy missile which is the Pakistani long it's a medium range ballistic missile in the Pakistani inventory and it's based off of 8
export missile the M class exports and both are actively testing short and long-range cruise and
metals as their inventories are growing and that is one of the concerns I think as we are talking about the basic puzzle though is
does anyone know what these pictures are from so in November and November 26th 2008 two weeks before my wife and I got married and tell you actually
a group nominally sponsored and based in Pakistan the luxury Tiber orchestrated and a pretty
c-based see launch attack against Bombay were about 12 it doesn't militants lead by the one survivor from the militant group
America's kasab pictured here siege the Taj hotel hotel
chabad house in Bombay and killed over 170 Indians and westerners and the Indian government was faced with the
in about how to respond to this is the third private patient that the Indian government believe was sponsored by Pakistan in the since 1988 the year in with a test nuclear weapons
and the the question facing Union leaders how do we respond to a state that sponsors militant attacks against The Metropole or metre
targets are hotels in a financial centre when they have nuclear weapons and so the warrior then it was a new weapons had in bold and
find a sponsor these groups for a perpetrating more daring and ID say tax against India and because Pakistan have nuclear weapons India didn't have a
Skeletor reaction Pakistan for these attacks and still didn't government for a deck it has been trying to deal with what they believe is a policy paralysis
about dealing with the Pakistan that is more willing to support militant organisations to attack India now that has nuclear weapons
brief outline of the basic deterrence there and political science and economics the core of nuclear strategy both in the Cold War and
is deterrence Theory so hopefully it's not too basic I don't need to talk about the basic physics ideas will go through a really briefly some of the choices States have
in had the operation eyes are so it's really important india-pakistan context of the causes of and the process of nucleation South Asia how and why in Deer Park
why nuclear weapons and then I close all the consequences and where we are today focusing mostly on the period since 99 May 9th
yeah it is the breakpoint in India Pakistan nuclear equation that's when India led by the den BJP government testing nuclear weapons Fallout 3
the Pakistani government the definition of definition
inspired by Gaslight I'm selling Herman Miller with stretchy this will be familiar to rates to basic 2
any context is trying to preserve the status quo by threatening unacceptable cost to an opponent an adversary if they do x write some specified action
you do x I will do y and the ideas we preserve the status quo in the idea is that why the punishment that you impose on your avatar opponent
should I be greater than the benefits of them achieving whatever their objectives is x such that they order
reminder taking the action examples with children so I haven't eaten much also myself and his staff
Stan things and you know one as children get all the rated turns into turns by punishment example that I'm telling you
if you if your child does in a something something bad you punish them by saying the room deny them dinner time out right so the
punishment after the fact if they do eggs in another example is if you if you hit me I will
tell your mother there is a there's a putative aspect to the detergent threats such that the punishment
the benefit of whatever an average of Jackie would be that it was before we were going
Armin Target thorough nuclear forces to make it impossible for them to carry out their first strike so in a in a case for somebody is attacking me at the turnstile
that would be a set of killing your mother and take your time off so you can attack me and presumably the cost of cutting your arm off so you cannot achieve your objectives in the First
is efficient to deter you from undertaking it right so I think about this determined by punishment we will we will punish you with such a vehicle
after you undertake the action such that you you have no incentive rash on sent it to do so vs we will ratchet
past while you try to achieve the objectives such that you won't be able to in the first place so it's an important Distinction we think in the even in the
are there to get from the Cold War the Distinction was counter Forest vs counter value right so for those the mirror Cold War nuclear strategy when we surrender Target Silvia
other economic or industrial capacity that was largely determined by punishment strategy so in the event that they launched a conventional or a first nuclear
we would retaliate against our cities the alternative wasn't it was a big role in The Cold War in a case of a commercial complex we would
nuclear weapons are there nuclear weapons such that they were not have the ability to launch those weapons at the United States or it's allies so the deterrence Theory
several basic requirements call them the three c's right so you need to have the capability to impose the threat the your prime
read so if you if you're threatening to destroy an adversary cities and even the do something you need to have the cave
we need some explosive capability because it most important in the nucleus and need a delivery capability nibabel hit their cities write an essay
to the to the average Siri I need to be credible right and this term credibility in the concept of credibility as
mod cold war strategy and still dogs new strategy today right credibility is the hardest part of this how could you threaten what was
catamount mutual suicide and have incredible by every right so in the event of you know so in the
Cold War Began example is if the Soviet Union took West Berlin was it really credible did you know
threaten lunch hundreds of nuclear weapons at the Soviet Soviet cities the Soviet Union probably didn't think so right and so undeterred by
deterrence by denial trade-off which one do you think is more credible in the case where an attack is coming out as more credible threat to kill their mother and response
Watercraft alarm what is an attacker more likely to believe it is it is disproportionate to threaten certain pewter
and so it is often more credible in this is where the trade-off between the debate early in the Cold War about two turns determined by punishment
on the credibility differences between the two that determines Biden I seem to be more credible the Avatar is more likely to believe that you would try to stop them from achieving their objectives
millions of an innocent civilian as I had nothing to do with the fight in the first place after something
so the important it was the that the size of the US Arsenal made it possible threat in both
but they were I think there are many strategies to believe that the two turns by tonight on Nations were still more credible to the adversary but at the heart of deterrence is a social credibility
and authority is communication the adversary needs to know that you have the capability and credibility to threaten the punishment or deter
nail threat that you that then you may have to make a threat it has to be published the average he has to know what the threat is the average I need to know what
objective your lightly rolling a red line down for and that you have the capability to inflict the punishment that you threaten so there's a huge
Bering Sea that is required for a deterrent to operate Dr Strangelove the movie what's the problem with the doomsday machine in
Strangelove is a great line what's the point of a Doomsday machine if you don't tell anybody about it for everybody that the Aborigines to know that undertake
turn actions will result in some punishment for two turns to operate and fit as a concept
the cast of the racing at the cost of train to turn an adversary predates nuclear weapons by centuries dawn of Warfare
the nuclear weapons fundamentally altered deterrence equations for several recent right one the explosive you even Hiroshima bomb
times 100000 people entire cities with you know a single warhead
more than that the missile age really changed how to turn could operate because prior to nuclear weapons what was the most destructive
military technology and stayed in state cemeteries and we're now how did how did the allies and
how many attack and the problem was to send hundreds of aeroplanes and sort is in enemy Territory
complete that kind of damage so your old pilots in airports was a risk that no risk to your pilot than
that you required to destroy entire cities from much smaller to you could wreck it up the costs really quickly without in
podcast yourself in the way the strategic bombing of firebombing required of the nuclear age and what's your number
psychological impact of an avatar of being able to destroy entire city for the single warhead promo for is very little risk to itself
ratchet up the ease of imposing punishment in Waze a dinner to the nuclear explosions
is there a family with the basics of uranium plutonium nuclear weapons right so I don't need to go through and reassure him bitoneum from reprocessing there's a basic
Noosa fishing weapon so what is important I think it is most regional Powers are operating so india-pakistan South
I have nuclear weapons South Africa little known facts South Africa nuclear weapons from 1979 about 91 most States start with fish and weapons
move to boost efficient weapons defence nuclear power set Fusion weapons most of the United States
Nicola is composed of Thurman thermonuclear weapon think of the a bomb that's fishing in
special weapons the age did the H bomb Fusion weapons and extremely
roll a thermonuclear weapon read as a primary Knights Fusion secondary the mysteries of Harris operating here right so North
India Pakistan is real is assumed to have boost efficient devices but I it's possible their Future Weapons unknown than ever tested
the nuclear forces Britain Britain is basically the United States that leased their weapons from the United States
RFA tridents so those her basically us weapons the French a Fusion weapons but india-pakistan are operating in the fishing
boost efficient random that's important when you can get to make it on Wheels you're talking about characteristically different weapons the number there be required to destroy the entire City
are much lower wants a Fusion weapons but obviously efficient it or a boost efficient device could do a lot of damage as well but that's not
you know you're only halfway there in terms of operation is a nucleus and I think this is often forgot we talked about the preparation process deep state need more than just news
and Warheads functional and reliable Warheads delivery capabilities rate so the first question you have is ok how many and what type of nuclear weapons
I want to have Indian Pakistani this question is unclear how much is enough for Indian Pakistan is on clear how much is an opera trying to write China as about
it's estimated in the 200 400 thermonuclear weapon range size faced with us
fences conventional counterforce capabilities is Uncle how much is enough for China to be able big piece of you know this question is
a big concept in the in the coral was secure second strike capability so we were worried about dinner so worried about a bolt out of the blue First Strike you lose and number
happens when you have enough they'll be able to provide that not only in terms of numbers but in deployment modes right where are they were where there are bass and how they're
Italian back with certain d against the Soviet Union such that into the server uniform trying to undertake what is known as a splendid Forest
places like being the ability to fully wipe out your new chlorosil capability is first dates of when they XIV
mobile number is an appointment mode such that an adversary cannot be company that are fully Disarm that states nuclear arsenal
are the questions how do you deliver them bread so most States start with aircraft you've got aircraft your ringtone
weapons aircraft as a delivery capability
UKF to penetrate any defences right you're not going to get there without a fight and so you know it's not it's not the ideal type of delivery keep Billy railway strategic bomber
if you've compliments of your escort aircraft there are not survivable if the aircraft as you can recall them they're piloted
bring them back the disadvantages they still have air forces air defence it sorry so then
Powers are attracted to ballistic missiles of various types for a ballistic missile have the advantage that can launch them from a far right there different Ranges
put yourself you there it's not risky for the user that can be recalled though
land based ballistic missiles we have icbm silos in Wyoming and North Dakota
sickness on land we moved United States move quickly to see based ballistic missiles slbm
why why do you think sea bass is attractive Alicia United States right so
if your subs are quiet enough there are virtually 100% survival bread because it very difficult the track if you're so
quiet enough and this is something in a different assumption and that wants a static why is a sea bass capability it has
Revival second strikeforce probably in the US case but states ssbn the sea bass
ballistic missile nuclear submarines as quiet as United States is increasing evidence to show that we are pretty good at tracking Soviet sbends wheels
tracking service during the Cold War I don't know how much I mean you have to soon and you know so Soviet sbends as a
later generations of quiet and we're still pretty good at track in them you can imagine first-generation Chinese sbends Indian spn4 going to be so loud
nuclear power the diesel power which actually helps with the noisy nature but you know it is it is not necessarily the case that all states that acquire CBS cable
don't have survival second rate with the attraction of Seabiscuit AC base force summer a submarine base nuclear force is more
Lamby Lamby sports with all the imminent out there now you can track you know were more sites might be within a flush out lamb base for sister then you can
increasingly some States States led by the United States are attracted Cruise missiles as new delivery tomahawks
Tomahawk land and air base nuclear version the French have an air launched cruise missile
mainstay of their nuclear pore structure because they can Cruise missiles
what's the warrior now that with ballistic missile with Ballistic missiles racing missile defence is in the oven
is drowning threaten to try ballistic missile so one shift is to Cruise missiles which there they
altitude control so there's more recallability I think the Cruise missiles in the ballistic missiles but Premier Li
missile defence is some States put the nuclear forces on a military control some stays put them
sink in a very firm civilian control this is a question that I say to wrestle with during the Cold War additionally the department of atomic energy
managed the nuclear pets in the United States is on the very first building control and then as it became clear that the United States will have to Delegate some
nuclear forces to the army in Western Europe for tactical nuclear weapons the US Arsenal
Kmart of military management but still under in a civilian authority it's like Pakistan or completely under military control about that
fundamentally the the question that regional powers in particular had to face in Wizard the superpowers didn't as much as what are you trying to deter with nuclear
why are you tracking nuclear weapons and what are you using them for in a larger Strategic Policy so some States
nuclear weapons just to deter new careers against that stays like China free sample right with huge geographies in 3 million min arms
that strategy really facing conventional threats on land the way that the US and Soviet Union were facing off in Western Europe
China and India both have nuclear weapons to deter nuclear use against unless you worry about a nuclear hereditary you don't want your address I don't have nuclear weapons
not have the ability retaliate to deter nuclear use against you and you can then rely on what we call an issue of retaliation strategy
you just need to be able to survive what might be a first strike against you and tell you when nuclear weapons against your avatar is population centres this is your Classic 2
nuclear weapons don't need to be on high alert retaliation doesn't need to be immediate it just needs to be certain and
you don't need tactical nuclear weapons because you're not using nuclear weapons on conventional forces that might be attacking you so this allows for much more Central
assess management if that's your in if your aim is to deter conventional aggression this was the US and NATO during the Cold War
we're conventional interior already in Europe in order to set the the conventional capability of the Warsaw Pact and the sea
we United States need a nuclear weapons the threat of tactical nuclear weapons to offset that differential
weapons first if Warsaw Pact commercial forces came crashing in Western Europe explicitly use tactical nuclear weapons
dancing what's up at forces weapons unless you use them against me
family strategic weapons compared to hear you have a very forward aggressive tactical nuclear weapons capability
how to render use nuclear weapons first wreckers you're trying to destroy conventional attacks against you and a kind of looks like a denial and Punishment mission at the same time
an original power is a piece of the same question now can anyone guess where India Falls
I forgot to tell you that I tried period against Pakistan not really what about China and feeding Indian and watching all the way to Delhi the Premier League
internal use against against its own cities what is Pakistan for what is Pakistan worried about it's a Pakistan
Milly worry about India international superior already and having been at the receiving end of dismemberment Familia 1971 Mattel talk about Pakistan has operation
very aggressive very oriented towards Battlefield nuclear weapons against any conventional forces that might cross the international border
a first year psychology symmetric escalation doctor and they threatened escalator commercial complex is a nuclear very quickly because
earlier than you know your India would before any new other nuclear weapons new years because they're worried about Indian commercial superiority
Pakistan actually started it's it's nuclear program before India tested that so-called peony and 1974 because
the 90s Celtic about this actually right now so India India security security vitamins took the right so has the 90621 China and which it's
it's it's conventional performance shock even the the end of the Indian army in the Indian leadership because the Chinese
the Chinese perform so much better than the end is in the 62 war in India decisively last 62 or 2 years later
it's nuclear weapons right so the Indian military program gets it's motivation initially
is experiences in 62 and 64 China and to avoid in the future against China
Hedges under the new years in the subsequent leadership on the Ender Gandhi Pakistan
superiority and the rules really never any talk about needing nuclear weapons to deter the Pakistanis
so India had a civilian nuclear program we're going to Canberra from Canada some of the heavy water was supplied by the nice days and 54 reprocessing facility
474 Indira Gandhi authorises was known at the time of the atoms for peace program there is a category
peaceful nuclear explosion which was their legitimate legitimate uses it was believe
time for the clear large swathes of land for dams for sample rate in India was had
potential uses for this but didn't really full I'm in a peaceful who is closer to nuclear explosion it wasn't however a warhead writer me this thing was a rickety
metres in diameter device I mean it with Hawking unstable rickety fish in device that they test
suitable for a military program didn't have it wasn't even suitable for delivery by aircraft you have to
brought out the back of a cargo plane right I mean it's still give them certainly the the physics of being able to you no
efficient efficient and have like you know spiritual compression all that was put on in Dubai so it wasn't
it wasn't trivial but it wasn't a nuclear weapon in the sense of the year that we think of so a lot of work was still at yet to be done Aphrodite same for Ford Everest
I just had the ability to a list in a design rudimentary nuclear weapons weather for white test in 74 as a general security environment October
British Pakistani just won the 1970 war with 1971 war with Pakistan which split Pakistan into or talk about that there was a real motivation
Sony program nation is a combination of domestic politics and the power of The Scientist in India so in the Gandhi was facing a
series of losses in state government's she wanted a big when the there are several very prom
physicist and engineering who promised the the big boost in her electoral fortunes if she tested
happened and they really wanted to test a nuclear weapon because it working on it so I just like to test things that you work on and they have been doing this processing for 7 years and she then
opportunity in 1974 when right before serious state elections the authorisation test empirically
testing actually help with that much electrically but there is a belief that it might and sort out some of the motivations for the test from 1974 until
1080 night for about 15 years India's nuclear program went into effect of dormancy there is no high-level authorisation from Indra Gandhi or her
Asahi Delirium prime minister after assassination 1984 for the militarisation of the program so India scientist worked on
some of the theoretical work from miniaturisation getting India in a place where if it had 2 mil is a program it could
there is no actual physical work done that after 1974 Pakistan someone different security environment
in your life 262 war and then face China's nuclear test but never really face the threat of a mass of conventional invasion from China really wanting nuclear weapons
the Chinese nuclear threat not the Chinese conventional threat Pakistan was really scored by the 1970 one more one more
was the war in which East Pakistan was birth in the Bangladesh refugee crisis Westpac
is a Pakistan at birth in 1947 was split in 9 contiguous with Indian the middle east and west park west park nearby Punjabi
if I can always dominated by bangladeshis Bengali sorry leader bangladeshis Bengali straight so there was ethnic tension between
Punjabi comedy the politics of Pakistan Bengali felt like there a second class citizens and Pakistan that created political tension and there is no prizing in
Tammy wein India intervene on behalf of the bengalis to split East Pakistan v West Pakistan India this is a huge strategic victory right
you add two flags of Pakistan in a surrounding you in your able to make them two independent countries
that you have birth Bangladesh from Bangladesh from Pakistan so it's not like they would be allies
inner conflict strategically this brought up pretty well for India before West Pakistan now present a Pakistan this is a pretty Siri Mum it right your
East Wing is amputated and it was at the hands of the Indians right so as early as 1965
if you came through the Indian might look at nuclear weapons because of China zulfikar Ali bhutto who is the prime minister of authorising the program
1870s so we will eat grass relieve sorry we got hungry but we will get a bomb about it's one of his famous quotes remember this is this is services 1965 but after the
tell me one more in January 1970 right after the 1971 war nuclear weapons program with Express intent of militarised nuclear weapons
any international Tower so it wasn't because of the Indian peony right which is 1974 pack
nuclear weapons program predates India's 1974 test the real motivation was the 1971 Pakistan cannot suffer the conventional defeat
at the hands of the Indians again and so the program was triggered for a state
that was essentially desperate for nuclear weapons Pakistan tried all possible Avenue straight so yeah the Iranian pathway which was led by EQ can't ever
you can't yes we can't this horrible horrible joke I apologize but designs European
from the Netherlands from the inside he stole the blueprints for what ended up in the P1
and that he might have a little bit of Pichu designs right so he stole the arenco centrifuge designs from from your raincoat self or he was an employee
back to futon so I can deliver it program and they set up Cascades
the P1 at Cohuna with Pakistan wouldn't I for the 1980s was you're a Mauritian facility than president
Zia is a good shed repeatedly interactions with the United States the problem was what happened in 1979
Charlie Wilson's War anyone this true
get the heart of Christ in the the revolution around but also have what else December 1979
the soviets invade Afghanistan and Pakistan is America's one of the most useful countries in
in the world in a stairs because you know stairs decides to supply the Mujahideen and I can't start a fight the soviets how do you get supplied to the motor then you'll have to write them through Pakistan
the relationship between Pakistan and the United States florist because we really had no option for a history doesn't repeat itself but it rhymes Road exact Centre
thousands and when we were when we were at war in Afghanistan we needed the ground lines of communication to Pakistan
and the relationship between the OSI and the CIA in the 1980s because of the usual not going to stand became
what's the right word for in blossomed but it was always there always tension and that relationship but due to us non proliferation lead
in Congress the United States would have been obligated to sanction Pakistan and cut off all aid
Pakistan were to assemble a nuclear weapon racks and India never signed the nuclear non-proliferation treaty required estate
not a member of the non cooperation treaty with nuclear weapons weapons face
sanctions cut off of us a right but that threatened us operations in Afghanistan so that could happen so the there is a lot of tension between the non proliferation haha
state department and executive so the Reagan administration went to great lengths to play fast and loose on
Pakistan was with US nuclear program everybody knew the Pakistan had a nuclear weapons program but the wording of the the language of the legislation required
let you know invited was not as a solo as I meant that the US president certify the packs and does have nuclear weapons right
as long as the exact and the executive to find nuclear weapons as the assembly of a nuclear weapon as long as Pakistan do not cross that
executive could certify the Pakistan was a 9 nuclear weapon state and was therefore in the 8th in the relationship between the US and Pakistan
could continue
is the Pakistan Pakistan Pakistan and this is the this is the president of the executor bhutto in 1979 I think
79 and he's the he's a present pachysandra in the 1980s and we get through the AC
to nucleation rates 083 there's some Chinese assistance to the Pakistani nuclear program in fact unprecedented I think in the annals of proliferation China
it is now I think you know out in I think the declassified aren't we believe the nicest believes and I think Pakistan is a metre
50 kg of each of you from Pakistan right that's effectively to bombs worth of huu
kilograms of a program designed to see you from China plus the design for a uranium
uranium core warhead known as a chick Ford as a fourth test in the Chinese test series 19 3 and 86.96
do us essential condenser Parkinson nuclear-capable state certified as a non nuclear weapon state right so there are two screwdriver turns away
if item is a nuclear weapon stay in the executive continue to do that in March 1987 year complicate all of this when he claims a Pakistan has a cable
in Time magazine so all the non-proliferation Hawks goughnuts right here you have the president of Pakistan saying to
hi magazine the Pakistan you can write he's a little bit so you can write Pakistan's ok with it and make them on and they did and
Dan that you are kind of Stephen Solaris amendment were in the present had actually so if I park somewhere tonight in the safe for the way would you put in there I made easy
the present to to be able to see that and I'll be lying because the language of this clean nuclear device right so the device wasn't assembled executive
could legitimately clean the Pakistan did not have a nuclear weapon even though I had around the pit over there the explosive package over here
we're here but it will be in three sides of the room but you can you can certify that wasn't a sample so was in a nuclear weapon and so
you know by 1988 the non-proliferation Hawks give it up in Solaris you know equipped that had a Saturday night special capability it may not be
elegant but ill do the job and one of the advantages to the Pakistani nuclear weapons program was given the fact that they had a test design from the Chinese
they conducted a series of call a test in the 1980s but they don't have to answer looking at a heart test to know that the their weapons are work on like the Indians who were indigenous
they're put on in devices
1980-present George HW bush and president and as soon as you know the US dollar
collapses anymore
call Tess is out of this material see you if you so yeah you especially in the in this case it's
it's a spherical compression rate they wanted to as they're testing this post of charges actually got a uniform compression with because they weren't using it's raining device but they won't
contact devices it was raining implosion device and so you could do a call to without the fissile material right to make sure the
compressions you can do it you can do you can do sufficient number of cancel out the first material and if since the design itself was tested
a heart test that wants a had enough fissile material and in the design it work
sun inner spirit remember India's going is in dormancy but there is a in response to Z as claim in
Time magazine and several other statements India bring this program out of dormancy in response actually to Pakistan spoken by so there is a
the narrative the commercialism is there India India's program nuclear program baguette Pakistan's nuclear program but none of the other way around so
Durham Street about Indian conventional power India has a rudimentary nuclear hedging program in the 1970s it was only when Pakistan
clean publicly that I had a nuclear weapons keep building bit India brings program out of Thomas e89
Rajiv Gandhi orders work on weaponization miniaturisation production line all the things you need to have a military program and any only is turning that at
resetting to develop delivery capabilities there they have indigenous missile the opening the preview missile and it was playing from
and in this period right so it will take another for 5 years before they would have a militarised program that they could test
there are several aborted test 1995 prime minister role of the congress party is on the brink of test and us ambassador Frank
goes to ambassador prime minister round as we know you're about to test don't do it you're the weight of American sanctions will kill you and now we're back off
couple months later of the BJP which is a Opposition Party the other the main Opposition Party the time when the office for the first time then office for only 13 days
pull back from a test they were planning to conduct when they were in 1988 the BJP it is manifest your service is going to test nuclear weapons
when does cut off guard when they came back to power after they had to order test 1996 right everyone claims that the CIA was caught off guard by the May 1998 test but the Pita Pit
publicly day if they came in officer in a test nuclear weapons again and it did take a step to camouflage the activity in the test sites but as soon as I can
office in two months after their win office for in an apartment majority they test nuclear weapons of 5 fishing devices
decided everything on the Samba Premier League China as a reason for testing nuclear weapons and then the question was how does Indian
overly test nuclear weapons operation it's nuclear capabilities as mentioned before India has an issue of retaliation passed away so test nuclear weapons 1998 and the questions Halloween
who sings India very quickly decided to have a novice youth policy and don't have a very assertive management of the nuclear forces and rely on it
retaliation Kimberley say no tactical nuclear weapons just strategic weapons the capable is under 2 billion custody and the aim of the dark
to determine clears against Indian population centres by punishment strategy and their long-range ballistic missiles America
sorry but the premier live in a missile capability now and they have a very recessed pasture very few weapons on alert most of the Arts is actually
don't piss time some subset is at Harris rating is put is primarily it would take several you know several steps up a little later before it is
do not you know on hair trigger alert is as American Soviet weapons for Pakistan
surely appa India they have moved away from your inner Richmond to petone Em for the visit here what's your finished Italian
put on in weapons so much better if you
Battlefield nuclear weapons weapons and you have payload constraints of your trading off arrange for payload
gets you much better you the way she's right it's about 41 advantage and once they had the
devices in a little worried I was always worried that India would attack it's nuclear facilities once it acquired basic nuclear weapons capability through the rain
pathway now it doesn't feel that as much and so most of the production is out in the open and with Chinese help so there a series of Chinese reactors reprocessing facilities are coming online
and Pakistan is tripping the Petroleum production capabilities
and North Korea so there is a missiles for in your room in Richmond capability trade the Pakistan had with China sorry with North Korea so I got the noodle
source from North Korea in exchange North Korea got some pieces for it's uranium enrichment capability that it now has and China also salt
sign some are the mdmx for missiles which are the shocking and ghaznavi missiles her for Pakistan
what's if you're trying to have in Pakistan nuclear in who's in the middle
bacon sandwich India rate so the enemy of my enemy is my friend
not I mean
questions and I think the reason the Chinese lightweight like that you provided a nuclear capability or system but you don't want to take on the inner responsibility if they're
Pinot a fracture in the state and local weapons fall into extreme it's hands in the Chinese was you got to somebody's tractors & Chainsaws washed
but you know you can think from the strategic perspective I make sense remember have India focused on Pakistan and this is one way to do it I think that's a Chinese motivation
so Pakistan because it's trying to to Indian commercial power has an explicit and explicit first use darken right
this is a bold in the past 1516 years first world is credible because all of Pakistan's nuclear weapons Runner military cost
I'm like India with a civilian custody and control and nuclear weapons Pakistan is a de facto praetorian state the army is a diamond in decision making body and so all the New Groove
program for cradle-to-grave is an army management program a shift to Battlefield nuclear weapons there is a
what's a missile if anyone has been following this it's a 60 km short-range nuclear weapon system
are there we filled it at the edge of Battle that will Target Union forces if ever if they cross international border there is a Cruise missiles Patrol also designed me about
weapon to ride in the Baba and they have a an explicitly determined by the night on Messenger trying to deter Indian conventional ataxic Rossi international border
so there's some the many questions about where and where we are in terms of
how India and Pakistan think about nuclear weapons in their fourth posterity
question why would Pakistan ask for some of this because the crux of the problem now is he doesn't have any territorial this
Pakistan Road why would India want to dismember Pakistan further it prefers a stable Pakistan it has no territorial ambitions and Pakistan Dorset there's a
is a disputed in a dispute over kashmira but frankly the liner control on both sides is effectively the de facto water there won't be much turtle revision over
instantly if you're worried about a conventional attack across the international border how do you get there I'll get to that in one second
after very quickly talking about in the nucleus sense what the differences between South Asian the Cold War and nuclear weapons
the key differences between India Pakistan in the 90s and Soviet Union one rudimentary capabilities still organisational
not as mature in Ida country as in the Cold War especially in the later years the colour obvious Lee but there's a big difference
rates of the flight times between India and Pakistan on the order of couple minutes us over 30 minutes half hour
I was going on if you have any early warning
is launching a potential nuclear Strike 2 minutes before the thing is going to hit so your reaction time have too much quicker
skip through this hear the other big difference is as imagine why would India why would India be
conventional attacks against Pakistan wouldn't be Avenue she wouldn't be the first one is the Indian problem right now is facing a Pakistan that is more
Liam bold and two large militant attacks in India using organisation or organisation sponsored by the state Believer be sponsored by the state like
Muhammad and the strategy has s*** changed since Pakistan test nuclear weapons pirate and 1888 Pakistan strategy
Queen by Sia and general Aslam bag nose bleeding India by a Thousand Cuts so the strategy of inner cutting into the periphery right in the line of
Cashmere in the mountains we could have a real convention battle but you can have in a terrorist infiltration to be some attacks and just you know small cuts
strategy shifted since 1988 it seems the frequency of over infiltration by regular forces in the kargil war in 1999 and then
attacks on Indian Metropolitan cities with his pakistan-based militant organization's conditioner India wouldn't be storing bourbon
Rachel India's mainstay threat Prada nucleation was if you if you try to stretch your brilliance by Thousand Cuts who's gonna punish you were hurt
army if you're you're an army let state and only control state will cross all international border and we will treat your army right and that will punish Pakistan
the determined by punishment scratching in your head at the conventional level Prado nuclearization
fight for a while but in extreme it's threatens tactical nuclear it is an Indian forces if India tries to return it across international border
India find now and that's the steering which India think about convertible Comfort Pakistan it's not for Territory ambition or any Territory or before retaliation after a private patient
so there a couple examples of the kargil war remember this night in the May 1999 so this was a year
are you after the testing nuclear weapons general professor mosharraf who ended up being
during the first phase of the Afghan war in 2000 before September 1st September 11th nevad shareef history does repeat of anniversary
then the prime minister he is again the prime minister today by the way head then general provision
who is the chief of army staff Orchestra in operation wear on uniform regular Pakistan forces of the Northern Light Infantry in Northern Light Infantry
credit into several sectors in Indian helico smear and Indian Territory and responded with trying to dislodge
90 forces previously this exact operation been attempted 1965 India launch airstrikes across the line of control and open the second front of Crossing
best time the bishop he responded very differently because of Pakistan's nuclear Association the BJP was
The Strand Penshurst and hair loss is because the threat of escalating the conflict deterred the BJP from into the same kind of
had an 18650 the India had so it it refused to allow air operations across the line of control so Indian aircraft could not cross line
Hot Pursuit of Pakistan infiltrators and most importantly did not warrant open at the second front the police were India conventional advantage really
come to bear is on the international border here but India has a huge
in this plane second which is international portraits 0800 in a previous provocation India has always open up the second we can really bring a commercial power to bear
Pakistan this time the BJP refuses to rent over it did not mobilise any of its mainstay can measure forces on the international border and did
open up a second front and so it took Indian forces a lot longer in the sustain much every losses in the kargil war because they had to expel the Pakistani forces
symmetrically so didn't have the virtue of airpower hidden behind Pakistani lines and it wasn't any ability to take
map of this front by opening up a second front in the response is restrained because packets
what is a nuclear power so surely after September 11th here 2 months later 3 months later there was an attack
Indian parliament Grace you had about a half a dozen gunman break through the barriers of the Indian Parliament House imaginative and attack on car receipt right there be the equivalent
you had a Jay Jays you Muhammad in joint attack on the Indian Parliament in Delhi right never heard of before
these Milton group which are normally supported by the Pakistani state would attack the Indian capital right so you had this attack
oh Bishop mysterious imagine the United States would do if a militant organisation attacked the US congress rate so you can imagine the out
in India the time to limited war here across the line of control right so destroying Terrace camps across
under a lot of pressure from the US government because remember what's that we're immobilization for one Afghanistan this point right we need Pakistan United States needs
tonight be distracted by a conventional war with India can you imagine how that would have affected us we're not gonna stand if India and Pakistan going to convert 4
the lot of pressure on both sides to not go to Waratah deputy secretary see the time to carpeted gets on the phone is on the phone he said like twice a day with
BJP Origin m2 in a show restraint and for a while but then is the secondary attack in a town
call town car colour check in jammu which is an army town and the Jewish militants killed 36 Indian army families and so the point is this is
peak of the crisis is enough is enough for the mobilize India three the column three three strike course is in the main offensive
what is the Indian army 800000 forces in total in immobilized in the assembly boxes which are much larger than a 60 km
in the three positions boys for attacks across international border so this is it becomes real for South Asia
mobilise his forces just on it as a Bluff and so does real concerned at the the BJP what authorised attacks and at this point
Pakistan and gauges in some serious nuclear test 3 nuclear cable muscles without the present
to the owner of the Cross in a supporter that Pakistan may have no option with his nuclear weapons the US and the United Kingdom evacuate there an essential personnel
very serious at this point after after these new
and again a lot of pressure from United States on India premiership odds play orders several months later the strike force back to the
the peace and can tell me the interior of India and later on she said look I don't I don't think that was high but I don't want to be responsible for starting war
answer there is a real Powerball with record of India to engage in this kind of conventional operation is Pakistan and defeated the Pakistan army there's a real risk in nuclear weapons will be used right
the third instance with the Bombay attacking 2008 to talk about beginning
so here right this was even more Addis in some ways than the parliament attack this wasn't a ragtag group of 6 guys in a car
a dozen welltrain heavily on militants coming by sea from Karachi quarterback in now turns out by retired
play handlers the United States picked up signals intelligence and intercept between handlers in
star who were formed Isa officers quarterback in the operation is a attacked Bombay 170
it will in the media tends to downplay the number of westerners are deliberately targeted by the militant
l e t militants and your India was just a fire we are treated this attack
I was again paralyzed great so this time it's the congress government that the BJP government is making decisions and it doesn't immobilise forces time by the prime minister of my mum and sing
you do not want to repeat a 2001 2002/1 immobilise Force and not do anything so what do we do and here we have the you know the
Alice is the Indian policy community faces is any serious convention retaliation risk snooker escalation itself now and
the cabinet meeting so this is this report from the cabinet meeting where the Prime Minister and the Defence Minister for minister of finance minister home in
I'm eating and it was one of the just when the dust settle all the principles agreed that the unpredictable in the Pakistan side in the fear of this decision makers car for a just before
including the new corruption stymied any possible chance of military action in his behalf after 26/11 is there is what they're called the Bombay attacks
26th of November so there's real process now about how do you deter
militant attacks against the India stayed in the first place and Pakistan has
has successfully determined in a conventional Power by lowering the nuclear threshold taking a play right out of the NATO Playbook threatening early nuclear use
Indian forces to rent across the international border so now after what we have is more frequent and intense Christ is triggered by Pakistan
disable if they're in bold in by the shield of early nuclear used right knowing that India can't really retaliate with ground power right
I can get into we have some time for questions we get into why India hasn't tried to help an air strike option then gets in the politics of the Indian military the service rivalries
has the air force has always refused to to think about options that don't involve the army mobilising
is the belief is there Pakistan with wood Italian on the ground and so the air force doesn't believe the standalone air options are possible without a
should be mobilized Pakistan if you're facing a conventional facing
John Fury with only grown because the size and growth rates of the two countries are so disproportionate the India's Gap is just going it's going it's going to be a yawning Gap at this point right
is it going forward how do you slow India down so there's one theory out there which is this periodic attacks on India's financial and
hubs kind of creating periodic crises get for an investor account skittish so you get periodic slowdowns be triggered by there so you can
hoedown India's economic growth potential if you make it risky to invest in India so that's one Siri out there the other Siri is Pakistan is always had crazies
that is trained to attack good Christmas kill Indians bad creases cool Pakistanis and so they need it in the safety valve theory and they've always had a safety belt
it was customary now she is like down because Indian army knows how to prevent infiltration Cashmere or while I was going to Stan Wright
US military has to be asking why it is Guy speaking Punjabi and I'll be honest because there is a Punjabi train militants the only TV that have gone now don't understand it
and they're killing Americans and here now if you can turn them against the earliest a great ride the so there's a as long as you're not killing Pakistan is a good militants right and so
130 out there that this is the Pakistan states still views these militant groups as strategic assets of the state
perpetually attack in bleed India by 1000 cards and you know if you can get in through Cashmere if you can infiltrated by sea
to Bombay great if you can you know hit deli great before nuclear weapons hitting Bombay Delhi really wrist serious conversion retaliation
you have nuclear weapons and an operation nuclear capability and tactical nuclear weapons to deter that convention retaliation those kinds of modest attacks and more possible
two kinds of theories out there
the people here again the more about those who were who were who had first annexe
interislander reports that you had Punjabi speaking right I mean most most of the most of the Afghan Mujahideen or pasta speaking
a lot of the ladies that was pretty the pretty 911 and they were supported find it and
strong relationships between the ISI and some of the Mujahideen groups in Afghanistan that ended up being the Tauranga the only Tuesday they reckon it's Alma Park
the net worth of Pakistan had enough gunnison or very strong and they also have these other groups also write so they needed militants to go
quite what end of the Americans as well as in a car's Isa na it would be it would be these in the letnje shahamat so there
Punjabi speaking militants well-trained Punjabi speaking militants fighting in Afghanistan alongside Pashto speaking haqqani network militants
you know that was a safety valve for a while and now I think this is why Pakistan may have an incentive your for a fight to continue Organics town for a while so I had some place to
is crazy for a while and worried about Indian influence in Afghanistan so that you know that there will be those Milton sweetbox into Pakistan
Pakistan faces in an awful school attack recently you know there is a real Terrace in Pakistan also it's a family
good nautical Indians in America
yeah read I just I mean
so I think I didn't even a suggest a ladder I mean it is it is it is remarkable that the l e t
so after 2000-2002 the only tea was nominally band but they themselves and Harper said who is the
how did the early tea leaves openly not out in the tribal areas he lives outside Lahore in a town car Marika everybody knows where they are they open the fundraising he goes on TV
calling for the death of Indians and openly right and the fact that he is it open question whether it's
support a passive support but at least the evidence suggests that at least passaporte is allowed to freely operate he's allowed to freely
organisation exists it could be shut down very is loose in the heart of Pakistan it's like 30 km from The Importer the Indians could hit it but they were
and put the network is allowed to recruit and operate openly we're not talking about it like the Northwest front though in a car booked in the
where is this is this is Heartland of Pakistan in so it is it is it offends credible I credibility like credibility to think that
it's not there isn't some stick policy to allow certain group to operate to some extent well thinking to Target the rest
different house on different days but the security groups I think or allowed operators want those of the other goodnight
videos of Sydney is fine so some of those groups have been very very Fierce and are allowed to operate still and I can't
and the only tier as long as they're not killing Sony's in Punjab seems like the Pakistani state is this one to tolerate their assistance
cancel that an actress a policy and this is different from the call right we don't have I don't think I said something to do with that kind of proxy level militancy right we have to strategic assets
military organisations to try and we can the other state plus nuclear weapons to deter the retaliation so that I think what makes it particularly dangerous
clue here I do you have any is extremely frustrated right I think it worry in the United States is that if there's another mass casualty terrorist attack in Hindi
how the BJP now you have prime minister a new prime minister who is by all accounts a little more aggressive than it's predecessors
and you know there's right now the stability in South Asia is predicated on Indian restraint following one of these mass casualty terrorist
so if there is another Bombay how will the BJP respond right there we can talk if anybody tried to call so we talk about that you just
if anyone ever wants to get in some of that the wheels got the basic idea is you know any has a commercial ads commercials security it has not used it yet
be there some believe that Pakistan's nuclear threat is a Bluff and India execute such conventional injectors below the nucleus raffle maybe maybe
pretty rescue protective we talk about tactical nuclear weapons that would at least at some point be the Bold to you know another pretty reliable maybe and
you'll have is not just one refresh all but night and so you'll have to worry about one of them deciding that this is the end of the use nuclear weapons I think
it's a the Pakistani strategy is actually quite rational it's it's deterring it's deterring with the restaurant that we might use tactical nuclear weapons but also through a madman mechanism
nuclear weapons say one of our British might use if you come and that reinforces the rash on the term threat as well and so you know so far
yeah both and Cargill sorry I didn't in three instances cargo brockham and Bombay India has been relatively restrained as conventional
play ocean and it's response and so far that has taken India off india-pakistan off the excretory Highway
continue going for emotions in India I'm running very high visible Pakistan particularly in increase shelling across the line to control the pest
are anything if there is a significant attack in a major city that involves the death of many Indian civilians still be a lot of pressure on on
prime minister ability to do something about it and then you know all better off because you have nuclear weapons potentially mixed with conventional conflict and that would be the best
I think there's something they were likely it says element of terrorist attacks mass casualty terrorist attacks at dinner exist in the Cold War that makes South Asia quite different I think
and so is there accommodation proxy forces in the arms race that I think makes it particularly unstable so I'm at the stuff
we are almost at 10 but I'm happy to take questions for a while if anybody has any for this afternoon to get it out yeah yeah
yeah so this is getting the escalation Thomas Road so Pakistan also has strategic weapons
that put most of India's major cities in in retraite so the idea being that deters Indian retaliation for tactical nuke Pakistan
Nicola used as a war terminating strategy because the address of the ideas into commercial forces attack Pakistan stands and fight commercially find that are losing these taxable
forces but now I have a secure second-strike capability also from Pakistan so India has no incentive to use a strategic nuclear weapons against Pakistani cities rugby
nuclear use on your forces operating on Pakistani soil that's already happened in my Willie was deli in Bombay for retaliator
not now absent that the strategic capability to write then you could easily retaliate and there will be no reciprocation for Pakistan but pockets and is trying to establish
escalation diamond so that it could use tactical nuclear weapons and that would be the end of it so anyway have no incentive to retaliate was strategic nuclear weapons against Pakistan there is some
looking at lower ordering options for itself but there are some capabilities that could be used for softer targets
cities that India tries to develop tit-for-tat capabilities and then that's that's basically your escalation letter
swell in the back
22 often and then the core world pin I think there is a does a limit over once every
23 years is not nothing and you know there's always chatter there have been there in several instances where the Indian home Ministry claims I don't know how good
disrupted several attacks by Led on on Indians on India
every 7 years I think you know that's that's that's not nothing and they also choose
strategic Mum's to do it so she looked at the timing of the attack on the Parliament two months after 9:11 just as
sunny us relationship is growing again maybe disable if you can get away with it because you are so going to protect you the Bombay
attack was just as then present mosharraf was there is discussion of including a Back channel final agreement
and the only tea and the India Focus militant actors video player spoilers and so
something as a composite dialogue I'm going between India and Pakistan in 2008 literally everybody knew what the final solution
silver to India Pakistan look like Impreza musharraf was very serious about it this was spoil it with them Pakistan v doing that that deal in disrupting the diary so India had no often but it's
composite I live at 4 Bondi Parade and has a really restart it and so those strategic moments I think our our our chosen
bye bye Pakistani militants to attack in D
oh yeah that's it that's a whole so he's told her
who provided the uranium enrichment capability to Pakistan here or orchestrated network of global suppliers for the
for the centrifuge for both state policy right to he use that network to get North Korea it's centrifuge capability
but whether with completed state support or acting on his own he also decided to make some money by Moonlighting maybe with
Ryan and Lydia and there's Blue Da Ba Ford customer don't know who that is but you know there's a big day but also the packs and how influential if you can't really
the moving to the petone designs anyway paec which is he responsible petone
competing for designs and ownership of the Pakistani program so in Pakistan
pistol that's a dispute but some of the sum of the proliferation activities
it is unclear whether States possible whether there is some steak complicity and he detection Zone or the actor completely honest
cells nuclear technology I mean
catalogue you could you can get the brochure for it so the it is true write that you know there was
you definitely have to let you know I'm just kind of interesting cos you're on in Pakistan or natural
sunny what are you know that natural in Iran is also been involved with the Bluetooth
that he would sell centrifuges to Ryan simple puzzling maybe was for personal gain would be a very strong explanation
there is some evidence here pressure rock in the late 1980s also for if this if they're interested in your in Richmond
a trap so you know he passed on it but yeah I'll be there as there's no question that there's this is a big night proliferation failure
a bit like you have to live with some acid from possibility to do some of the stuff some people didn't know about it
the rain on the take rate which is entirely possible I'm currently the North Korean deal with a flu Pakistani 78 so they it was military
for the talk before centrifuge Cascade over the request that was different state to state the level of complexity other people in the park
I probably will be hard for me to believe they didn't but they probably made up in state policy last question I think then we going
Pakistan
yes William Post
tonight's 98 but then after September 11th to Pakistan
recently I'm not a Pakistan expert in this case in a very like you know the empirical evidence for this is we don't know but packet
very vulnerable I mean I think a non-trivial proportion of their revenue comes from from us international aid but on the other hand
given the militancy problem I think most countries before a stable Pakistan to an unstable Pakistan and have you saying she's got a really
the fabric of that state into it it's it's a very thin line you walk right and I think
and there is a belief in the radio station that was one of the other as I do need a Pakistan for against that serves or is a nuclear program but we couldn't deal with both at the same time
the week in the United States wasn't happy it wasn't like he was happy about the Pakistani nuclear program but it's certainly true that the exact it was willing to
by the way and tolerate certain point probably on the list is kind of an Evelyn nothing much you can do about it I'm not sure Telstra I actually think that there are a lot of leverage points we then I said could have had in
and then take advantage of them but that's also you know it's a ministration fighting this warm and I believe I have the bandwidth deal with both and I think that's kind of were they
in the 1980s to stop Pakistan from from becoming a ghost in the first place but now that they are through the hard to see what you can do
put this situation
you either keep going incrementally the way it's been going well you take a big step
is going to do something while you're too slow
which is not if you can buy white skips
what's your name
I think it was a real door I think it was a real does an app for tuning 2018 my mind saying and then foreign secretary short form and was going to be at MIT actually
3 at the centre for national studies with us you can but I believe the they were India was ready to do the
in 2008 and was ready to do this in 2008 so no elements of the Pakistani secure
and the party forces nearly or not and so it was just politically untenable after the Bombay attack for the
political leadership and soda spoilers the spoiler spoilt
but I'm in the politics of it will just no way that that can make it a survived if it if you continue with the
the dialogue and it was also it was also the case where the they were they were elections with the next year read
I know where the composite I like could continue to bomb in your country could do that that's just unfortunate you know the unfortunate republics and I think the only team you that right
you probably this attack and you will kill the composite dialogue and a back and that's exactly what happened a maybe in it's interesting because it's sometimes you know you need an x in the
and Modi who is hawkish in the BJP has a credibility get the right on his side right he's protector his right flank which often test
India so he's an opportunity I think and I wouldn't be surprised if there's some movement toward it in this immigration provider don't know whether a text so I think you're right
all the pizza everybody knows what the final deal looks like there's something like you know there's one Hiccup about whether it's sequential or simultaneous
do you know association of the Sea actually like everything else gets in it would you dated
maybe in a motor has 5 years so it's possible if anyone in India can do it I think it has to be something from the right the question of whether there's a will in partner willing
Pakistan exactly so ok I think we're over time so we should I go to pick up my kids from daycare so thank you guys