welcome to finntack shaping the future the world of the Nan's and happy spray
may I thought what the heck you've got to be a little in a bed of tray teaching from outdoor as though this is not a virtual background
the if the sun is too much for the the birds are too much that's an additional thing remain can give me advice line
not today we're going to drive until insurance and technology or with some call this little sector fintech as insurtech
litter and it's not just simply because the excitement as around payments and Challenger bags in apps like
Robin hide in the Capital Markets in so for that we leave in short activity and I also think insurtech is an interesting feel that it brings all the peace
gather & somewhere it brings together a part of any ants that has big Legacy and combats in every
where there is this handful of life insurance companies in property and casualty insurance that's those that are for
find some insurance on our homes are Auto sliding so forth healthcare insurers particularly in those countries that have
like the US big open healthcare systems insurance companies big Legacy companies have tended to be a
behind the curve of Technology compared to the Wall Street firm behind but a little behind and then the insured tickets sell
vintec within and sure sure it's has done some really interesting things particularly around alternative date I wearing a dive into some of these
opportunities and also they're there a little bit new forms of alternative date it's not just a better
rating it's about our driving it's about our homes it's about thinking about can we underwrite insurance risk
related to how we live Our Lives how we drive our cars how small businesses or operated and whether there is more
information that can be brought to bear or not just finished inclusion but the pricing and underwriting of risk of course
the same trans about artificial intelligence wanna see some really important friends around user interfaces and one of the most interesting areas around us
face is what's called claims management in the area that you know hopefully you don't have to think about too much but a Monks this class of 80 or more I'm sure
that somebody is had a little fender bender had some scrape up on the road and now that there are apps that you can
can your mobile phone take some quick photographs and put it right into the system claims management is changing quite a bit now as
startups in the space that basically say we will get you better claims management faster smoother and a better user experience
so with that I'm going to try to upload the slides again we can join
the community to gather sort of videos or an please raise your hands actively romance going to be watching for any
hands up in the chat and if the birds get to be too much just know that I'll go back in on inside on Wednesday
how is it so far it's fine it's very nice don't worry me that I can keep having a little bit of
Indulgence here in this beautiful outdoor setting and what I'm going to
Heroes go to the share screens
so we're going to talk a little bit ready to start a little bit about the insurance value chain and the sack
landscape now and traditionally in business scores traditionally in worlds of fun and finance Majors there's a lot of time
banking & Capital Markets and some time but less time spent on insurance
I sell I want to just lay the groundwork a little bit about insurance some of the challenges in the sector itself and then get into this field
tac insurance are what are people car insure tech opportunities business models of the startups so that's where the goal of the class the reader
we're really about this area of insured tech there were a handful of them the back of international
reading was really talking about some of the regulatory challenges and weather in shoretec is well change some of the risk in terms of
deleting this space and then a little reading about Asia and if you've not had the opportunity to look at some of the readings because they were just put up last Friday
go back it should have died then take her take a little lock and again we'll see if there's anybody wants to give a little fuel in this
what are fraternities in the current insurance sector what are the pain points you think that you might want to highlight
and then again this is just a little conversation go and so remain here we go
you're free thank you for today and felt there is a little pain Point Michael
as always Michael is helping herself to get a started go ahead
I think I'm just really kind of underwriting pricing just
games a lot of opportunities for automatically baka
two sides of processing it's the front end when you're actually trying to get your insurance when you're actually it's caught under a
insurance company is pricing and giving you a vulnerability of insurance and whether it's a life insurance where you might have to send some medical test in the like
homeowners insurance renters insurance auto insurance where there is a process going on at the front and and and then there's also the price
if you have an accident insurance is this product that basically if you never hear from your insurance company and they never hear from you you've paid
me to protect you against the rest but the risk is not generated a lost but then you have the accident then you have the prom
then you have to send in a claim and that price us and the back and the insurance companies want to protect against fraud they want to fulfill your claim
I want to protect against fraud and the claim adjustment process is a significant time and human and paper based and some time
legal based circumstance so Michael Wright pain points at the front and particular paint points in a claims process inside
anything else you want to throw it I guess
another big is going to be
different type of insurances come to live there is more and more are becoming quantifiable and this is
do a number of your bands are things we can get insurance on the selection of things and which we can get shirt it's gone increase dramatically Castell
25 of the risks are getting bigger and bigger and sometimes it's not just a new risk in society but it says there's Alexandra saying the quantified
let's take auto insurance and a company that started a number of years ago called metromile Simple concept what if we charged ensure
is automobile insurance night by the month but maybe by the mile can we quantify that you've only driven a mile and
the insurance and if you're a heavy driver there's more and in fact what if the Myall is out in the country roads or it's actually in the sea
and where are your driving so quantifiability the analytics the computer paper ability but also the connections to all of us with
and the Internet of things give it a little bit of a preview with the rest of the other hand
that which we talked about or semester machine learning alternative data influence there put a new factor that we've really not talk
about in banking and Challenger bags and Payment Systems is the Internet of things devices possibly changing the field of ensure
Danielle would you like to go
connection there's an opportunity for the insurance landscape to be changed by Elton of data in that companies can now inform
with a lot more information on Saturday than they previously had so where is for health insurance or life insurance you might have had to fill out a survey
hit by varying degrees of honest on those kinds of service now or suddenly generating an extremely accurate picture of ourselves
possibly by everything we do in the world and companies can access that information access network and it's really
space is that Justice we said data aggregation important feature in the payment space with companies like clad and Galileo and everything
there right there collecting day between the banks and the Payment Systems and then hundreds of thousands of fintech store
they're ready to aggregate is in the middle of the day to aggregators in this field as well to collect that data commercialise the data but maybe stay in
when our lives and all the sensors and data collection efforts and hundreds of thousands of store apps on the other side as well
Nikhil this is more specific to the health insurance ID of things where
play times in health insurance claim 90% of claims are ordered you located and most of them Basin exits to go methods with the influx of a I like you can review
you weren't review in before and she can uncover more fried waste and abuse than you were so this is the market they haven't size yet because they don't know how big
my setting is a big trend as well and sometimes it's not truly artificial intelligence for machine learning it's
the remarkable ability to collect sore clean up the day to standardise the date of that might also have a beer
machine learning on top of it but it doesn't have to be the machine Laura and I guess it's sort of this partnering up and then what are some of the Chan
we're going to talk about some of the challenges for the startups trying to get in there capital regulation and is anybody have a viewers today to the
why we haven't seen with some important exceptions but we haven't seen big tech firms getting engaged in the insurance
ls7 Port exceptions for talked about in China by the way by why we haven't seen Amazon
there in a credit card space in apple in and payment space but why we haven't seen big big tack by Morris
yeah I'm so I just think that it's mostly because there's a loaded barrier stand rename be like as you mentioned regulation and also like Alexa
which all of these insurance companies already have so I think it's also regulation and High Courts because of lack of expertise that prevents these attacks on cement
insurance market so I think that's right but I'm also going to put out the question throughout the class and as you thought experience at the air
is it just that we have in garden area is it possibility that that again big tac is about data networks and act
is the back of international Settlements has written Ansell do they want a layer another activity upon that network upon
network we haven't quite seen it I said that with one import exception in China and China a number years ago big Tac
Alibaba tension WeChat partnered up with what are the largest insurance companies in China and the three of the
started effectively and insured Tek it's the world's largest insurtech if you we still call it that and it was an arm
owned and operated by three big very big companies ping on with the insurance company and
so it wasn't direct it was a joint venture but it's a question of will we see this coming into the future or not
so let's just sort of dive into the value chain you've got a design a product you've got a market it goes all the way to claims management you can be
any one of these pieces this is port from the federal Insurance office of the US Department of Treasury from a report last year
each of these pieces might have a piece of car petition and a pain point we talked a little bit of our claims management that claims man
separate insurance from the banking fintech we've talked about what a lot of the underwriting and the front end
getting a product in the marketing you'll see that an awful lot of disruption is going on at that Friday marketing is sales
Rugrats it's bringing in the customer it's a better user interface a better user experience in the underwriting and
inside you can under a credit you can under 8 insurance it's basically how much insurance will I provide to whom it what price
and in that on the riding price house ultimately comes to administering the policy and then the claims management side of it
each of these pieces in the value chain might have pain points the front the front for these deciding products to policy administration
actually has a lot overlap with the banking sector not identical important differences so
sector look like I just list company is on these several next slides life insurance property and casualty what I want you to take out of
protect our names in your country whether it's China live worth metlife for Nippon life in and in Swiss life it's that if you look
these companies were founded many or 20th century but many are actually 19th century
the concentration and the survival the persistence of insurance companies is quite
assisting around the club Victoria about the big 5 and shine up but in any country in any country there's a handful of insurance companies once you get your
top 10 Euro 85 to 90 + percent market share particularly in life insurance and property in cash or take a little less so
other fields in this course health and managed care more a feature of the US healthcare system where it's private insurance
big diversified companies across the globe diversified simply means that it's both in life and and property and casualty in the law
it's Marty line but let's not forget their sorcery insurance and then brokers and the broken side is an aerial
disruptors of starter so well maybe we can broker insurance and buy brokering insurance is basically making the sales making the marketing
what night taking the risk onto your own balance sheet benefits administration software the only Cup
is there a 21st century companies on this whole sort of review is in the software and services side effects so that's kind of my current
you know or apply us insurance premiums just to give you a sense of scale of a market about why did a hair trillion-dollars a year we talk about
Factor that's about 7 trillion in the US I'm sorry 7% of GDP
elrow statement there which is about 1/2 million this is consistent with that syzeza the premiums being paid into
direct premiums Red Health and life side of things just to give you a little flavour and these will be on canvas of
by and large are big part of the life and health side is so savings products there is competition between live companies
and bags live companies and investment management companies on the annuity side the disruption said to speak is been happy
largely and property and casualty but to the extent that insured text starts to get into the space I think he will see more more disruption in the saving
excited as well the companies like betterment and all those companies we talked about in the wealth management side or and wealth Tak I think
c starting to say wait maybe we can get into the annuity side as well the annuity and saving side of life insurance products
Property & casualty just a little break down here in the US and so now we turned the challenges pain
what are we have this is true of any and company company you could be a cup of tea that's been in business for 100 + years and you're you're sitting there going
selling through an agent or broker network and the agency and brokerage now work here in the US takes a big
I think on a property casually said we're probably in the 10 to 13% of a premium
average but in some products it's much larger so I'm a little smaller the life side the premiums I think her and hi Singleton
The Temper sent on average in while I'm not sort of an expert of all the that's basically means of you pay a
thousand dollars for your auto insurance 100plus dollars $120 is being taken by those agents in progress
claims administration we talked about it very paper and human and chance of litigation risk all about and insurance companies are built
around this Legacy Tak just like an Indian payments and in credit
every dollar a premium a big chunk is not only going to the agents in the brokers but a big chunk as of going of course to the whole claims
the whole value chain and because it's deeply regulated in many marketplaces you can offer a new type of
parents without getting some official sector approval going through the product design face often has
Legacy and time delays within it and of course just like the other Fields there's a whole sort of questions about user-interface and user experience
all of these present challenges but they also present opportunities remain any questions not yet but that's sweet rose City seconds
no I don't see hands up tomorrow
so insurance and insurance tech you can sort of say I want to be involved in the pricing and underwriting the
the policy administration the claims management survey for different sectors improving the customer engagement lowering operating cost
of course it always goes back to can you do something better quicker cheaper but as we talked about earlier it could be in product design
wow it could be in in notches doing a cheaper and pricing got more availability and his metromile is died really in
using metrics to get to a new type of product itself in the quoting and issuing a products
what are some of the opportunities more specifically I think across finacial technology it's about user-interface and user
experience so that could be in the southside it can be in the account management digital a mobile phones but also in the conversation interface
underwriting we've talked about it really not just the machine learning but the alternative data and then clear
I think these are the big three they seem pretty simple once I say it but it should have like thinking about it
if you have a business smart or if you're going into this business or you're at Prudential life insurance are Nippon life it's sort of saying how can we use techno
to enhance user experience how can we enhance basically the pricing and availability of our product underwriting how do we
back at the first two user experience in underwriting very much true and banking tac claims processing somewhere tuna
and it's about data capture now one port of the day to capture and you can see it
drones the Internet of things smartphones telematics wearables I am curious
see if anyone will raise their hand is there anybody actually taken insurance where the insurance company is sad for your automobile
we want to have access to your driving record directly through your car's telematics telematics is a word that didn't exist 30 and 50
it's really or if it did exist it wasn't commonly used it's about all the information
if your car's collecting I'm driving in the computers onboard your your car
Nitrous GPS Anakin service as you're driving smartphones as well can assess her driving
smart furniture not just locational devices but they can get all of us the ups and downs of your driving what is that mean
smartphones and the computers on our cars a product can be offered it says we no
about your driving that we will give you fine tune pricing and underwriting
should around the round Google deal with ascension to store and analyse the medical records from the hospital network and I'm curious
think that kind of entrance the big pack into the medical world is going to be more common in about might be a potential Avenue for those kinds of companies get
insight into health data that they would need to make them competent to move into insurance
Victor can be very influential particularly the big AI companies like Google and video in China to the extent
and we'll see there are some startups that are entering this field because they're very good day datalytics in machine
to the extent that they can be dead aggregators like Google you're actually right I don't think it's just healthcare by the way but I think healthcare is a really
you submit that many insurance companies healthcare management companies in the US have a tremendous amount of date and they want
and I want to with that data provide more fine tune insurance products but also help manager healthcare system
better so I think it isn't happening for certain big tech companies that are at the cutting edge of of data Analytics and machine learning
my for every big tech company but I agree with that you did anybody have insurance
insurance think probably Alessandro he had his hand up but probably a question
add this little or a computer I'm bored and physically
treat everything that I do with a car wreck where it where are you but I was how many miles I drove everything can actually eat up for help me
decrease the cost of insurance some of the first telematics patterns filed
intelematics were in the late 1990s what we found it's really changed the field of autoit sure
this little visualisation about ensure attack again from the department of Treasury study last four I think it's just a good place to surpass for
we're not going to go through every box but whether it's sensors and telematics and this is a big piece of having those
intelematics there to lower Alexandros cost of insurance but also for claims management if the telematics and sensors are
upon an accident then you can lower a little bit the cost of claims management and the insurance companies can have
the accident actually happened potentially figure out who's at fault see right at that moment
play 9 and that automobile visual computing literally downloading uploading photographs into the claims
process we've already talked about machine learning AI but blockchain technology want to touch a pod of all the fields of blockchain Technology that
generally have heard about in many of them are hyper-reality field is weather with the use of
blockchain technology that we can have an ape and only law that is Tampa resisted whether there would be trust
the art of insurance card parametric insurance in essence if we had an automated smart contract that says
this happens I get paid so what's the best one Field Group of students started last year studying it
hair for a group in Asia was parametric insurance for airline delays if you couldn't
on tape resistant larger on at Ledger you would embed smart contracts it says if the play
takes off more than a half hour late you automatically get paid a mobile app no trying to rely
Caroline's whether they're accurately telling you are not that they plan to go off late put it on a blockchain technology now maybe you could do it with a scent
your base as well but there are many people looking at whether to use blockchain technology for parametric insurance but the sensor is intelematics the visual computing the
that was a real Department of Treasury so the boss of put something only on the edge in terms of blockchain Technology
about 4 ensure attack is still the age of Challenger funding and it's it's particularly true in insurance because
take an insurance risk winder your balance sheet that's a liability of an insurance company that's a liability that in the future they have to payout
Acclaim line an accident a loss on your home or on your life so many companies
fighting shower Jess if they're startups how can I access capital on the banking sector you can possibly do it through security
you can basically say I'm not gonna I'm not going to be on my own bow and she I'm gonna suit a renter bow and she I'm gonna lay it off
Cimorelli here you can lay off some rest in the reassurance markets but it's not quite the same for these insurtech startups
most Challenger bags partner with some Bank data warehouse line of credit and possibly also
then sell their loans after their initiated here it's not as real boss it's not as developed but again
insurance fintech startups for saying do I partner with a big diamond and insurance company because I can't build my balance sheet as
if you choose to be a carrier in a carrier is the term to say to actually take the insurance under your balance sheet you have the liability choose to be
it's balance sheet intensive just how do you find your startup run weight loss because all the stored us tender have mods
of building out a network in building the platform itself clearly the competitive landscape the regulatory frameworks
regulatory frameworks do you get licenced again similar is Challenger Banks remember we talked about these neobanks and Challenger Bank switch off DP
in the same breath of the same but more specifically a neobank is something doing a lot of banking functions that is not yet got no backing
similar here if you're thinking about starting an insurance fintech for what type of licensing will you get was just be a brokerage licence
in various jurisdictions you have to register to be a broker or an agent or you actually registering to take lives on your balance sheet become a carrier
and then of course user adoption and the use of data and it hurts to the use of data there are quite the
it doesn't we have the same conceptual framework that you have to be fair and unbiased but there are quite the same lost like the equal credit after
the actor here in the US and it's the use of data as will see it a minute if you sign a waiver and say you can use my driving record
insurance is Alexandra did they can use that day at also on the claims management side it's not just a lower the cost
to see if you call up and say an accident they look at the tell about exits a did this really happened so the insured
landscape when I can dive into the slide but it's just each of these pieces each of these pieces it might be the church trying to go into the building and payments
which is rudimentary sort of you could be going all the way to another area and say we're going to be the best date and letter
wearables wearables how many people have a Fitbit anybody want to talk about whether you've signed up for insurance
that your insurance company can get your data off with your Fitbit HR off of your Apple watch off your off you know what you're using for
or exercise can lower your cost of insurance on a pause remain and don't see any hands up
NZ Street with the insurance but what I did have is at my former employer
program where we would connect or tracking devices like 4 steps and stuff with this program that like would give you
have you got so many steps a day so I get tons of gift cards because of all the steps I tracked in and that that I'm sure I was
the internet something you got to your 10,000steps or maybe they gave you a preview for 5000 steps you got
is Uber rewards that we all know about rewards programs in credit cards and that's part of that two and three quarter
interchange there's these rewards by your employer ultimately the economic incentives is the employer can have lower cost of Health and
that data through the inner mediation of your employment contract was lower and health insurance course for some group
insured I think your employer is also doing it because they know if you're better health it you are so few more days off you'll be you'll be so hopefully
better employee so there are so lowering some of their their course in terms of their direct course but it also relates to help ensure
so wearables trackables telematics and the internet of thing the internet of thing is a term
about senses and it's about senses in many items in our home as well if you have a home
security system in the last 5 or 10 years you've got it able to tie that into more data
security systems have four decades somehow had to communicate through a security company to lawn for us men if the
alarm went off but I'm talking about more flying to monitoring and we all aware even know that very few of us might have it that you can
apps on your phone that you can communicate with your home to turn on your heat for your air
monitor your home home monitoring devices that makes all of us maybe more comfortable than our home is secure
or even to have the communication from the home if for some reason there is a problem in the harm
Sanchez on refrigerators for sensors on HVAC heating and ventilation systems their census Road houses
I need to see this just absolutely mushroom it's Arms of such is so what's that day to do for the insurance field that's why I think insurtech and
in pentakis such an exciting and interesting place because we are basically in a transformational time right now in terms of sensor
no i g and embedding sensors into our economies not because of insurance but because many
uses one as sort of monitor either their home their automobile the wearable the trackable and now
with this this really challenging time around the Corona virus crisis we talking about contact tracing
call back contact racing could also be Fatty and depending upon the jurisdiction depending on the regulation into
insurance rates life insurance rates or any form of insurance again largely dependent upon
where is jurisdictions regulatory and legal frameworks so what are some of the possibilities you can become
ensure that means actually committing bow and she becoming licence taking claims on as a liability managing the assets
you can be a man it's generally jitt think broker it's just a term to say you could be managing agent or broker
who sells those ricotta the two big divide but you could just be on the technology side or the day to aggregation site these would have various
or insurtech startups we won't get through each one of them to see a common thing and there's less is
by and large or founded in the 2010s so this is 5 or 10 years of dynamic change
you're going to see heavy emphasis or homeowners in Autos so it's in the consumer space very similar to
credit you see a little bit moving into small business but not Lords commercial lines though both penguin is a commercial
exchange a lot is on the front and on the auto side you also get Marketplace comparisons just like in the credit space
it's basically Expedia for auto insurance so to speak you could say your Expedia for fill in the blank insurance these were the
please comparisons like cover hand and goji
throughout your see home and auto small business is kind of the dominant how many is there anybody use the product lemonade for rent
insurance
so lemonade Garden of the field basically to say it's so many people pretty clear the us or renting
we just watch some insurance for objects that are things in our homes and in case there's a problem or maybe the landlord says you
dad renters insurance policy bizarre bizarre about
years old one of the largest Marketplace comparison in India remarkable platform again
broadly speaking Expedia for health and life insurance you know where you can price compare policybazaar
of these various companies just pies a bit or route uses telematics to price the products honest everyone
Auto companies when here are using telematics and smartphone some of them started on telematics some store read more in this more
but the merger of those to the art of the oldest Bell claims management just slowly
focusing there and I said I was going to mention about China the last on this less than I probably will mispronounce how to say it song on
which formed by three very large companies online China
it's gone public since it's a very significant company in China it's the only online insurance
licensing in China so it shows the licensing it had the backing of 3 very large company 7 years ago it got said licence
and it has a certain advantage that to my knowledge I don't think anybody else has been there so gives you some of the smarter and I'm gonna pores
you see if there's any questions regret I think
healthcare healthcare finntack ID still call ensure attack some people can call healthtec this is the
laurenzside and how technology is coming and disrupt again you could be an any piece of this
shower from FTP partner's but you could be in any piece of the answer when you do the payment side I mean
lamb side and would it be in benefits management but any piece of that and so any again most of these are in the US but not
just some of what were say American well is about telehealth the very important thing now that were in in a period of time that we can
are there doctors in person Daniel seem most not all of these are in the last 10 years Clover which is a
coring almost all of these not all of these are unicorns meaning worth over billion dollars Clover is about taking out
facts about how we live our lives and trying to under eye and lower the cost to us probably the war
wines or bright health which is selling a Medicare advantage is in the US on top of Medicare which is
provided you can you can have an augmented program on top called Medicare advantage brighthouse clover
your CI so there is a significant number of companies that have died into the benefit administration this is working with small businesses
minister there benefits that affects that was formed in 2013 by 2015 we actually use benefits
Alfred I wasn't worth was a CFL of the Hillary Clinton campaign was a 2-year-old start up but we decided to go with better
because we could outsource to this vendor are benefits administration for
start-up that start-up ultimately proved unsuccessful is you now but over the course of time 5000 Floyd
all that benefit administration in the health care and silver ore and it's 04 zenefits health equities is in this fee
Real Health savings accounts help that's what he's actually bite in the last 2 years a company called wage works that I was I was
in which works was a startup company I went on their board and managed the hiring of a CFL and help wage work
to go public as a private company as a finntack years ago health equities bought that company which works
very significant and sbi's well see you ever sad it's the marrying of finance and health so I can be through the benefits and payroll administration size
finance for a compete directly Marketplace comparisons like Go Health which is similar to policybazaar in India
all of these little subfactors and slices data related is sort of the last little slice
this goes to the earlier question about Google and healthcare while we haven't seen big tech there I think that were bound to because there's so many date
Cambridge mobile telematics do not please don't confused with Cambridge analytica Cambridge motel at Maddox you can see
0 Dida aggregators that are collecting telematic dater they're not alone and then with that day to come
I sent it to insurance companies insurance companies as well as one of my favorites in this
nearest selling a product that in factories if your factory workers will wear some wearable not a
about some of its like around the mid mid chest it range but if they will wear a sensor
you can lower the cost of workplace insurance you can also hopefully make the workplace safer so they're selling a safe
why is injury protection what it's about software and hardware because they're selling the wearables and it's called stormtech
will it be successful spin around 9 years so we're seeing in insurance tech which I think is so fast
and potentially transformative is a whole world of a sensors and collecting alternative day to whether it's for America
go back to the telematics whether it's from our watches or a wearables are Fitbits
smartphones from the senses and our homes all the consider collect data little bit of machine learning
always deep machine learning deep learning with some machine learning lower the course Rodney and
potentially and then on the claims management side as well sensor technology collecting the day to lower the frauds in in the
is one from the Braggs that they have the shortest claim settlement period that an online app was able
claim settlement down to less than minutes and I think there was one claim that was settled in seconds it was an order
it was something that could do quite quickly check the logically but I also think that it was a bit of them a marketing thing that they wanted to say you could get claims
countdown 2 minutes so that's a little bit of review