ok so let's let's go and get started till what is
is no complication no science used to be a very descriptive field where you would describe
the different kinds of Norris who here is seen the famous pictures the old pictures of the Golgi stained neuronz
different types of Lawrence describing what things look like in the brain and what parts of the brain are important for
bar behaviour based on the Asian studies it used to be extremely descriptive but things are changing in their sights and have to change dramatically over the past few
really neuroscience now is about understanding the brain how the brain works how the brain produces behaviour and really trying to
engineering level descriptions of brain systems and brain circuits and norah's and ion channels in all the components of Lawrence that make the brain
cancel for example the level of description that my lab works at in that I'm most excited
r s sort of understanding how the circuits how norms are put together to make neural circuits that implement behaviours or or
are to produce object recognition figure from Jim dicarlo who is our department head basically Circuit
scription of how the brain goes from a visual stimulus to a recognition of white that object is in the in the stimulus
time that there's been a big push toward understanding or generating for engineering level descriptions of brands and circuits and components
there is also been tremendous advances in the the technologies that we can use to recorder on throat so there are
imaging systems in microscopes that can image thousands of nor and simultaneously this says an example
have a movie recorded in a in a wake baby Mouse that's basically dreaming ok and I mean
what does looks like so this is a mouse that has a fluorescent protein that's sensitive to normal activity and so when you're is in a part of
become a activate they become fluorescent and light up and so here is it top surface of the mouses brain and you can see this
continuous activity sort of flickering around is this mouse is just sort of dreaming and thinking about whatever it's thinking about
so that one of the key challenges is to take images like this that had that represent the activity of thousands of narancia millions of
and figure out how to relate that to the circuit models that are being developed so here is another example so there are these
probs where is a basically silicone probs that have thousands of little sensors on them and and a computer here that basically read out the
activities are pulp nopixel so basically electrodes there can again record from thousands of neuron's simultaneously in there quite long
record throughout the whole brain essentially all at once this very high dimensional dataset
how do you relate that to the circuit models that you are developing it's a one of the key challenges in neuroscience is to
very large datasets that you know that look like this that just going to look like a mass and figure out what's going on underneath their ok turns out
people are discovering that you know why you might be recording from tens of thousands of nora's and it looks really messy but there's some underlying very simple structure
underneath of there but you can see it when you just looked at big collections of ne on site that's ok so I saw the
here is really to figure out how to not only just make those models by test them by taking data and relating the patterns of activity that you see
very high dimensional datasets do dimensionality reduction compress that dated down into a simple representation and then relate it
models that you developed one of the things were going to try to do in this class is 2
why these techniques of making models of meringues and circuits together with mathematical tools for analysing data
context of looking at animal behaviours for example in my lab we study how how song
sing how they learn to produce the vocalisations song Bros learn by imitating her parents that listen to their parents
ok
Venice
I was having a girl
ok so this is just a set up showing how we can record from neuronz in
Wilder singing and figure out how those circuits work to produce the song by this is at little Michael drive that we built it's it's motorised so that we can move these
what's around independently in the brain and record from Lauren's without the animal knowing that were like moving the electrodes around and looking for neuron's then the birds
Sun guitar really cool they listen to the parents they store a memory of what their parents thing and then they begin babbling and they practice over and over again until they can learn it
the of this song is a bird that singing with the microdrive on it's head and you can hear them run in the background sorry it's it's not over the loudspeaker Hill
you can everyone here that so so we can record from nose while the bird is singing look at the activity in this in this
and try to figure out how that network actually works to produce the song and also we can recording very young birds and figure out how the song is actually
and there is an example of generating action potentials which is the the basic
communication in the brain and ok and then we belt the we try to build
how old is in figure out how that how that thing actually works to produce and learn the song
tell tell these computational approaches that I'm talking about it or not just important for dissenting brain circuits related to behaviour
go the same kinds of approaches the same kind of dimensionality reduction techniques for gonna learn are also useful in molecular
genetic studies taking a transcriptional profiling and doing clustering and looking at the different pattern instead of there it's also useful for Michael
how do you say it's also these ideas are very powerful and studying a cognition so the so if you'd like it to work the Josh tanenbaum does and
McDermott study to develop mathematical models of how our minds work how we learn to think about things those are also
model based in very quantitative so the kind of working alone in this class of very broadly applicable they're also increasingly important in medicine
soul where can I get some point working to take a little bit of a detour to look at a particular disease that's caused by
in fact in an ion channel and it turns out you can understand exactly how that the fact that I am channel relates to this particular to
a type of the disease ok you can do that by creating a mathematical model of how a noren behaves when it has an ion channel that has this defective
very quiet and once you model that you can really understand why that happens ok so here are some of the course goes so
we're going to start by working on basic biophysics ignorant in networks and other that sort of principles underlying brain and cognitive functions were going to develop maths
all techniques to analyse those models and to analyse the kinds of behavioral data and normal dated that you would take to to study those brain surgery
and in the along the way we're going to become proficient at using MATLAB to do these things so how many of you have Xperia
MATLAB OK great and not ok so anybody who doesn't have experience with MATLAB we're going to
really make an effort to bring you up to speed very quickly Daniel has actually just created a very nice MATLAB cheat sheet that's just amazing
sell Daryl be like to help with programming some of the topics that will be covering so will be talking
equivalent Circuit model of explain how this is broken down so these are topics that we're
and these are sorry the mathematical tools that go along with those topics that will be learning about in parallel ok so will be starting normal
sex and we'll be doing some difference equations a long way for that just first order linear difference equations and I think to be scared out I will talk about normal response
the stimuli and tuning curves and along the way will be learning about spike sorting in Perth stimulus time Instagrams and ways of analysing Byron patterns
coding and receptive fields and will learn about correlation and convolution for that topic we'll talk about feed-forward networks in percent
we're gonna start bringing a lot of linear algebra which is really fun it's really powerful and that linear algebra sets
stayed for than doing dimensionality reduction on data and principal component analysis and singular value decomposition other things
then take an additional extension of neural networks from feed for an hour so figure out how to make them talk back to themselves so they can
doing things like remember things ok and make decisions and that involves more linear algebra eigenvalues and then
I'm not sure we're going to get time to sensory integration and bass rock so by the end of the class there are some important skill
that you're have are you able to think about a noren very clearly and how it's components work together to give
Iran it's properties and how Normans themselves can connect together to give anal Circuit it's properties
attack write MATLAB programs that simulate those models you'll be able to analyse data using MATLAB your bill to Visual
high dimensional datasets and you one of my goals in this class is that you guys should be able to go into any lab in the department
call things that even the graduates to his benighted do ok it so you can do really great stuff as you're up
ok so one of the most important things about the
class is problem sets because that's where you're going to get the hands on experience to do that kind of that analysis and write programs and an
the data please install that it's really important if you don't already have that Wheels like scripts for prom sets
and Daniel made some nice examples on Stella and of course that the guidelines for peace at submissions are also on Stella
that's it any questions about that so let's let's go ahead and
and get started than with the first topic
ok so the first thing we're going to do is we're going to build a model of a Nerang
this model is is very particular it uses electrical components to to describe then you're on now that mean
prising sense in Iran is basically an electrical device it has components that are sensitive to voltage is that generate current that control current
are answer we're going to build a model using electrical circuit components and one of the nice things about doing that is that every electrical search
like a resistor a capacitor has a very well-defined mathematical relation between current and the voltage
close to that device and the voltage across the terminals of that by so you can write down very precisely mathematically what each of those compose
so then you can then take that all those components and construct a set of
or in general a set of differential equations that allows you to basically evolved that circuit overtime and plotly
voltage I'm inside the cell as a function of time you can see that that model moron can actually very precisely replicate many
properties of Norris actually really complicated and this is this is the real reason why you need to write
there are many different kinds of Lawrence each type of Iran has a different pattern of genes that are expressed so this is a cluster diagram
call type based on a transcriptional profiling of the RNA that each that I think it was about $13,000 on that were extracted from a part of the
you do the transcriptional profiling gives you up a map of all the different genes are expressed in each Laurent and then you can Costa them and you can see that the
part of the brain which is in the hypothalamus expresses all of these different cell types what are those different sheets many of the
paintings are actually different ion channels and there are hundreds of different kinds of ion channels that control the flow of current through across the Membrane of a Nora
cancel this is just a diagram showing different potassium ion channels different calcium ion channels you can see they have families and and
subtypes in all of those different ion channels have different time scales on which the current varies as a function of voltage change they have different voltage
what's the third sensitive to have different inactivation so many ion channels when you turn them on is stay on but other ion channels they turn on and then they slow
Decay away break the current slowly 2 k's away and inactivation and all these different ion channels have different combinations of those properties and it's really
hard to predict when you think about how this Nerang will behave with a different kind of ion channel here it's super hard
just like look at the properties of an ion channel and just see how that's going to work in Andorra because you have all these different parts that are working together ok
Gillian Porter bill to write down a mathematical model if you have an Iran it has I could different kinds of iron tell you can actually predict how the door is going to behave
no that's just the ion channel components Laurels also have complex morphologies right there has some some morons have the
this is a n t cell in the cerebellum they have these very dense densely elaborated dendrites other animals have very long dendrites with just a few branches
I don't have very short stubby dendrites and each of those different morphological patterns also affects however
response to it's Imports because now I'm out here at the end of the day or a course to the Soma and and
what does the spatial structure also affect our non-response and and those produced very different firing panel so not Sumner
if you put in a constant current they just buy a regulator so turns out we can really understand why all of these things different
things happen if we build a model actress
different parts of the circuit actually do call different things so neuron's have are not just one power supply they've got multiple power
hi is the power up different parts of the circuit that do different things have capacitances that allow unknown to accumulate
overtime act as an integrated if you combine a capacitor with a resistor that that circuit now looks like a foot
it's smooth it's past inputs overtime alright and these two components here this sodium current and this potassium make a spike
generates an action potential that then talks to other nerds ok and you put the whole thing together and that thinking act like an oscillator it can act like a coin
detector that can do all kinds of different call things and all that stuff is understandable if you just write down a simple
any questions ok so what we're going to do is we're going to
describing this network we're gonna build it up One Piece at a time and we're going to
with a capacitance but before we get to the capacitor we need to do one more thing we need to do one thing first which is bigger
wires are in the brain break an electrical circuit you need to have wires so what are the wires in the rain
what wires do in a circuit so what what what
in anora what's that carry information
like that the travels down the axon a ghost other Norris but there's even not simpler answer than that yes
ion channels are these resistors here but what is it that connects all those components to each other
is the intracellular and extracellular solution ok and so what we're going to do today is understand how the intracellular
cellular solution acts as a wire and it's not just it's not quite as simple as it as a piece of metal
hey it's it's a bit more complicated there different ways you can get current flow in in intracellular and extracellular solution
can I go through that and we're going to analyse that in some some detail in the brain
why is our our intracellular and extracellular salt solutions and you get current flow that results from the movement of eyes
in that aqueous solution so so the solution concesso ions like in exercise
mostly sodium ions and chloride ions that are dissolved in water what is a polar solvent that means that the negative parts that the oxygen
slightly negatively charged oxygen is attracted to a positive ions ok and the intracellular and extracellular space are filled with salt
at a concentration of about 100 mm and that corresponds to having one of these ions
about every 25 angstroms apart so at those concentrations there are a lot of
and I was Iron can move under different conditions to produce currents
current flow in the brain through to primary different mechanism diffusion which is caused by
variations in the concentration ok and drifts of particles in an electric field so when you put an electric fields of
a beaker filled with salt solution you put two metal electrodes in it to produce an electric field that causes these ions to drift in
and that's another source of current that we're going to look at today so here are our learning object
for today we're going to understand how the time scales of diffusion relate to the length scale and that's a really interesting story that's very important
we're going to understand how concentration gradients lead to currents that's not as fix first law and we're going to understand
charges drifting electric field in a way that leads to current and the mathematical relation that describes voltage differences
that is called Ohm's law in the brain and we're going to learn about the concept of resistivity
so the first thing we need to talk about if we're going to talk about the Fusion is thermal energy so every particle in the world is being done
by other particles that are crashing into it and at thermal equilibrium every degree of freedom every way that
call can move either forward and backward left and right up and down or rotations this way or this way or whichever way I didn't
come to equilibrium at a particular energy is proportional to temperature in other words
particle is moving in this direction in equilibrium if we're having kinetic energy in that direction that is equal to that is proportional to the
temperature is is in units of Calvin relative to absolute zero and the proportionality constant is the boltzmann constant
connects of drawers per Kelvin Sony x the boltzmann constant k x temperature what you find is
Freedom will come to equilibrium at 4 x 10 - 21 joules which is in amount of energy
room temperature at zero temperature you can see that every degree of freedom has zero energy and so nothing is moving nothing is rotating the
morning any direction everything is perfectly still ok so let's calculate how
fast particles move at thermal equilibrium in room temperature so we can may remember from
breast physics class that the kinetic energy of a particle is proportional to the velocity squared one have MV squared so the average velocity
have a particle at thermal equilibrium it's just 1/2 times that much energy
it how fast like a particle is moving for example a sodium ion so you can see that the
Fred velocity squared is just Katie of RAM we just divide both sides by
to the velocity average life his greatest 10 of the 5 m squared per second squared to take the square of that and you get the average locity is 320 m
set me a set the air molecules which have a similar mass to the study of mind
300 metres per second so I would cross this room in a few hundreds of a second game
gold wedding along at 300 m per second what happens to them
when do each other there are crashing into into each other constantly ok so in solution apareco Collides with a water
every about 10 of the 13 times per second 10 of the -13 seconds between collisions moving a little
moving a letter from Direction crash in moving in a different direction crashing ok so it's just if you follow one particle is just kind of jumping around
ok it's diffusing so what does that look like that Daniel made a little video that shows sort of 2 scale this is possession in
and time is in real time so this video shows in real-time what the motion of a particle might look like
Kennedy point it's just moving it it's moving colliding and moving off in some random Direction
you actually see this if you look at a very small particle
who was the tenure who did that experiment looking at pollen is brownian a brown what was his first name
brownian motion have you got a brownian motion so somebody named Brown was looking at Holland particles in water and noticing the
letter Jump Around just like this and he hypothesize that there were being just All Around by the water
ok any questions ok so
what can we say about this there's there's something really interesting about diffusion it's that's very at non-intuitive it first
Asian some really strange aspect to it that it distance that a particle can defuse depends very much on the Thai
and it's not just a simple relation so let's just look at this so let's ask how much time does it take for an iron
to defuse a short distance like across the but the salvo the Soma of an Era so an iron can diffuser
the song of an era in about the 20th of the 2nd how about down so let's
Orion in the cell body and asked how long does it take an iron to reach the end of a dendrite that can be about a millimetre away
can take about 10 minutes that's how long it will take an iron to get that far away from it's starting point
how about frequency 20th of August 2nd here here it's like 5500 seconds
but 10 minutes about how long does it take an iron starting at the cell body to defuse all the way down so you know there are no words in your body that start
spinal cord and all go all the way down to your feet so motoneurons in your spinal cord can be very long accents
trying to get from from the Soma all the way down to the end of an accident along axon
somebody just take a gas it's 20th of the 2nd here 10 minutes
anybody want to get an hour 10 years ok
why is that that's crazy right how is that password.in so you know that a cell body is making proteins in or
stop that have to get down to build synapses at the other end of that accident and and proteins diffuser hack about slower than irons do so so
a submarine could make stuff for that for the axon it would never get there in your entire lifetime and that's why cells have to
make little trains that they literally make little trains that package up stuff and put it on the train and it just marches down the axon until it gets to the
to that to the end and this is the reply ok so we're going to do is I'm going to just walks you through a very simple there
a why this is true and how do think about it ok to do so normally things defuse in three dimensions
but it's just my charger to analyse things you can get you can get basically the right answer just by analysing how things diffuse in one dimension
tell me the story of video to show show you what this looks like this is I think 100 particles or lined up near zero and we're going to turn on the video
I'm also defusing it one moment ok so you can just watch what happens to all these different particles
end up over here on the left other particles end up over here on the right you can see that the distribution of particles kind of spreads out
ok it's already pick up why that is where why that happens so the first thing I just want to tell you is that the
population of particles if they all start at zero ok in a diffuser 1D away from zero the distribution that you get is gaussian
ok and the basic reason is that started the centre and every time that they have a probability of one half of going to the right and one half of going to the
cancel basically there are many more combinations of ways a particle can do some laughs and do some rice and end
quote started it's very unlikely that the particle will do like a whole bunch of going right all in a row and so that's why it's
the density in the distribution is very low down here ok and so you end up with something that's just a gaussian distribution
so let's say let's to analyse this in a little more detail so we're going to just make a simple very simple model of particles
to the right or to the left we're going to consider a particle that is
operated a fixed velocity VX4 sometime towel before a collision and working imagine the each time the particle collider resets it's
randomly either to the laughter to the right every time will step right by a distance Delta
velocity times the time tower and the other have two particles will step left by that same distance OK so they're going to either to the left or the right
to the right by a distance Delta if we start with n particles
all of them started position 0 at x 0 then the we can write down the position of
protocol a time step I sorry time step and ice particle a time step and we're going to the each particles
doing their own thing ignoring each other so now you can see that you can write down the position of
miracle at time step n is just the position of the particle at the previous time step plus or minus this little Delta
any any questions by that ok
if you ever just haven't followed one step that I do I've just let me know I'm happy to explain it again I asked them I'm watching somebody
something really simple and my brain is just in some funny state and I'm I just don't get it so it's totally fine if you
I mean explain something that you don't have to be embarrassed cause happens to me all the time ok so now what we can do is use this expression
compute how that distribution involves over time that distribution of particles this does ice particle overtime
time step in the average position of the ensemble is so these brackets mean average so the bracket with an I
that I'm averaging this quantity over I particles ok so it's just the sum of positions
for every protocol divided by the number of particles that the average position so again the position of the ice particle time step and it's just the
record the previous time step plus or minus Delta we just plug that into their into there and now we calculate the sun but we have to terms we
and that turn lights break them up in the two separate sums so this is equal to the sum over the previous positions plus the sun
how much the change was from one time step to the next that make sense but what is this song for something
all the particles how much they changed from the previous time step to this time stop what half of the move to the right in the left
so that song It's just 0 can see that the average position of the particle at this of the park
at this time step is just equal to the average position of the particles at the previous times that means is that the centre of the distribution chain
if you stole the particles that 0 they defuse around the average position is still 0
this year
just herself this bracket means I'm averaging over this quantity I so you can see that's what I'm doing something all right and dividing by the number
particle particle number so if we have 10 particles I goes from 1 to 10 thank you
ok so that's boring but we use the wheels to trick here
where can I use now to actually calculate the interesting thing which is on on average how far to the particles get from where they started
calculate the average position of all the protocols were going to calculate the average absolute value
where they started ask on average how far do they get from where they started wood 40
so absolute values not really likes the hard to deal with but this is exactly
the same as calculating the square root of the average square the same as calculating
that make sense ok so what we're going to do as we're going to calculate the variance of that distribution I am the square root of that various is just the start
deviation which is just how wide it is which is just how far on average the particles got from where they started
ok so let's push on we're going to calculate the average square distance that was going to take the square that at the end
so the average of the position squared we're going to plug this into here ok so ring a square it so the
turn on the particle squared is just this quantity squared let's Factor it out so we have this term squared + that twice that times that
what's that term square ok and we're going to now plug that average so the average position squared is just
the average position squared at this time step and is the average position squared at the previous time step
plus some other stuff and I take a look at what that other stuff is this is posture - 2 times
which is the step it takes the size of the staff times at so what is what is that average of these are positive
these are -0 and 1 it is the average of Delta Square Road Delta
is always positive right so what is this say what this says is that that parents
at best time step is just the variance at a previous time step is a constant is that what does
is the each time step the various grows by some constant Delta is a distance
the units of variance of a distribution at the function of Distance if the various at x 0
direct me to all lined up at the Origin 1 x two-player the various will be Delta squared the next time step it will be two Delta square the next time step
up at some time step and it will be an x Delta square so you see what's happening the variance this distribution is growing linearly
we can change from time steps to continuous time so time step
time that time then step number is just time the tower which is some interval in time like the in
twinkle Asian it so you can see that the variance is just growing linearly in time where the variance is just 2 time
e x t where d is the is what we call the diffusion coefficient is just length squared / time
why is that because as time grows the variance
so if we want to get from we want to take time x something that gives
variance it has to be variance per unit time and variance for something that the distribution of disease
has to have position square yes ok it's just the
built into the definition of the diffusion constant ok
any questions about that so now what I can tell you so and now here here is the answer
so the variance is going linearly in time what that means is that the standard deviation distance the average distance from the start
is growing as the square root of time and that's that's key out that I want you to remember
the distance
fuses from it's starting point on average gross is the square root of time
ok so pretty small molecule typical small molecule the diffusion constant is 10 of -5
metre squared per second we can just plug in some distances and times and see what how long
Lexapro how long it takes this particle to defuse some distance ok so it's do that lets plug in a length of 10 microns that was arse Omar
what's $10 - 3 cm time is that squared Lang square so it's 10 of -6 cm
divided by the diffusion constant 2 times the diffusion constant 2 x 10 - 5 cm squared per second is 6 m squared cancel that leaves us
50 milliseconds in 1 mm that was the length of the dendrite
so that's 10 of the -1 centimetre so we plug that into our equation for time time is just l square I forgot to actually
is the equation that I'm solving so what is the equation of
squared is equal to 2 DT and I'm strolling 40 squared over to see that's that's the question I'm so
I'm giving you a length and I'm calculating how long it takes
so if you put in 10 of -1 here you get 10 of the -2 / 2 x 7 seconds which is about 10 minutes
how if you ask how long does it take to go a metre that's 10 of the 2 cm it's 10 of the 4/10 - 5
somebody over here figured it out right away about 5 x 10 of 8
a year is pi x 10/72 + 4 - 50%
ok questions birthday
call Sona runes and South and biology has
to extraordinary lengths to overcome this craziness
which explains a lot of the structure you see in cells ok
so there's another so that's at so you can see the diffusion causes the movement of iron
from places where their concentrated to places where there are so many iron straight so let's take a little bit slightly more
look at that idea so am I tell you but now I fix first lot in the ideas Fusion producers are Netflix particles from regions of high concept
the regions of low lower concentrate and the flux of particles is proportional to the concentration gradient I know this is just really up it's
if you have a box and on the left side of the box you have particles that on the right side of the box then you're going to have party
refusing from here to there you're going to have particles defusing from there to there but because there are more of them over here they're just going to be more particles going this way
then our that way here still has
and have a 50% chance of diffusing here or staying here diffusing somewhere else in particles here also equally have probability of going out of the way but just because
more of them here there's going to be more particles going that way you can just calculate the number of particles going this way -
number of particles going that way alright and I'll give you the net number of particles going to the right but what what is that look like
you have the number here minus the number distance away and what if you were to divide that by
the distance what would it look like looks like a derivative so if you can't collect the flux
it's minus the diffusion constant as one of the Delta the separation between these boxes the concentration here minus the concentration there and that
it's just a derivative and that's fixed first one I have a few slides at the end of the lecture that that do this derivation
more completely so please take a look at that if you have time OK this is
an important concept ok this fix for slot the fact that particles that concentration gradients produce a flow of ions of
is so fundamental to Hannah aren't work in here we're going to be building that up over the course of the next couple actress
so imagine that you have a cell that has a lot of potassium ions inside and very few potassium ions outside and you can see that
you're going to have potassium ions diffusing from here to sorry and I forgot to say let's say that you're so all in it so are you going to help
defusing from inside the outside through the whole you also have some potassium ions out here and some of those my defuse in but they're just
how many more potassium ions inside and outside concentration wise with the probability of 1 going out through the holes just much higher than the probability of a potassium
back into the song sorry I'm just zooming in on that channel
or through the Membrane lots of potassium ions here on average there is going to Netflix potassium out through that hole
are we can plot the concentration gradient through the whole thing can see it's high hear it decreases and it's low outside
answer there is a netflow this proportional to that steepness of concentration profile
true you get a netflow even if each particle is diffusing independently they don't know anything about each other and yet that can't
next ingredient produces a current or concentration gradients go away white why is that
calcium ions will flow from the inside of the sail to the outside of the South Island toll they're the same concentration and then you have Justice
play back inside as you have flying outside so eventually that would happen to other cells why doesn't that happen
what that that's that's exactly the right a few intervene in a intermediate steps
if you would not be alive anymore the potassium ions which just a fuse out and that would be the end but what happens is
other iron that other proteins in the Membrane that takes those potassium ions from here and pump them back inside and maintain the concentration gradient but that cost energy
does proteins use ATP and that ATP comes from eating ok
but eventually are concentration gradients go away so so
that is how we get current flow from concentration gradients the next topic has to do with the diffusion
in in the presence of voltage differences in the presence of voltage gradients
ok the bottom line here that I want you to know that I want you to understand is that current flowing around or Bay zones what does that mean
why do we have a resistor aleksei across a membrane or in the intracellular and extracellular space of a
the current flow through that resistive medium is proportional to the
is different the current is proportional to the voltage difference across the two terminals that
and the proportionality constant is one of the resistance so here current
MP is the voltage difference is units of bolts and the resistance has units of ohms
questions about that ok so let's go through let's develop this ideal
understand why it is that a voltage difference produces a current that's proportional to voltage
salt solution ions in here dissolved in the water we have two metal plates we put a battery between the two metal place that holds those two
get some fixed voltage difference delta-v and we're going to ask how much what happens ok
you've been here there's one plate that's it one potential there's another played at another potential there some voltage difference between those that's Delta v the two plates are
play distance Al and that that voltage difference produces an electric field
the points from the high voltage region to the low voltage region
so an electric field produces a force on a charge we have lots of charges in here that's proportional to the charge
and the electric field so what is that Force going to do that force is just going to rag that particle
the liquid through the water so why why is it
Bestway vacuum in here and we put up a charge there and metal plates and we put a battery across what would that particle do
Edward it would move but what what would this force due to that protocol exactly so it would have Aussie
we're just increase when you start moving it will start moving slowly and crash into the plate
now what happens here why is that stuff in the way and so it keeps it it's accelerate and
get hit by Watermark your right and it gets pushed off in summer some direction then accelerate in this direction gets it again but it's
accelerated in One Direction before it Collides ok it so here's what happens
diffusing around great but I'm eating
up as a little bit of acceleration in this direction in the direction of the electric field
so you can show kind of using the same kind of an app that I that we used in calculate
the distribution that the changes mean and variance you can show that the mean of the other distribution
pause that starts at 0 positive particles shifts in the in the electric field linearly in time
and you can just think about that as you know the electric field reaches and grab that charged particle and like poles it in this direction
viscous drag so now a force produces a constant velocity acceleration
is called the drift velocity so the force is proportional to drift velocity
what is that what is that little after it's the coefficient of friction
an Einstein Clovelly noticed that the coefficient of friction of a particle being dragged through a liquid
is related to White any gas Fusion about particle
that qualities like gonna give me chill the frictional coefficient is just 8000
diffusion constant so if you actually just go through that same analysis of calculating the mean of the distribution what you find is that
moves linearly and type it also if you take if you take put your hand and and you know you're in the swimming pool you put
in the water and you push your hand with a constant force what happens what let me flip it around you move your hand through the water at a constant
what is the force feel like
yes exactly
me the same thing ok so the drift velocity is proportional to the force
proportionality constant one over the the coefficient of friction which is the no deal and what is this force proportional to
the force is proportional to the electric field right and
so let's calculate the current so I'm going to argue that the current is proportional to the drift velocity times the area
a why is that so I have an electric field it makes this particles all the particles in this area here
is there a constant velocity in this direction so there is a certain amount of current that's flowing in this area right here
that makes sense now if my electrodes are are big and I also have electric field up here than that like 6 cars and current
appear to and if there's electric field appear then there'll be current flowing up here to it so you can see that the amount of current That's Falling between the
is proportional to the drift velocity and the cross-sectional area between the two electrodes
cancel that's really important let's now I showed you I told you that or we figured out that the
velocity is proportional to the electric field right so that current is proportional to the electric the times the area and the electric field is just
search difference / spacing between the electrodes bright and so the current is proportional to voltage times area / length
can we have a proportionality current is proportional to voltage times area / length and now let's plugin what that tonality constant
hey we're going to let's let's think about this is now like Ohm's law or right
is proportional to voltage difference that the proportionality constant here is something called resistivity otherwise known as
but we're going to use resistivity
difference let's rewrite that a little bit so that it looks more time slot current is proportional to voltage difference
and that thing that thing is right there should have units of what one over owns so that
1 over resistance let's just write down what the resistances resistance is resistivity x length / area
does stop and take a breath and think about why this make sense resistance is how
resistance there is to flow at a given voltage rate so what happens if we make are really small what happens to the resistance
the the resistance gets back the amount of current get small because there's la select Plus
go to the Electric Feel This is in it so the Chromecast down and miss the resistances we make up late really big the resistance Get Smart
what happens if we pour plates further apart what happens to the resistance of the plates are four
hotel is bigger and resistance is bigger but what's going on physically what's the plates of further apart so what happens
write the voltage difference is the same but the distance is bigger and so the electric field which is voltage per
distance is smaller and that's smaller electric field produces drift velocity and that's why the resistance
goes up ok now let's start
about resistivity resistivity in the brain is really really lousy ok the the wires of the brain
I just offal ok so if you look at the resistivity for copper which is which is the wire that you
Electronics the resistivity is 1.6 micro ohms centimetres ok what time is if I took a block of copper
centimetre on a side when I put electrodes on the side of it and I measure the resistance it would be 1.6 micro homes
amp thing with 1.6 microvolts
ok the resistivity of the brain is 60 ohm-cm
a centimetre block of saline solution intracellular extracellular discussion has a resistance of
the ohms instead of 1.6 micro homes more than a million times worse ok
what that means is that when you try to send current brand-new Strata sense of current the ball
just drops you need a huge voltage drops to produce tiny currents and that's why
has that's why the brain has invented things accidents because the wires are
bad that you can't send a signal from one part of the brain to another part of the brain Through The Wire you have to invent this special gimmick called an action potential
signal more than a few microns away pretty cool right
why it's so interesting to understand the basic physics of something the basic mechanisms by which something works because
what you see is a hack to compensate for weird physics rate yes
this High
you're asking what causes that high resistivity yeah it basically has to do with things like the mean free path of
the particle in a metal particles can go further effectively before they collide so there
resistivity of is Lauren no it's a property of it's a little bit different inside the cell because there's more gunk inside of a sold in there
outside of a silencer the resistivity is a little bit worse it's 2000 centimetres are 102000 inside the cell in more like 60 outside
yes what's your outside the cell it's basically the same everyone
ok so that's it so here's what we learnt about today we understood
the difference that the relation between the timescale of diffusion and length scales we learnt that the distance that are particle can can defuse
what is the girls only is the square root of time concentration gradient
and we are we talked about fix first layer that says that concentration differences leader particle flux the flux is proportional
the gradient of the derivative of the concentration and we also talked about how the drift of charge of charged particles in an electric field
2 occurrence and how that the voltage current relation of a zones line we also talked about the concept of
Liberty and how the resistivity in the brain is really high and makes the wires in the brand really bad ok so bad
I have I will take any questions yes ok
any questions great so we will see you when is the
tomorrow so I will see you Thursday