the phone can't answer is provided under a Creative Commons licence your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality
resources for free to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of mit courses MIT opencourseware at ocw
am i t daddy you today is give a very brief introduction to nearest circuits why we study them how it started and and the possibilities
I'm out of understanding biological clothes and trying to translate those ideas Into Temptation Alcoa then I will be a bit more specific and discuss some initial at times at start
completion role of feedback sitting out and then I was switch gears and talk for a few minutes about couple things that are not related to sit with me
Rio work on particular side about in the context of open question challenges and opportunities and I think we'll catch up an over the next several years in
inspiring set of you to actually solve some of these open questions in the field why I'm very excited about study
biology in studying brains is that our brains are the product of millions of years of evolution through evolution we have discover how to do things that are
casting fast efficient and so if you can understand the biological possible can understand the machinery by which we do all of these amazing feats then in Brisbane
listen to the dictate how we see how are you can recognise objects are we can recognise or literary events ensure the answer to all of this during questions
ski then somewhere here inside our brain so the question is how can we listen to Nirvana Circuit decoder activity Movin right information in the
I can change the translate all of the ideas into computational cost a lot of fascinating properties that biological codes carb needless to say when
play There Yet in terms of computers and Ann and Rosie are hardware and software work for many decades I think it's very unlikely that you're amazing iPhone
6 or 5 or 7 or whatever it is will last four five six seven eight nine decades known about computers will last that long our hardest
amazing Isla competition going on in our brains this is quite this thing from the way we think about I got him some competition in other domains now brain suburb
how will architecture the same chunk of tissue can be used for several purposes through learning and through our experiences we can modify those architectures
cardless cash been quite interesting and then maybe we'll come back to the notion of being able to do single shot learning I supposed to some machine learning algorithms required
lots of data to train we can you send the discover structure in Darra the notion of fault tolerance and robustness to transformations
1 robots are released from the mental property of biology and one that has been very very hard to implement in computational circuit and print nearest
how to have different systems integrate information and interact with each other has been and continues to be a fundamental challenge do that all the time when walking down the
is it going to rain this information with all this information with our target our plans were interested in doing and social interactions and someone
are there any red circle so I think we are in the golden era right now but we can begin to explore the answer to some of these storing questions in brain said there is a logical level
study high-level country phenomena at the level of new on Sunsuper some examples of that later on
how to this towards the end we've had the opportunity to begin to manipulate and disrupt and interact with Nitro Circus at an unprecedented resolution so
can begin to turn on and off specific set of neurones and that has tremendously accelerated are possibility to test series at general
and then again the notion being that empirical finance can be translated into compilation with it really understand how biology solve the problem
invincible should be able to write mathematical equations and then write code that mimics some goes some patience and some examples of that we talked about in the visual system
change into Carlos presentation advertising for a couple of books that I find interesting and relevant in competition your science and haven't got time to do any
today in our field of competition your science at all so all this lights will be in Dropbox so if anyone wants to know more about completion your size this are lot of a tremendous
L'Oreal Batista of this one and kill been talking tonight
view internal techniques to probe function of rain circuits and this is showing the temporal resolution of different techniques and
solution of different techniques used to study the surface all the way from evenings that have limited spatial and temporal resolution such act and and
thicknesser very high temporal resolution really poor facial recognition all the way to techniques that allow us to interrogate the functions of individual
within your arms what I'm going to talk about today is what we refer to as the nearest Circuit level somewhere in between single neurones and then samples of neurones
potential solution of MS where we think it's were lot of the competitions in cortex are happening and where we think we can begin to elucidate how
interact with each other very beginning we need to understand what a neural gas and again this is probably a good familiar with these
basic fundamental understanding of what is to integrate information to cease information through it's then Rise interested information and decides whether
acquire a spike or not interestingly some basic intuition Survivor on a function were essentially conceived by a spaniel Monica
you wanted to be an artist his parents told him that he's not coming out this week is to become a finishing a medical doctor so he follow the tradition he became a medic
then he said well what I really like doing is drawing and so he bought microscope people in his kitchen and he spent a good chunk of his life drawing
look at neurones and he would rather and their shapes and that's essentially how neuroscience started just from this beautiful an amazing array of
conjecture the basic flow of information this notion the disintegration of information through then tries all this integration happens in the Soma and from there news
play will it to firespike on that nothing more nothing less that's essentially they did the fundamental unit of computation in our brains how do we
put on those processes this family of different types of models that people have used to describe what a new does this molars defer
in terms of their biological accuracy in their computational complexity one of the most used one is perhaps we need to read in Pioneer on this is a very soon
RC Circuit in basically integrates current and then she'll the new undersides went to fire or not a fire
essentially treating neurones as Point mass is there are people out there who have argued that you need more and more detail you need to know exactly how many dendrites you haven't
extend write an on and on and on what's the exact solution at which we should study assistance is a fundamental open question will know what's the
attraction there people to think about brains in the context of blood flow and millions and millions of neurones average together they are people who sing the you actually need to pay attention
the exact details of how every single then drive integrates information and so on for many of us this is a sufficient level of attraction ocean division around that
integrate information so we like to push this notion that we can think about mothers with single neurones and see how far we can go understanding that we're ignoring
of their inner complexity of what's happening inside in Yeronga
science it's very very easy to build this intermittent fire model simulations I know many if you do this on a on a daily basis this is the equation of this art
the current that flows through a capacitance this current that flows through the the resistance which we think of us this artistica to think of a camp
ion channels in the Membrane of the neurones and and this is all the rest are all those to eat in terms of a lot of the simulation that we use to understand the function of neurones
I can just tell you that there's nothing scary or a fundamentally difficult about this he's just a handful of lines in MATLAB that you can take a look at if you've never done this
what simulations this is very simple and perhaps even wrong simulation of an integration and an Italian
how to build models of Indian around this fundamental properties of being able to integrate information and side went to Paris by questions
really want to tackle in in cm comfortable with putting together lots of neurones and understanding the function of Circuit it's not enough to understand in 2020
are there interactive together we won't understand what is there who's there what are they doing to whom and when and why we need to understand
did you off most Williams together in the form of circuitry definitions in the circuitry like these where we Start Connecting
Dr Paul nirens together information flows here in the circuitry in this direction we refer to the connections between your arms and going this direction
aspeed forward refer to the connections that flow in the opposite direction is feedback and I use the word regarding connections for the horizontal connections within a particular
this is just a fix the enclosure for something discussion that will have next and also today in the afternoon with ginger Carlos presentation
throat a lot of anatomical work we have began to elicit a some basic connectivity between neurones in cortex and is the primary exam
what's that has been sighted extremely often of what we understand about the connectivity between different areas in the macaque monkey we don't have the diagram like this for the
rain most of the detail anatomical work has been done in macaque monkeys so each of this area into this box is here represents a drain area and this in cups
our understanding of who talks to Huma which area talks to which other area in terms of visual content is a lot of different parts of Cortex that represent visual information
where at the bottom would have the retina information from the retina flow through the to the lgn from the LG and information goes to primary visual cortex sitting right here
and from there this week escaid that is largely parallel and the same time karate call of a conglomerate of multiple areas that are fundamental in process
visual information will talk about some of this area is next and will also talk about something serious today in the afternoon when Jim discusses what are looking the mental competition
involved in visual object recognition one of the fundamental clues as to how do you understand how do you know that this is a particular visual area how do we know
this is important for for provision has come from an atomic collision smuggling monkeys but in some places in humans as well so if you make lesions in some of this
depending on where you make that Lucian either become completely offline or they have a particular chunk of the visual field were they can see
more higher order types of deficits in terms of visual recognition example primary visual cortex was discovered by
studying the projector your bullets in soldiers during World War 1 and bye-bye by discovering that some of those people had a blind parts
show feel and that was the organised depending on the projector of the bullet through their Occidental for text and that's how we became to think about B1
ask fundamental in visual processing it's not there is this ABCD right for a number of reasons one is that the lots of garlic
there is a lot of different different stages that are connected to each other and what are the ways to define a hierarchy is by looking at the timing of the
princess in different areas so if you look at the average latency response in each of these areas you find the desk and approximate car key in for
turn get out of the retina approximately 50 milliseconds or so about 60 or so many seconds in LG and approximately 10 millisecond cost
first step in time for the average latest distribution you'll see that it's not a strict hierarchy for some of the neurones in area
early neurones in before me fire before the late neurones in V1 and that's that's far more complex than just a simple
one way to put some order into the swimmingly complex and garlic circuitry one simplification is that are two main pathways what is the so-called what pathway
call where pathway pathway is essentially is that the ventral pathway it's mostly involved in visual object recognition trying to understand what is there the dorsal pathway
is mostly involved in motion and I've been able to wear objects are stereo on
used in terms of thinking about the fundamental computations in this series
complexity within each of these boxes of with zoom in in one of these areas with a complex character of competitions there multiple different
sportex essentially 6 layered structure and their specific rules become refer to this is a canonical microcircuitry the specific set of rules
information flows from one layer to another in terms of each of these cortical structures this canonical circuitry
common to most of these areas their this group about which layer receives information first and Sense information to areas are more or less constant while the cortical Observatory
this is a mean that we understand this circuitry well or what each of these connections is doing with certainly done but this our initial steps to decide
what song is this basic biological activity that possible mental computation of properties for visual processing
when would we call the first approximation or in medium approximation to Visual object recognition the notion that we can recognise objects very fast and this can be
playing essentially as bottom apparently process extensive this afternoon someone to essentially skip that
I'm jump into Morrison were there with and trying to think about top-down connections I just let me briefly so why we think that the first part of visual information can be
play silly approximated by this purely bottom-up processing why is that additional ever we can recognise objects very very fast as a series of experiments
Australian object recognition can happen within about 150 seconds or so we know the fish illogical signals and align with Rodger recognition
happen very fast within about 100 250ms you can find neurones that show very selective responses to complex objects and again with you see examples of
the receiver on the official is that have inspired generations of competition models that are purely bottom-up or there is Nowra currency and then
be quite successful in terms of visual recognition to first approximation the recent excitement with deep convolutional networks can be traced back to sound
this basic biological inspira competitions that are clearly bottom-up so the summarise and I'm going to give any more details you think that the First 102nd
also of a visual processing can be approximated by this bottom-up logical sequence of competitions
this leaves open fundamental question which is why do we have all these massive feedback connections we know that in cortex there actually more
recurrent and feedback connections and fit for ones and I like to talk about today is a couple of ideas of what all of those feedback connections may be doing so this is an
go study looking at a lot of the boxes that I showed you before and showing how many of the connections to any given area come from one of these other barriers
Pig just primary visual cortex this is saying that a good fraction of the connections to primary visual cortex actually come from which you that's from the next stage of
sing Rogan from V1 itself all in all of you quantify for a given year on in V1 how many singers are coming from a bottom-up source that is Foxtel GN
how many singers are coming from other one year olds or from higher visionary is it inside that they're more horizontal and top-down protections than bottom-up ones so what are they doing if you can
play the first country music and restore vision so well with bottom-up parties what are all these beatboxing now start doing so this brings me to
I like to discuss today of recent work that we've done to take some initial principles in thinking about what this feedback connections could be doing in terms of visual recognition
they start by getting you an example of trying to understand the basic fundamental unit of feedback where is this Canada competitions in by looking at the feedback
me too to be one individual system next I'm going to give an example of what happens during a visual search where we also think that feedback signals may be play
fundamental role if you have to do a very small two kinds of dashboard have to search for objects in the environment and finally I will talk about Pat and completion how you can recognise object
Cavalier cluded where we also think that feedback signals may be playing an important role before I go onto the Scribe what was in the feedback from
one may be doing lemons grow very quickly classical word that she will and be so did that God than the normal price by recording the TV of neurones in primary visual cortex
we started working in kitchen's and then subsequently in in monkeys undiscovered are neurones that show orientation tuning meaning that they respond
despite each of these marks gear for response to an action potential the fundamental language of competition in cortex and respond quite big asleep with
sing about of disorientation and essentially there's no firing at all with this type of them us and the Celtic feel this was because Transformer
standing of the essential compilations in primary visual cortex in terms of filtering the initial stimulus this is what we now is 5 by
and if you look at deep convolutional networks many of them if not all of them start with some sort of filtering operation dad is in recovery or filter with symbols
type of orientation that we think is a fundamental aspect of our start to process information in the visual field beautiful things that
need is not only to make this car is Barossa to come up with very simple graphical models of how they thought this could come about and this remains
what is the fundamental ways which we think about how orientation tuning may come about if you record activity of neurones in the retina or in the lgn
are you fine with call centre surround receptive field surgeries symmetric receptive fields with an area in the centre that excites in Iran and
the surround that inhibit the mirror is that if you put together multiple energy and Cells orientations workers receptive Fields
are aligned along a certain orientation and he simply combine all of them simply are the responses of all of those neurones you can get a new one in primary visual cortex
add house orientation to uni this is the problem that's far field from soul this by the week for five decades the many many models of our intention TuneIn
this remains one of the basic bottom of bit for when ideas of how you can actually build orientation tuning from very simple receptive field informed
thinking about how basic computations can can give rise to intuition tune in a purely bottom-up fashion
so-called simple sardar complex hours I showed invariance to the exact position or face of the oriented bar within the receptive field and that's
straight in a simple cell so this simple cell has orientation tuning winning the response more vigorously to the east orientation than 2 days
station however if you change the face or the position of the rent in via within the city feel that response decreases significantly in
what's this complex cell that not only has orientation tuning in the repairs more vigorously to this orientation and to this one but also has a face environments been in the liver
Amal is the same way regardless of the exact face of the exact position of the Steamers with that they related
we can build this complex sells by summation of a trivia multiple simple salsa going through imaginary have multiple simple cells with different receptive
the necklace 1% on this different positions you can add the map and and create complex is this fundamental operations of simple and complex
text can be somehow fresh to the root of a lot of their bottom-up erratic and models lot of the deep convolutional networks today essentially cub variation
is going to seem so filtering step nonlinear impatient that give you in variance under concatenation of the filtering and environment steps along the visual
so in full up with this idea would like to understand the basics of what are the computations
formation that's provided when you have signals from B2 to be 1 to do that we have been collaborating with Richard born at the Harbour Medical
who has a way of implanting Prior lives this is a device that can be implanted in monkeys in areas v203
what's the temperature and that's reduce or essentially eliminate activity from areas v to 1 v 3 so that means that we can study be one without activity
ARB 23 can study B1 son's feedback example of recordings in this area this is
normal activity that you get from from from the mirror on here is when the presenter visual stimulus is a spontaneous activity each of these dogs corresponds to a spike which of these line
12 edition of the of the stimulus that traditional way of showing roster + 4 responses to this is the spontaneous activity centre stimulus
does an increase in the response of this year as you might expect their pants after answer this is this that restores here so this activity
no here they turn on their pump this or lowering the temperature and you can see that the within a couple of minutes they're essentially significantly reduce the response
lastly silence not completely silence activity in areas V2 an under 3 reversible so when they turn the pants off activity
so the question is what happens in Parramatta visual cortex when you don't have feedback from V2 and an anniversary they have
is the sum of the basic properties of E1 do not change consistent with the simple model that I just told you
where are the orientation tuning in Invermay visual cortex is largely dictated by the bottom up in Boots by the singers from the lgn the
and I will be there between V3 nothing would happen with orientation tuning in primary visual cortex and that's essentially what they're showing here this is our exam
orientation-selective this is Direction selectively what happens when you move unregistered by within the receptive field so they're showing the direction this is showing
mean normalise response of the neurone is the preferred directions in Direction orientation the maximum response they leucippus wants to
when you don't have activity in vitro and we see red Christmas Day control data and essential the tuning of this was not alter the preference for the
was not altered the same thing goes for directions to chilli device support entation tuning and direction selectivity did not change
let me see if you're worried about the dynamics of the response so stupid and showing with the minimal responses as a function of time x 0 is when the
turn on as I told you're ready by about 50 minutes seconds or so you get a bigger as response in primary visual cortex and this if we compare the orange and
cars will see that this initial response is largely identical so the initial response of this V1 around is not affected by the absence
repeat back from Beatles to see a fact we still to see a change in the firing rate here largely at about 60 Minutes seconds or so
the presentation oversimplified cartoon I think of the bottom up fuel and visa like response driven by
I'm signals from the v231 coming back about 10 minutes seconds later and that's when we start seeing some of the street but related
add some of the basic properties do not change when top of these are being dictated large in my bottom of signals they Dynamics do change the initial response is unaffected the later part
response is affected I want to say one thing that the dust change and put that I need to explain what an area summation curve is so if you percent customers within the recipe
a neurone of this size you got a certain response I should start increasing the the size of a stimulus you anymore because response Size Matters
the better to appoint there comes a point where it turns out that the response of the new and starts decreasing again so larger is not
better a little bit better this size of us an inhibitory effect overall on the response of the surround suppression and this area surround
Christ in premiership quartic awesome earlier and he asked for a very long time out there when you do this type of experiments in the Arts
the fact that surrounds depression does not disappear that is you still have a peak in the response as a function of a similar size but there's a
depression that is when you don't have feedback there's less depression you have a larger response for the estimate so we think that one of the fundamental competitions
back is providing here is this integration from multiple Nelson the one that happens in V2 and then Innovation to activity of neurones in area
to provide some this suppression this is partly the reason why are not a number excited about a uniform stimulus like a blank wall or you're interested in changes and
that you think is dictated by this feedback from V2 to be one we can model this centre-surround interactions as the ratio of
Goshen course to forces what is the one that increases the response we are going to say no molestation term that suppresses the response from the stimulus is too large the number of
dusky essential you can I think of this is a ratio of oceans Rog to the rate of Russian Cars 1 dictating the centre that respond this around
to make a long story short we can feed the data from the monkey with this extremely simple rate of mushrooms model and we can show that the main parameter that
seems to be acting upon is what we call wn that is this normalisation Factor here so the the tuning factor that the
how did the strength of the surrounding Division from v to 2 v 1 within that's one of the mental things that's being affected by Fiddler
this is the game with spatial extent over which we took an exit this action on primary visual cortex you think that's the main thing that's affected
this type of special effect may be important in other role that has been ascribed to feedback which is the ability to Direct attention to
patients in environment I want to come back to this question here and ask under What conditions and how can a feedback also provide important features Pacific
signals from one area to another and for that I'm going to switch to another task another two different crap which is the worst wall the task the cast of visual search how do we search for
objects in the environment sufficient to focus on specific location but we need to be able to search for specific features we need to be with the buyer's RV
sponsors for specific features of this term as I was searching for specific it's not enough to
to send feedback from B2 to be 1 and direct attention or change the size of the receptive field of attention to a specific location another version
let's talk about of visual related theme that relates to Visual search is feature based attention when you actually paying attention to a particular place to particular colour
feature that's not nursery located at the space at our friend here has studied quite significant people always like to know the answer of 4 is that ok
about a competition model and sun behavioral data that that we have collected to try to get this question of how feedback signals can be relevant provisions
this initial part of this condition model is essentially the 8 months type of architecture that has been paid
goodbye Tommy Porgy on several people in his life most notably people like Max Grace and favour and intimacy I was thinking that by this time people would have described
in more detail I'm going to go through this very quickly again today in the afternoon will have more discussion about this family of models to this family of models essentially ghosts
series of linear and nonlinear competitions in a hierarchical way inspired by the basic definition of simple and complex cells that I described in the
haha well on result of these models do is they take an image this are pixels does a filtering start this filtering step
involves Gabor filtering of the image in this particular case there are four different orientations and what they're here is a map of the visual input after the
linear filtering process the next step in this model is a local Max operation this is pulling neurones that have similar
YouTube references but slightly different scale in the recipe feels or slightly different positions in the receptive fields and this Max operation is nonlinear
is giving new invariance to the specific feature so now you can get a response to the same feature irrespective of the exact scale or the exact position
dim that receptive real this word level S1 and see one Initial emails by Fukushima in this study was carried on later bye bye
any others and this is directly inspired by the simple and complex cells that I very briefly showed you previously in the recordings of human please
filtering and Max operations are repeated throughout the hierarchy again and again so here's another layer that has a filtering step and nonlinear Max
step in this case this filtering here is not a Gabor filter we don't really understand very well with you and Cindy to and before are doing one of the
when does a cubby news in the world using here is the radial basis function where the properties of the neurone in this days are dictated by patches taking randomly
natural images of this is feed forward all of this is essentially the basic ingredients of December competition that was that happy news
object recognition you can have more layers you can have different types of competitions the basic properties are essentially the ones that are described here
talk about this not this for my part the best part of the money now I asked you where is wool do you need to do something you need to be able to somehow look at this information and
bias your responses were or the model to us regions of the visual space that have features that resemble what you're looking for
your car your keys Boulder OK I'm going to see what happens if you're looking for this top hot here so first we have a reference
what's on in the model of the top part this is the cat here and we have a representation in Arabic laboratory of how units in the highest echelons of this model
please cancel have a representation of the features that compose this object and high level in this model is that representation
8mm multiplicative fashion the entire image essentially we buy is the responses in the image based on this particular features that we are
this is inspired by many fish illogical experiments that have to agree approximation of modulation in feature list
has been observed across different parts of the visual field searching for red objects near is that like bread will enhance the response through
antara Beach Road field modulated by the pattern of pictures that were searching for in here after that
normalisation step this animation step is critical in order to discount Huey bottom-up effects we don't want the competition between different objects
repeal irritated by which object is brighter for example so we normalised that after modulating that with the features that were search
gives us a map of the image where each area has been essentially compared to the speaker said they were looking for and then we have a winner-take-all mechanism that dictates
where the mother will pay attention to where the mother will fixate on first where the things that object is located so what happens when we have this
bark that speeches Pacific and that molars responses recently targets or objectives were searching for in this to images either in order to raise or when
embedded in complex scenes we're searching for the stop object and the largest response in the world is in India in the location of where the Opera Quays
India other two images of searching for this accordion here and a game the model for sable to find that bike this comparison of the features with customers
more generally this our object array images is the number of fixations required to find the object in this object array images one with
the first taxation if the mole does not find the object in the first location this with call innervation of return so we make sure the mall does not come back to the same location
and my will look at the second best possible location in the image and it will keep on searching until it finds
60% correct and eventually have to fight fixations if can find the object almost always right in clear this is what you would expect by random search
randomly fixate on that different objects of the Maoris be much better than that and then for the aficionados whole plethora of Julie bottom-up models that don't have teeth
what's the weather this is funny of models they were saying nearby people like Lauren TT and Kristoff cocky sale in sea bass models on the you can see there a couple of other points in here
all of those models cannot find any object that is it's not that this ultrasaber searching for are more salient and therefore that's why the model is finding that we're in
something more than just warm up your music for objects under the
conditions so we had a multiple objects that just have to make a cicada to Target object to make a long story short this in the community performance of the model and the number of 6
under these conditions and the model that recently in terms of how well humans do this is that a phone every single individual subject in the stuff
ugly just keeps on the details you can compare the air is that the model is making how consistent people are with themselves with respect to other subjects is
add to humans the long stories the mall is far from perfect and we don't think that we have capture everything we need to understand about visual search some people allergic to before
the notion that the moral lesson have this major changes with eccentricity and for the answer on long way to go every single with catcher some of the essential initial in
cancel visual search and this is one example of how visual feedback signals can influence this bottom-up parking for recognition quickly move
third example that I wanted to give you a call feedback help in terms of visual recognition were other functions that feedback could be playing and for that I'd like
discuss that with Aaron also been other and in love in terms of how we can recognise objects that are partially occluded this happens all the time as you
Iran and see all tricks in the world be cancelling counter object where you can only find Parton information and have to make button button condition fundamental aspect
we do that in all sorts of scenarios it's not just restricted division all of you can probably complete all of these buttons you Spartan completion in social scenarios
why do you make inferences from Spartan knowledge about their intentions and what they're doing and we're trying to do ok do we want to study this for him how you complete pattern have your
from Barton limited information in the context of visual recognition there a lot of different ways in which you can partially occluded objects
a few of them would have needed was used to paradigm called bubbles that's Sean here essential it's like looking at the world like these you don't have the small Windows
can see the object performance can be tied to make the task harder or easier so you have a lot of bubbles it's really easy to recognise that this is at toy school bus
how long before bubbles it's actually pretty challenge so we can type 3 performance and the difficulty of this task very quickly the Mr by showing you
V6 performance subjects perform as a function of the amount of occlusion in the image of the function how many pixels your showing
can you just on what do you see here is that with 60% occlusion performance is extremely high performance essentially drops to chance level when the object
more significant amount of robustness in human performance for example if I've added more than 10% of the pixels in the option and people can still
this is all very quickly would have been discovered by doing invasive recordings
how many patients while their subject were performing these recognition of that are partially occluded it's illegal to put electrons in the human brain in normal people
so we work with subject that have from a commercial interactable epilepsy subjects that have seizures in the notions need to implant electro in order to
what's the sashes and be in order to ensure that when they do a reception and they take out the part of it in the rain that's the response superstitious that they're not going to interfere with
the functions such as language this patient stay in the hospital for about one week and doing this one week with a unique opportunity inside the human brain and recorded
logical data depending on the type of patient we've used the different types of electrons this is what some people refer to us equal electric electrical to go traffic signals
potential single is very different from 10 or showing you in the little spikes before this are broadly of tens of thousands of millions of of
very very high temperature solution at the mini 2nd level but very poor special recognition resolution on Lee being able to localise things are the millimetre level
what's up with these we can pinpoint specific locations within about approximately 1 mm but have very high signal-to-noise ratio signals that are dictated by the
an example of those signals is shown here these are interesting and potential as a function of time this is the answer of the stimulus and this 39 different rabbits
100 showing this unoccluded face with very vigorous Change by systematic from one tried to another old of those great races are single try
similar to the roster Plaza I was showing you before I'm going to show you a couple of single trials wearing individual images where
partially ordered in this case there's only about 15% of the excess of the face that being shown and we see that despite the fact that we're covering 85
more left of the image was still see a pretty consistent singer listening as are clearly not identical for example this one looks different there's a lot of our ability from
another just single trials showing that they're still selectivity for this site despite the fact that we have small tracking system
in which this five different faces were presented each line Christmas that Riley Cerato close as you can see the data are extremely clear there's no processing here this
Radha single single trailers with the partial images you can consider the biggest response here responses are not as nice and then leave me alone here
broadcast all these images are different locations of a lot of our ability here if you actually fix the bubble location
repeat the presenter same image I'm still in random order but the same image is that the thing is I'm more consistent not as consistent this one that's only more consistent
give me a very clear selective response tolerant to a tremendous amount of occlusion Indian interestingly the latencies response
significantly later compared to the whole images so if you look up for example to kinder Ms you see the response start significantly before to Hannah Ms for the whole images
Qantas careers start after 200 seconds I'm trying to crack try this and showing that pattern completion the ability to recognise that art occluded invoice
significant delay at the physiological level is the architecture in silicone mould
Mary Wilder promise Victory square rapidly when you start having significant population I'm going to skip this and just very quickly are you I'll tell their initial step
Bill Lotto has been doing trying to add the currency to the model strength while both feedback connections as well as regarding connections within its
to try to get a model that will be able to perform pattern completion and therefore use this feedback thing is to allow us to extrapolate from previous information about
subject bill will be here Friday or Monday not sure ill talk to him more about this morning this are essentially they belong to the family of 8
belong to family of compilation net worth when you have finished your operation special and saturation pulling and organisation Jim will say about this family of models today in the app
new Hindi bottom-up models and would be has been doing is Alan recurrent and feedback connections retraining this model is based on this requirement and feedback connections
comparing the performance with the human psychophysics that I showed you before this the performance of the unit 4 Marlow this is the recurring model
he was able to train to try to get out whether feedback is relevant Hobart and completion is to use with backward masking back or masking
percent that image and Amelia to that image within a few milliseconds you percent noise it wasn't a mask and we will have our you that masking essentially in Toorak
back processing essentially it allows you to have a bottom-up approach information shops feedback I don't think this is quite extraordinary resetting the stories Polly Farmer complicated
automation Supacentre picture you have a bottom-up stream you put a mask and interact all their subsequent feedback processing so if you do that I disable level
you can show that one arm is particularly if the interval is very short to consider typical impair the pattern compression performance of the mass comes within 25
of the actual stimulus performance in recognising these vehicles object is significantly impaired interpret these to indicate that feedback
needed for button completion this is bills institution of the recurrent model where because he has regarding see now you'll see us time
is models so we can also present the image percent in mask to the model and compare the performance of the computational model as a function of the occlusion in the animals
that must condition is this and distil two or three more slight I want to show ID new three examples of potential ways in which feedback singers
important the first one has to do with the effects of feedback on surround suppression going from v to 2 v 1 within the by doing this of experiments combined with the competition
weather Fremantle invitations we can begin to elucidate some of their steps by which feedback on episode it's role we hope to come up with essential alphabet of competitions
to the filtering on immigration operations that are implemented by feedback the second example was feedback to features that dictate with
initial search Dash and their last example in both our preliminary were trying to use feedback as well as recurrent connections the phone Pat and completion and extrapolate from
information to do is just a few more slight about something that's a couple of things that are happening in your science and completion
that I think I tremendously exciting for people 5 again there's things that I would definitely be very very excited to follow up on
the notion that we're able to go inside brains and read out my local code and eventually write down computer code and build amazing machines is I think you're very appealing and
I think I'm ready we were a long way from the able to take biological Coles and translate that into into competition cos it's really extremely
13 reasons why I think this optimism that this may not be as crazy as it's beginning to grab some men this information about wiring diagram
exclusive resolution are lot of people seriously thinking about providing us with Map maps about which year and talks to which other near on this was not present Everest
what's the weather now beginning to detailed information that is much higher quality than ever before the second one is the strength in numbers for decades we've been recording the TV one year
can you finish the time now that many different ideas and techniques are there about which we can listen to a monitor elective motor neurones simultaneously I think there's going to be game changing
your office your resume but also for the possibility of invitation models that are inspired by
did you up the genetics and to manipulate this Circuit with unprecedented Resolution that for one second this is the c elegans this is
microscopy image of Housing congrats Rise the circuitry little soldier in this pioneering world of Sydney Grammar a couple of days ago I slept to mapping the connectivity of each one
102 neurones exactly for each year on who is connected with is representing a rather complex way in this diagram here that people are big
do this type of heroic type of experiments in cortexo were beginning to have initial inside about connectivity about Holden Reservoir with each other
commission in cortex we are nowhere near being with this for humans not even other species nice and so on yet
first in in the community of having a very detailed map for the question for you for the young next generation where are we going to do with this month if I give you a fantastic detail wiring diagram
off the chunk of Cortex how is that going to transform our ability to make inferences and Bill new complication of moles
from one more your house is that I didn't have time to talk about this work over that can landed with Matthias is ondansetron is a recording of spikes from human cortex again in
you have epilepsy I'm just watching this life because I I can't it under $300 is not a simultaneously recorded population this is what we can record from
the time using microwave is now this is different from the type of recording slideshow with work is the actual spike that we can record and these 318 Euros is
history of recording from this 280 neurones took us about 3 to 4 years of time there more people that are you saying is a 2/4 and imaging
turn all massive multilateral address that are beginning to be able to record activity of hundreds of neurones simultaneously my good friend and Chris
inventor Ed Boyden believe that we will be able to recover from 100000 year and simultaneously of course is far more dangerous than I am and then you can think bigger disc
I didn't think about the possibility of recording from 1500 simultaneously in week or a month one may be able to come it's remember Samara from very large
there's going to be transformative the gold in field of molecular biology people would sequence a single gene and they were punished in tar sequence ACCC
until that was a cold paper and that's when it's been 5 years just sequence in a single gene now we have the possibility of download by advances in technology
a lot of all recordings will become obsolete will be able to listen to the activity of thousands of neurones simultaneously and again it's for your generation to think about
the Transformer understanding of how quickly can read biological in the unlikely event that you think that's not enough here is one more thing that I finish transforming how we can
safe for biological coat and then using the knees are referred to as after genetics where you can manipulate activity of specific types of new
a flash a lot of computational models today lot of hypotheses about what different connections may be doing at some point we will be with the test with unprecedented resolution
somebody want to know what is this new one in v to provide kind of feel like it's providing with me will silence only neurones in me to that provide feedback to be one in it
without affecting for example all of the other fit for work processes and an answer that can be derived from this type of
say so because we have very high specificity in our ability to manipulate circuit because we'll be able to record activia many many morning around simultaneously and because we'll have
delete all the alarms I think that the dream of being able to read out and Dakota Rochelle code and translated Into Temptation code is less crazy than it may sound we think that
me able to in the next several years and decades smart people like you will be able to make this tremendous transformation and discover specific I wasn't about intelligence by
directions to ration from biology that's what it is here will be happy to keep on fighting under and I will fight everyone will be happy to keep on fighting about
how amazing to use of season would I try to describe is that by You by really understanding biological cause we'll be able to write amazing computational code I put a lot of arrows here as I'm not
Kiwi the I'm not saying that we solve the problem there's a huge amount of work