the phone can't answer is provided under a Creative Commons licence your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality
resources for free to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of mit courses visit MIT opencourseware at ocw
am i t daddy you can be most about face is going to connect to watch in the car now let's talk about today and what an answer talked about
I just start preparing for this that I should see if you think about primates intelligence in the cold pizza conditions might be connected both to the species were studying
intelligence start with this kind of creature in the paper nature
speak the Genome of the octopus sequence there was a really well than the public press is finally putting the intelligence the are going to sit there
jeans $10,000 than humans that's of course that have a strong argument the plants and 45000 genes that we didn't tell you very much about intelligence
Austin's the profound where lots of jeans that are important for development of the brain and there's very hibernate in certain gene families that I controlling
another system is one example of a better understanding the intelligence of other creatures in the octopus
study the point I would like to stress about the octopus there's really nothing social about the species actually almost simultaneously with this paper there was one we poured about
production one particular species of octopus it's not actually office violence or more affectionate but this is really the one exception to otherwise life that's pretty much nonce
so in the octopus you have like the egg station in this Lara which actually very early on there's no like interaction with Mum or anything like this the go
surface of the ocean in this start feeding and try to grow a sister can because only a few of them gonna survive then we Productions of a scary Enterprise mini
octopus the male has to be careful not to be eaten by the female and the process when did successful then I did the male stops eating ice going to die
for most of the answers are going to hatch and that Mum is going to do with basically to to make sure the freshwater is going to be delivered to the xx
set in the times of lights off your life so you can be very intelligent like an octopus and just gave you just mentioned extraterrestrial life maybe at the
this is out there might be that social and so that doesn't necessarily have to be a connection between sociality and the telligence second thing is you can be liked by social
and you get lots of protection being in the group following James Dickson this we don't necessarily make you very smart so I don't want to argue against the connection between
reality intelligence in the form of social intelligence but we have to be careful there's no necessary connection between those primates there's this idea
social intelligence hypothesis that really want me play me so intelligent is there sociality it's let's consider because the arguments are it was most strongly put followed by Newcomb
Lincoln 7608 cruises to this idea what this primates the primates are a small group of mammals without final
are there very diverse second a very small primates just like 30 grams all the way to 20 kg animals evolved study like 65 and 5 million
there was Mouse Extinction and see if this hi diversity within the mammals starting from this point on so they're certain things in common office with other mammals but
very special many weeks of the species are social Social but they're all social they develop very slowly so it's really Vader
from the octopus investments made into the offspring that have been many Offspring and the lifespan of this and it was a pretty long octopus lesson 6325
their visual better than other mammals which have a factory oriented binocular vision many have colour vision so vision is very important for primates
and they have on average larger brains than other Melbourne South so I won't miss any of the anatomy of primates what makes this special order mentally but a few points
Pinterest complex primate white ones and Domain Factor reduce body mass of the Big Banana
this is flight of body weight and you can see this lock relationship between the two
it's something that you find all of the animal kingdom but if you compare crime it's to other non-primate mammals you can see that there is larger increase with body mass
Queen Mouse in Aussie for continent of neurones the number of when you're as increasing was sleep with body mass and it doesn't other mammals this is obviously very good measurement the others
if you look for brands Rocky the sing weed in again see that can in primates have any more neurones than on primates just these two examples year so this seems to be
organisation the other measures you can look at so for example the neurones size is increasing with brain size and gold and so when a collage of green and gold NZ
the cell you want to test me my neurones are just getting bigger primates if we're not so much the case for the size of the new one pretty much these constant in the head piece the size of the way
or how much white matter do you actually need for urine to connect of the brain regions in rodents apparently the fibre cannabis increasing with Wayne size so again you bring my
just because you didn't the anatomy of the basic element requires he will get more space but in primates is not the case you get more white brain matter there's like it because the creativity
complex support faster with increasing size and endurance just like very coarse indications that there's something special by the planet
are compared to other Melbourne leading brings the premises forward facing eyes that can do binocular vision of their scores
cranium that under the maximum speaker from other mammals are they also special and other ways that are important if you think about embodied cognition it enough
thanks to all these points but obviously if you have a hand as complex as hours with your favourite many primate species there lots of things you can do and then requires you to be able to control it and
power to drink with the environment at animals night here so the shoulder is this more mobile does not pose with so many species and in the face they are
you said you might have seen here so if you go our go self up in the two more complex animals that's not which has become increasingly with used and I'll tell you
why do I just make important specialisation primates sociality is very important as well and so therefore main principles of sociology
is the dominating one is the second one here it's called a meal transfer system it's a polygamist might email organisation and what
44 the social life of primates because we're just at the social behaviour has to be complex so they can be Corporation like women defence and hunting which all the animals of the True Blood
what is the same time as competition for food mates dominance hierarchy and it's a function of the complexity of this Auckland Violent Soho
social life was beautiful describe a dry itchy and the Robert cypherden this wonderful book of metaphysics and just going to quote from that so they study baboon monkeys in the wild and
is what episode about the Domain of expertise of the balloons and I did fall on monkeys in the age of social life most advanced than Marty me on my if you my group certificate includes a torn
metres in your family's which means of do the sea much they stay in the group and they found families and they're going to see a constant over long periods of time they have a linear dominance hierarchy
any of the changes often and the linear hierarchy of females in The Offspring that can be stable for generations daily life in a baboon group includes small-scale alliances that may involve
individuals and occasional large steel 4 million battles that involve all of the members of three or four Metro lines males and females can fun short and bonds
a longer-term friendships are the D2 cooperative child wearing of all the social and triggers a kind of an awesome melodrama in which each individual
predict the behaviour of others and form those relationships that we turned the greatest benefits of the problems with the baboon mind my soul and it's environment in which has involved
what's the problem station baboons can express into words other bubbles and this is really important again like if you're so sure you don't have to be very
can you go smoke it to be social but there's something special apparently by primates the links are intelligence to also gelatin so again so the intelligence of
what what's Santa's favourite of the primates have large brains and primates apparently group size is correlated with brain size across different species and not the home range size
Jennifer pothesis have to forward to more complex and hobbies environments until like a similar proxy for the complexity of your social life and your physical I predict there's a better
queen size with the social like than physical light the complexity of an individual social relationships increases exponentially with website new planet small and when I get back to this point
baboons not a primates know their peers dominance work and social relations within the dimension the previous light is good evidence for behavioral work the actually privates know something about it
social knowledge contract with surprising cases of ignorance outside of the social Domain even when it's something as important as a predator so keen insight
Cassidy Berwick monkeys what they observe is the monkeys what are the main products to them is a python and the python of walk it is the cross in the sound of this
and this application is the Word monkeys make the connection between these trailers and the presence of other Python which is really striking you would imagine this at the first thing that they would have to learn
whether she falling the trailer to the bush and have a surprise the phone find it I think they're not example is so and environment leopards of course predators also
monkeys have a way of putting the carcasses of animals down to down into the trees to protect them from larger predators like lions to the presence of a car cos we're
go to you that likely there is a different world and again divided monkeys they don't make the connection so there's a car cos they're they're not pretty good scared about it it doesn't mean the day
even falling alarm call some other species is the weather in Eagle is approaching or if kale is approaching so it's not that they're really dumb in this way but there's
play This Way Bitcoin dress if I like all the details about the social world and the obvious that they can express 449 social factors
then give specialisations we can talk about this in the rain for processing social stimuli and then there's actually evidence that he must have better sociability that they are less stress
and if they would like to success and so so this all works to say that if you are socially smart enable environment on the media at primate species
except except for producing the f word is a good argument to be made your social intelligence will never go to the next generation this is like how social Titans and
I did this one important point is oftentimes not made and that's if you become smart and smart and there can be the physical environment your physical environment does not change rematch
if you weren't working with a sorted by began his Martin smarter interacting with the safe environment the elements in your social environment interaction with the old is Marcus Martin actually setting
arms race where you not only improve your situation by getting smarter and I'll be able to get smarter not I keep pace with the other swirls money you and Sue can see like how they could
between sociality and intelligence that did Willy this arms race is not a crow for physical interactions but for social interactions so did you actually have to be able to better pretty
movie of someone else and you are in your group and you all to know something about that individual I forgot to be successful so their arguments against the social intelligence apophysis
in particular vehicle out of many other species so there are other social species are you know some examples of complex societies but instead as much as
smrt South Sudan know about the complexity mostly for this week is and whether we're compared to waves and wheels for example primate societies are more
and it's going to be like a acoustic injection of this hypothesis we actually some other correlations that did you predict
yeah well and sort of the private order social learning Innovation until you start only quality with grain size and that was good size she could imagine a scenario where should the evolution of basic
social intelligence is something it's very basic to play me but then you go to different species within the primate order an outlook way that they become so smart like orangutans or
you can use to Olds and it will make the two more important than their social allity OK there's two different apostasy
directions to Tonkin macaque monkeys is the visual displays you can see they're turning to each other and well you might think they're trying to figure out what's actually going on here
here's the alternative hypothesis of this is still use so you can see this guy we just invented cool to those pick and soda
yes with more important to your intelligence you been able to beat the social system other individuals and your trip or your ability to meet her and ice
soul and Less intelligent or at the just Monika just survive likeability
unique specialisation weather good at the argument that I can't make it the following so didn't know they have to actually be true knowledge and just not like Lauren associations
and the Whispers to do with the complexity of the safe environment if you've different individuals or just a typical case for these Blue Monkey year 3160.
animals in 82001 of the 6th try it it's gonna be virtually possible for you to learn all these different people might relationships and then behave intelligently bass appointment
English relationships can change very fast so it would not be a very smart and tried it a list of all these Palace interactions in the neck deep on that no single be able metre
give me another service efficient recognise associations like petrol in again so human observer bias apparently not very good to predict that's if they don't know the animals very well personally
are you might think well maybe not exist is it like a list but you don't really like this much you play like this in the world to it and it also did doesn't seem to work because social relationship next friendships
transitive Zambia friends be in sia frames it doesn't that ANZ is going out with your friends family relationships are complex the non-associative is the mother of b
he's not the mother of so there's a more complex interaction there as well and then find oops finally the candy summer kids membership in letterbox gases
again would you be able to keep track of this you better have a packet of my love what's going on I rather than just make a list of associations that you like it it's very difficult to prove it's not a source
thank you have a good arguments to consider that actually does private health active knowledge office of Environment so there's one example for this week if you make the point very nice in the store
is a baboon monkey and she was actually living with farmers and South Africa it was a habit of the time they
you please dogs wording goats with the boots and sitting here you can see here here
turn off the heat of the goats so she is licking salt here which is something that begins with natural not do she will continue to engage in social behaviour certificate for the moon so she would
the gold to example but the most amazing thing about her which is little hard to see you soon as you are here she's can one of the little yearlings year and brings
talks mother and the description of what what does animal was doing what's when will it goes about home and then Santa silver separated
from The Offspring she would actually go mannequin the tried to pick them up and and would not stop until she was finished and just wouldn't happen that's ok mate ill go to a car
and so she would have to put order into the social aware that she was living end and she won't stop until this order was restored and the promise that they
add a ball to tell any of the adult go to the Indians or know any of the pairs but this was like oh well this was not a social environment that she was in and she was structure according to recorded
so the social knowledge they know what the status of individuals like the age of the gender they know but the
list of individuals and they reckon I can be simply like women and mothering and then based on these observations of the different individuals in the social world that built this kind of
I like friendship kinship and hurricane are there an interesting a complicated structure to them and the concept of the person
and is it going to be talking about visa conditions of different things you can recognise a person from the fees but if you can recognise a theatre doesn't let you know word is
so the person point of includes like something like this is a juvenile female monkeys the daughter of accident so far this is not your help and expansion of this month
is the we work with the date of this personal intersection between Africa conditions
what is the study which agency colour talked about in social cognition so as to yesterday
pretty important in in primates about a third of the primary brain is thought to be involved in to go function so this is a lot and this is a lot of information to be gathered from the outside visual world
but also it's difficult computationally together this and surgeon was explaining some of the competition or challenges that are finishing has to sort of yesterday and it will come back to some of this point of the leader
so what is Netflix a Jimbo saying that's the base unit of cognition and just be quickly what it actually says more than a collection of features
Michael's of perception actually anchor sites that Sophia proximity of elements together if these elements their similarity with them together large entity if there's good continuation
elements together and two lights if there's a common Face Again to go to the large entities and something similar to 4 faces if different face parts in the wrong
position but now you're putting together correctly you can certainly organise a face there's a larger scale organisation to Notley goes beyond just being a collection of features and maybe something simple is going on for
commission that I'm sure we're going to talk about missing a physical directions when Franklin's causality from just a Sequence of Events or sauce
movies where you are telling yourself like a complex or story unfolds even there's just a simple geometric shapes moving around so this creation of like higher order
what does intentions I think is essential for tea with it's a constructive process of the brain and poses on the Peace information it gets from the eyes it's just in the collection of features it's colour
pictures of symbolic representations it can Creed meaning especially to think about the face if it's official someone you know that's very meaningful and it makes information actionable and this
I think that the important to turn off the ignition and social cognition and faces are smack in the middle of this ok so I already had this movie to use again I am
the social communication is taking place here you can see the facial this place here for the older male Who season the other animals that begin with this place by the way you mostly
minnetonka macaque instead you can understand what's going on their right and this is something very special again I didn't have an all animals is facial displays and Charles Darwin
again what are the first people to notice it in 1872 is that the use your face to crash your emotional state otherwise your emotions are private to you but used
official language tissue suppressor emotions and oftentimes to do it even if you don't want it just happens automatically and it's not possible in all animals so if you
fish or a frog there lots of really cool things you can do in ocean sit on the front porch and enjoy the day lots of things that you can have in common with with primates but they should communication with
something more than being the millions Pacific mammals you actually have in the face musculature that is not a taxi from bone to bone but it's no attention to the skin and soap
skip this to rats your weather whiskers help you can see if you're younger a labelled you can see the active Explorers each other's faces and it's so much a century fashion that's passed with
Campbell the West Coast because of this muscular truck and there's a specialisation it's becoming more and more refined a primate so we just monkeys and trims and humans with 23 different facial muscles to becoming more
flexible I mentioned before the snout region is increasingly reduce and Primacy of some simpler primates where they still have strong smell which is limiting the ability of the safe to move but the more
I'm just getting the more flexible this muscles become and the more expressive the faces becomes the faces not now because we're sandwich with sort of signals eating without andonisus monkey switch as shown
give a six that I think his preference that again for assistant that can analyse these three important information about the state of another animal
it sort of interested in faces I like to show this movie which is showing a sweet old and attack monkey and
what's the point of this study as you can see the is attending by closer to faces experimenter of course there was an awesome I think would ask me I didn't put that there is this
listening to before but it listen to it the second thing I like to show this movie is exactly what happened right now it's like you're all getting really excited about this outfit
Powerball little critter right and I've seen this movie now it's time to the still like this is still like my reason
open Sierra you can see it's getting really excited about is being very active and now he's reproducing the station specific and there's a specific station to action that's happening
human babysitting for 3 months 17 monkeys for 2 weeks and you can see that there is an interconnection between birthday preceding and what they're acting on an automatic fashion
what does emotional part I think this really important there's nothing just episode in point and you can control these things faces really get very deep into your emotional and social brain automatically
one of the lines of visa to my location to try and forgot the circus the bank that possible and then to use this to get in order to solve the brain function I'll be on face perception ok
the pieces are sending so you can I try starving suicide entity the getting their social communication there's emotional responses and there's also Gates following so Direction
eyes are looking to your following automatically become controllers later but his initial automatic response this one very nice illustration from the British TV show you have people wearing this
large deck 125 and where their eyes drawn on this NASA to the going to One Direction and so you know that this is not real
but what's happening if your attention is drawn concentrated is upper right quadrant and it's getting annoying all the time because you know that there's nothing there you're not at the Natalie paying attention there but automatic
find out if you come back again again again and so this is another thing that comes from the face it gets deeper into attentional control system
what can start with a stupid faces arm the most important source of information we can gender an aged person identity even things like perceive trustworthiness Alltrack
I'm just a very brief look at the face and then addition amical signals like moving over direction of rotation of the object from the place so I just work so
what's the challenges faced of up to you and said you are some of the challenges like this one year lighting conditions can sometimes benign optimal
end the first thing for you to analyse the seat in the sea in its localise where the faces are I'm going to take a little bit about the conditions of that
I want to know where the faces are you want to listen for that you won't want to know like who is in the car and I just realised that the images that I had from this which I walk or something from the godfather make
best way to where is the other picture of this individual here on in display of this five faces of alright
and there's another Joel the same colour on and another person down here with two different directions in this like to see this better
will thing is the we have a way of letting these two pictures to each other knowing that there from the same person even though physically on a pixel by pixel basis these two actually much more similar to each other and
to think ID like Halloween is doing that achieving recognition in this condition in a manner that it's environment to Transformations that I can transfer to Rooty update
this is just a reminder that this actually is my difficult so this is of course just made up from Coke enthusiasm but there's a condition in the
Vodafone about the book nausea and to preserve person's face blind the social work might look like this so it's great difficulty telling one of the people from another this is
most difficult conditions and you can imagine that your social life would be very difficult and you want to think about social interaction would be great if they called individuals look like this
so there must be something about the new Anakin isn't so what's your face recognition so this story
starts with the charge ghost many your second late 60s and 70s he was recording from Mitre 10 Gore Tex I was showing pictures of monkey faces are the sofa simulator monkey head
word scrambler the phase in a look at the responses of sales and he was the first to find a face like there's no one here is one so this vertical lines are the action potential cell aspiring that disappeared
the ceaseless Sean and this is a beautiful time the controller to hand was shown and you can see the cells respond effectively to the face and up to the head so this was very nice find
if you talk and some time to come in so that you could publish it because you took it would not believe it's every animal but lucky they publish it
Slater and this is the first evidence that there is a specialisation in the brain for faces if I'm any other stuff I like other things than faces and thought for the day went to mingle
other objects of this was to view this is housed within the cat green this is the security products to one big sockets in the monkey bring and all the symbols you indicating positions where people
Anthony because optic ignition hardware it's base of the view that there is a big idea cortex how everything off your conditions can happen and yes of course you would have some cells that are
like the other sales the 9th a selected and the mixture on the complex activity will yes what gives you the identity of the object
try to discover face like this is a serious we know North Terrace talking about before the friend slices
and I thought from this images we was know that they may be in this large expanse of object recognition heart where they might be both specialist regions that are really there
electricity prices face is really Devoted To Face processing a processing only
soul how do you switch until you face to face processing or is it just the tip of the iceberg Basin your statistical analysis that this weekend just looks
Warface like in the neighbouring regions and second do monkeys also his local estate service like humans and yes they do and then what is the distribution of
this region's gorgeous outside so this is the engagement on many years ago you Stephanie macaque monkey same technology
slightly different coils and the picture that we got very consistent the across the fan animals you in the temple ob06 face selective regions
did you find it anatomically specific regions that Sunbury Asian from one of the two to the other but with the exception of the most poster if you find all these errors and all individuals on both hemispheres
the also three areas and prefrontal cortex which I will harder to find but the one in offer to quarter sessions as we do super it's the one of the temporal lobe so yes they are
look like this is like humans they said she was going to work safe kind of evidence by now that the existence might be homologous to prove
hi sweetie painting of the selected it was recording electrodes into the space areas and record from Cell
inside this fy dentified areas and I'm going to shoot your movie of one of the first DLC recorded from one of the region's so it's actually a video of it took my control monitor SA
sinking the monkey shows the quality is not great because it's an actual video camera be talked to take the image in addition to what the animals or you will also see this black square which is indicating radio
on the screen but anyway did not see this and you're gonna hear clips of everything works fine when they could potentially expired anyway is the quantification
96 different stimuli in this image that 16 faces and 18 on face stimuli-responsive normalised between -1 and 1 and you
the biggest response of this particular cell actually across to the 16 faces and not to any of the controller place you can see that there are some stimuli here and get a category for example
listening responses that are quite respectable when it to the pieces between the DS responsive to the face is the colour coded this for your response effect of the South Wales
symbolising response enhancement the Blues symbolising response oppression below baseline and event of using the same as that you can no stick all the response was to get from all the sales recording
the day of the day from this one piece area and get a population response Matrix and this works is organised you can put the button picture number from left to right
and you can see very quickly that most of the sales here are either selectively enhance or security suppressed by faces there's a small group in between Sydney like 10% of the South
where's that secure they're doing but if you do the population average you can see much for your response as well the faces and the monthly subjects if you look more closely with this picture
eliciting this intermediate responses this are clock faces apples pears they are things that have physical properties in common with faces you can pay the full assistant to be like
Barnes and this one true to what is area might be doing if we doing a computer analysis of the incoming stimuli to try and figure out of this face is so not
these are cells in the middle face purchase of a second was pretty fast and when you use the stomach quite a bit that's why I'm back we have 1 poster air
two middle face Area C the middle face Patras and 3 and he wants and was going to talk about this when Tal and just want you I am in addition to the middle state specialist
so we think that actually this is another automatically so conditions seat weekend
you're feeling sorry for this paper is in a different just cut and how answer these think of you screaming and did you know they're ok but still your flag something really
just happened and so we can't stop having this isn't for answers by Peppers when they look like they said and what do you think would be to be happy in life
just getting active you can wait features if you know you know this is not faces ok so what is covered by Charles gross this we celebrate fortnite
what's the distance customer to Vacations I just discovered if you were a few years before orientation selectivity so was a big drunk on that order processing
how flexibility of sour sauce getting more complex and like more concentric rehabilitation still engaged ones from simple to complex sells for copy cells are selected
I don't really have a spatial location all the way up to like the opposite of the visual system and all your friend take a selective not going to term Grande
some off you yesterday there should be one year on your brain or The Saboteur because now you can up with 1 your brain that's fine if and only if you see
mother no matter what she's wearing which direction do you see your from that's the newer correlator you receiving your grandmother is the divorce one year on and the other concerts like
the unit to meet the same point then horse bar look like one sale but like multiple cells but have a spot wasn't a synopsis of difficult sales if you have them
at the top of a processing hierarchy and that's actually have a woman's face is none of course is the opposite of you often would have talked about self-assembly since there's no you know things are the only
cause of sounds or Colette leotard mass action in actually were completely can sponsor specialisation if you look at a flight like this I think one of the things you want to have this I just at the zoo
Woody's on find any of this category who can house sells the Vivo face Lecter but a dog have to be vase past they will appear surprised if you put them over and over and over with 9 face stimuli because
respond to those but we didn't mean of face if they can respond to pretty much all faces there are differences between the different doesn't want to come back to that as well
one example we can actually out and what this question to buy wants to do a cold there quite it matter by for christening do I still missing you I please look at ok so we have
the monkeys like humans have face like regions and the monkey face patches appear to be dedicated dimensions of modules the practical implications of this is now with an president
access to funky imagine it's population of Sao is the coding For One High Level category and we know this category we can make stimuli we can modify the stimuli such as in Parramatta expressions
cancel insight into how the sales actually are presidents' faces how the ice skating properties from this faces and we can do cause all tests and actually show where they sell
involved in fatal condition behaviour
45 you a simple activate one particular Virginia mail going to tell in the second wire male why the monkey will be engagement test like this where to find
The Beatles to looks a bit like this is better the touchscreen monitor the animals free to move around it has to find the face in the scene in the scene is composed of
noise background in better than which the 24 different objects and the target object in this case the face is going to be raining and disability across like 10 different levels you would have other tasked with
body was included which you will not be able to see you but there's a monkey body gear or the monkey was looking for shoe then you would infuse Mawson world
logical agent in activating sales along with a Qantas agent collision with the Commissioner Mariah and then this television yes the face area now in this region is the Auckland directions
answer this for our experimental control are we into the day so I'll be outside and we can use the Ultimate Collection as controls
yes we have a taco medic so a normal behaviour are you getting better and better finding the face and the seam as increasing it's ability
do inactivating go to reduce face detection behaviour only in activating one face area of 12 in the temporal lobe
in one hemisphere and what time do colours does in yesterday's there is retinopathy at the civic processing so the animal can actually use a scanning strategy to go One Direction and
what time does the deficit and slightly this effect would be much longer if we didn't activated on both hemispheres over the control precisely for the animals mate I'll be opening your financial behaviour
and the controls for bodies and shoes are there's no that there with two controls and I went to the next day that the behaviour weird addictions outside as I mentioned it's very specific for
div inside the faisaliah the most basic of face recognition abilities face detection isn't there and then
meat explains baby with me the divisibility of a face like this would actually with inactivation look something like this where it's going to be harder to LA to detect
the second we can take a bunch of this is to be more precise questions about how their processing faces and she didn't activation study was motivated by earlier
video of yourself for features that should be relevant for face detection
and again the question is how can you detect faces even the lighting conditions of a difficult beautiful were combined than others emphasizing that course
in the face of a good rest is to do that the reason is that the 3D structure of our face the same with the lighting conditions are changing and so no matter weather like in shining from
the Origins because they were seated better to nose and forehead or darker than those in for it and saw your phone than human Soccer Physics of like 12 us looks like this before hit by to the left
right I know spider than now insurance over 12 of them straight away Styx actually together can love you too detector sex and it's like you are face the texting yourself honest using a very soon
20 find a course Qantas relationships in the city so what tried it was yesterday with a real face you would pass it into 11 parts and then randomly is
11 different luminance values 27km part and change the rapidly and then you now as it would look like this so no matter what the other pattern looks like he's going to look
particular aircon trust relationship for the forehead was the left eye and he's going to ask is not responding differently in this condition with a 4s brighter than the left I was India
with left eye spider than their forehead and you can do this for our Paris accommodation supplement oven parts and we can
play some combinations we can Mark by arrows the prediction from human psychophysics psychophysics told us 12 of this Qantas parents are going to be important it also told us with the pool
this one's going to be important for taking your face again for today or are you better than forehead OK this is what you found so what the shortest Poppy
diagram of all the cells are the traits found in the cells that he recorded from a child sun selectivity to some of this contrast features and to some of his
what's platytera upwards is 41 Qantas polarity in Wonthaggi the contract peer the number of cells you found the selective and it's a go-through
targum you said it out on you but a few examples of contrast Paris actually different sounds like different polarities like you for example more than 6070 sales
1 polarity not a single one deluxe the opposite polarity and this is true for all this polarities cos it's very consistent pattern second we can explain all the human Soccer Physics
can I preference is here that only you that these are important dimensions for these cells but can all these cases discussed here for the exact same polarity that you would have predicted from human psychophysics
in addition the other contract Paris that apparently don't like a physics but this was awesome care about so they seem to be using this course Qantas features and the again they value
face detection navigate to be here within Northern Areas involved in the face detection with simulator where it's actually hot and the detail I thought this was
is a computer scientist and of course you buy databases and how to use them and he would say I'll take him a few full yourselves into responding to non face stimuli
add talcum play by the rules of this course Qantas or faces are some examples you know this is just like the awesome dark
at least might be in some sort of the Tony has like one of these contracts correct but also human faces you can find some you know when a person smiling ring fitness classes lots of the score
if you're not indices the trippy there so they are so very contract great faces in there are some facesitting at 4 WesTrac and snow canals the coldest response
sales in the middle face patch changes you are increasing the more credit contracts I done the face or non face stimuli and the ancestors if you increase number Qantas in the face
the cells respond more and more if you change the contract 9th a cyclist else don't care so there's something else in the course Qantas is this else care about the net easily Fortress
two things the clear art faces in the course contracts are correct and we could actually predicted some studying
the first study we did with it took advantage of the fact that in the area but can record from faces over and over again at the house in our properties what is that even looked at the effect of Park
this is one of the central features & psychophysics of human face is it that you can get information from the space without any detail just from the rest of the face and example
if you have blurred face of the individual that some of you might recognise Woody Allen and here of course with the Glasses is a little bit fittings
you can recognise an and the other examples in the study where people don't worry last so you can recognise the same as he's just from the stuff that you don't need the details on the other hand we can process
focus on details and sort of his how do you do things with each other what we did was reconstructed face space a cartoon face space
very simple geometric shapes so these days are just made out of all those and triangles and lines survive the simple geometric shapes but if they put together they actually look like faces
navigate Brown address the space space we can go to prom with severe head faces the change aspect ratio they go from here to burn
we have a pupil size like more people see a very big pupils we have into a distance here to this Isa close together and like honestly so confession
career firefighter another stretching the outside of the Seas and son of Hawthorn and we would know when of the change this features and all the same difference teacher dimensions when and the
sing a new value every time you show the space it looks like the two photos trying to talk to you but maybe and licence is very simple so we just asked no matter what is the features are for the fur
should I mention does the final of the sale changes with changing the speaker dimension and as for the 2nd Dimension the Third Dimension and sort itself out for all the different dimensions or beef
for one example sale so we get 19 different training course and office 1970 for a certificate did you know what this particular celibacy
only Blackbird it like the ice makers to get enough for a part like the ice little bit narrow and white and like the iris that small ones was very typical for Holly
processing this feature is this Ramset tuning corpse some more than two-thirds of this is RAM sheep which means that the sales are willing the information that they are amazing and almost like
actually doing a metaphor but it's almost like to take the ruler measuring in title
willing this feature numbers one to one session they're out put another application there's that most of your cooling capacity it's actually at the extremes because many cells
Chris wants to see how many so it's more responsive to the capacities there that's the range Repco just a live and oftentimes with that able to recognise individual space and cabbages and didn't
ok the middle face patches the causal intellectual and for face detection this arvo tree off a selective based on these two fine is we actually
recently began to say design as a strong to be put in order to get to get backlash so we do things to do on modules that are there for face prices in the face personally
ok small letter by the presence of the entire series there is the Redcliffe tuning which is why use for the CSA sensitive to contrast ratio which is very useful for face
so we can we get mechanistic understanding face recognition so we can say ok this anymore two pieces that we can say like wider
what are some places in to others in fact you can predict from the cartoon with the sound or responding to pictures of a troll people with a very fine details physically and
purchase gold in compliance with a different system to have my face detection with some encoding of facial features and gift and cooling off configurations
ok so let's talk about this when I was one of four Gladstone I did it the following
questions whether defeat videos are connected to each other or not if you look at your organisation this piece errors are very for each other the most posted to the most answer is 1 in
what's the 3rd of the interaction of the primary brain 11 different cytoarchitectonic environments you could also imagine that may be the kind of his most local on the other hand there are interested in faces
or you would imagine that may be there are specialised connections between them the baby address this was with microsimulation inside a scanner and so it's first image the face areas within
electoral 21 office acrs here with required from sales make sure it's face elective but then we use this electoral to pass a car through inside the scanner
Lawrence Electrics going to activate sales that in turn is going to change blood flow and oxygenation so soon as we can pick up in the scanner and so yes if this work you should get a swath of Activity 1 dissimilation site
but if the sales at your simulation side appellations that are strong for clean after drive down from your arms you might also find activation that specially remote locations and you can then then see where the
Kitchens Ark where to the face areas computer flatten map of The Monkees the green arrows indicate by outline
hey Siri is your place now it's nation letter to one of the face areas and the snapper card for microsimulation there's no microstimulation so there's no visual stimulus the actually works doing sleep
complete darkness so yes we get it's water metre vt1 the simulation side and get multiple spatially distinct regions of the activated so they're strongly driven by the cells in this region
and this overlap with the face areas and because it was a bit one very consistent across different a serious if he stood outside the also get this patch panel for creativity but now it's out
play system and saw this is the picture of you guys just at the SPCA Rose I should be part of a network of face areas that are still only look at it each other there's no
Peter from Richmond research studies Wi-Fi the 90% of the cell bodies that are labelled after injection in side of face area or inside other face areas or the same face serious
there's a surprisingly specialise anatomically specialise in close network and kind of work
so in this area a l with my interior also virtually all the seals a face like that but you've probably emoji wish you didn't have before and then it's me it's me to confirm
we did not expect you said puzzled by we have no permission why it's happening but in this area yourself to like a profile you never let one profile
they also like the opposite of ideal in this region here now financially that some of the sales did not really seem to be face like that it's a small percentage but actually sells rc24
profile like 145 White they don't like left it like quite Nal this is being confused and then if you go to a m f
some sort of respond to all status doesn't matter whether I doesn't matter who they are doesn't matter how big they are in the other sales that I wasn't on here like where they are and who they were they are in
how big they are but they care exclusively about identity they can be very finely tuned identity in particular two people at the animals never seen in real life
this seems to be a competition going on from here to here in Junee Carlos a conceptual framework you could imagine that there's a
call that's not be coming out sort of letter and more can you be like in voice because impatient and for some reason great in this has to go to this mersa matruh computer
the highlight so we need to catch up on the question whether of these areas two different combinations from 150 Elliot and intuition and the opposite so I thought
they would like to be the same computation hopefully the same competition material and so why they're not at a serious why don't you want to mix the sales with one study this
comics explained some cruise competition work from your life was a question with Tom mchugo some close to that so do all in the tummy worm
about invariants in to talk about this at some point in the courts the different kinds of Transformations easy ones and difficult ones the easy ones are
F1 Transformations we're just shifting something in space or incisor you wanted in plain and soaked you learn how to correct for this transformation for just like three
play Ticket to any match that you can ever see this is where does the easy Transformations attitude changing the picture and the other difficult so if you change your face expression for
Wharf lighting conditions are changing or if you're training your head and depth this is a 9 of Transformation so it's not pretty ball from just like three dots and you can learn
the other could tell you how this picture would look like under Spotify transformation and one of the inside to enjoy was that if you learn this one to find information on a particular order category
you actually have no nothing about another hour to category like hearts it's actually quite surprising to me but they could be like a reason why you might want to have a call this house they didn't have to learn
representations across wine transformation with an omelette my location
yes to get a competition account for the system just described to you in a quarter next terms so we have three levels of processing so we have here like a front and where sells are
use of a face detection the old a selective you could think of this is like a three level crossing hurricane where are the level one is like a face filter that's just going
is Netflix or not the top level you want to go to the occasion I didn't show the examples again I hope I can show you the movies we have some self / 5
the fish light energy and in a technician without identity extremely reliably if you know
so you're more you get something pretty magic so you do get invited level number 3 we're just going to what you wanted me to be surprised by what is a by product you are getting mirror Cemetery
and that's something you didn't sneak into the system and just happens at Magic but there's information for Hawaii Southlands out of vaginal assumptions about the system
the point I want to make you know this particular model could be wrong but thinking about like how annoying to the money over the system might actually with
play a relationship you might think about so the fact that they are such as a processing it for five or six might actually impact with your side mirrors and if we are not what you find nearest
another level and you don't necessarily get this automatically just when I can you possess in together because I like
everything out of that and it's sizing here oops emphasizing here transformation too long this direction but you can see that at least it to level
sing the Isley 2300-1 lateral to the SSD other one deep inside and one of the questions we had a different end
will you my ticket by this is going to connecting faces to social perception so there are some places out there that are not really faces into the faces of dollars I just like one example Sophie
if you tell that they're not really we'll that Adrian's and wondering what is a creepy so there is no
that the Facebook belong to a real agent and the different klusik innovative ways of the faces of a body more likely to engage in the second artificial stimulus is a face
Bing that second other clues an agent in this world change fundamentally how interacting with it Wagner direction to the doll it's like you don't give a different in with a baby and so again like
Netflix the meaning of making the national Wellington to Whangarei understand what the soccer sizelation it is possible so I might look at this again this to think about this special just please social the Tonkin mechanics and
was any PhD student in the lab with addressing this question is like this one here and lucky there's no sounds we can actually play them this like movie
macaque monkeys and they can fix a movements of Vodafone plans expressions and with an ulcer of Steel to the just changing from time to time and with controls of toys at the
also know that I am moving or the don't think every second form 16 with the other and would ask it's wet an earlier study responding to this motion differently than
yes we found it six different 30 he was looking at if you're looking at a static form selectivity we're just reducing the way that the Erebus found
what's the middle set so all the success by motivation to updates if you know compare moving faces to all the eggs are responding more to the Moon faces in the second one
sunflower difference is Nadal roll the same date on more responsible internet extremely light if you're not in the right hand side of the modulation by moving objects to City car place you considered
all the areas or almost all have a slight advantage of moving objects over setting objects this is to be like a general motion sensitivity their interaction
I ship and motion you can see that all the errors are selectively more enhance their face motion then buy North Face motion ok but the owner pretty similar
snow can actually wondering if you have a conscious like this that wouldn't go to steal their couple of things that are different so sorry about motion or it's just about to
if you just want a picture of your one second you can see where this next quantum dear the offer you out of Mordor t-shirt and therefore this response across the board is about at the frequency you know that
update so what what club did was he was waiting another stimulus
if you think about creepiness actually like a little bit creepy said like a scrambled version of the motion of the John Deere should just the same frames of the movie but just left randomly associate with each other
so if anything of the Milton energy in this thing is higher than this one here and we can look now for the countries of those two and also the content to yeah I know what you find
zeros are qualitatively different he finds to face Terrace year which I was bonding more to the natural motion that's been scrambled motion and three phase
respond in Moreton scrambled motion than the natural motion so the opposite preference that's what we think it's Chris here that remember I was it a benefit for fishing
City faces a day just like a fair bit of content I didn't know where the some predictable if you show me something you are going to respond if it's something that I can predict even better
you guys are doing but this one's here they seem to be really sensitive to facial movement and naturalness of social movement that was next Smart
more deep inside the SDS models early and this is our look at the moment so there's no organisation and to discover the new face everything know before it's the 7th
would you call to MD which is really like a smoking area between face perception and agency and over
this is one possible link that the more it might be a second face processing system that can I go to all the evidence it's only in rectal that this area
the other ones I told you before the 600 intricately indicated to be like one network this area never showed up in areas that might be separate and it's kind of nice
it's been nicer to the human situation so human brain you have the poster SBS face area which is exquisitely sensitive a promotion if she often don't even get it for static faces
was sent to the promotion and beautiful study on that and this area by several account is a separate special
that's another thing another thing to the assistants might be in the end who can recognise this actor Hero
sounds ok who can recognise now ok a lot of things like identity
Jack Nicholson the typical African movement agencies not just in patients also identity in Norway
what is Aries are doing ok so my summary and I'm sorry lunch is there so we can be up and running macaque monkey
will be fine to him play two lots of domains with an attention studies for new tension areas here we apply for face processing be fine face selected areas for fish processing recording their microsim
in this region is supporting the notion of this are likely modules that faces and faces only
designer connected into a Facebook ad network it looks like all these errors have different countries visualisation so fy experiments are notoriously under
power in the weed out of number of different dimensions so very cold and face Terrace is not to say that all doing the same but you like different functions and lucky suburbs officer
Sunshine sugar and there is no contradiction to the view of the position and if I can 7th integrated could be separate and separates
listen with evidence of the crossing that we can understand no in competition terms and it's like one where we can link something's causally sometimes relationally
yourself to different levels of organisation to a very complex social behaviour and that's again I think I cool opportunity to have in the domain of social cognition
Goat Simulator very well because he has a pole for the NBA social brain you can make it take this approach deeper and get instant to Exeter intelligent beyond face reception desk