the phone can't answer is provided under a Creative Commons licence your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality
national resources for free to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of mit courses visit MIT opencourseware at ocw
am i t daddy you let me start by first I already learn to this but the talk about the problem of vision so you know we
this is this is just one computational challenge that are brainsaw but it's one of many of us work and are very fascinated by but as you're here in the rest of the course or other
equally fascinating but I'm going to talk about problems of vision and I'm going to talk a bit the specific problem bedroom and that's the problem of object recognition so
try depression lies that for you one thing ill see you when I talk is that are filled it can be motivated by words like vision and optic recognition we can only make progress
restart to operationally to find things and then decide what Domain models are going to apply and I think that's an important lesson that it will come across in my top
this is the way computer vision operationally defines from the proverb recognition invasion it's as if you take a c like this and you want to do things like come up with an answer space
best we have known label say car and you have water corp bounding boxes around the cars simile for people or buildings of trees whatever nouns that you
DARPA or whoever wants to to actually label mate so so this is I'm just one way of operationalizing vision but I think it gets at the crux of
which is there a Leeton contact what's call Aidan contents of this image that all of us instantly should have ring to our memories that we can say
that's a car that's a building of the nouns that happened to our heads we also not other related information about these things like the pose of this car the position of the car the size of the car
point that I'm going to tell you about this promise that that information feels to ask that it's obvious but it's quite latent in the images for implicit in the pixel representation
work done this problem understand is no you haven't I hope they give you some flavour from what the problem feels like so I'm I want to put it back up a bit and
where are from economy to plants perspective to ask why would we even bother ringing about this proverb definition of maybe this is obvious
you don't need to say this but I like to point out that we think of the representations of the tokens of was out there in the world has been the substrate so what you might do what's call higher-level cognition
memory value judgements decisions and actions in the world you can imagine building a robot and having a try to act in the world and it doesn't even really know what's out there so these
opposite of substrate of these kinds of cognitive processes and engineering perspective kind of process uses her behaviour is this is just a storm
and that might depend on your good abilities to recognise a discriminate among different objects I think if you look gorgeous you could imagine things that window terribly wrong if you
identifying what's out there in the world ok so that's just think about an engineer building robot I want it I want to kind of connect this is a slide a stuck in and I want
this course the idea than a mediaeval from nobody's backgrounds or from this background and when I think about the brain have this Queen here to say really neither
two side was studying the same coin from two directions here and really the question we have to offer excited about how many of you work so that is how does the brain work you can do computer science and
how about this question about this question but it's possible I guess but so so what these are all trying to answer this question and then
pretty obvious but when you have biological brands are performing tasks better than current computer systems machine machines that humans have built then the flow
turn the stairs kind of wanna go this way you kinda discover phenomena or constraints over here these leads ideas that can be built into computer code that can say how can I build a better machine base
rediscover with you in anyway we'll come in if you're excited to do the centre still excited of this kind of direction is that when you have systems that are match
star abilities or they can compute some of the things that we think the brain has to Compute the flow goes more this way we will become as many possible ways to implement
idea and he's become falsifiable that is that they can be tested against experimental Deedat asked which of these many ways of implement and computation actually
I'm in the brain and that's important if you say you want to build brain-machine interface is to fix diseases or do something it's on the level of interacting with the brain directly so I hope
skip this picture in mind as I think it's the spirit of the chorus that both of these directions are important and it's not as if we work on this for 20 years and then work on this for 20 years is really the flow across and I
the most exciting to us stay connected at a little bit of history is that a where was the fuel on a problem visual recognition you may I don't have never heard this but here
summer school so there was a summer vision project it was called am i t I used to think the story was apocryphal in 1966 there was a project that the final
Undertaker notification between actually name so this was essentially a summer project to say we're gonna get a couple undergrads things together and we're gonna
a recognition system in 1966 and the state of the excitement of AI we can do anything that we want and of course those you know this problem
much much harder than anticipate sometimes from the team easy for us are actually quite difficult if he wants this is happy to share his dad
with you it's interesting this piece of object that describe things like recognising packs of cigarettes on your desk
update the time of the Abyss here right so it's not like mad men or something so here we are today and I guess I just can't help it should get excited but he was like
cool machine it's is amazing it does it's complications the things got I like I can't tell you all this is 100 billion elements Southbound not tell you about any previous
and the thing it looks crazy but it only required 40 watts of power and the key here is that does not talking about this thing I'm talking about that thing right there right it's so
this is a scale of what you're after and you know me off until talk about power but this isn't the engineer's are especially interesting as a bill this is how does your brain solves problems such
hello why did show the speed great so I'm this is again the spirit of a many of the things that I hope that you guys are excited about the future of this field is another slide I pull out for
like to show us from an engineering point of view we are off and try to see well when I want to build machines that are are as good as are better than her brain so machines today you guys know this
many thanks precalculation tbhs when I was a branch doing a recently want a Jeopardy in memory they've always been nice I mean machines
in the symbol for the memory seeing in Parramatta got a grocery store hey what's that's barcode done I don't know what that was but it just skins in and somehow
this forms a vision that fishing so we better than us what song forms a vision that are more complicated than required generalization like object recognition on the brothers
we like to think that we're still the winner is that even things that we take for grand like walking this is quite a challenging problem engineer's really want to move this over here
race to discover how the brain solves object recognition in the reason I put the suffers from an engineering point of view that just doesn't mean right a bunch of papers in a textbook this is part of the brain does it but
we help to implement a system where this is at least match with us and props and as soon as Sunday will be better than us and this is also a problem that it's a gateway problem that is even if you
this Domain we think that the systems were studying mate generalized to other for instant sensory demands and I think you're here it is ID Gabriel told me you were going to do an auditory-visual
pressing session later in the week ok just build better systems let's step back and talk from a scientist point of view so this is really not
what is the part that I'm going to give you today so I want to understand you're right that understand what does that mean it really means if you boil it down
to discuss if you like is that you have some measurements in subdomain so you can think of this is a state space here like this is like the plant the position of the planets today
this is like the position of the planets tomorrow right so you can say this is the DNA sequence inside a cell in this is some protein it's going to get me through your shirt
mappings that are predictive from one Domain to another we can give life examples of what we call successful science for that's true it's been all this is the core of Sciences to predict
some measurements observations what's going to happen in the future or some other set of measurements so predictive power is the core of all science and the core of understanding and
can you find if you wanted to beat that you think is another way but this is what I come to you and thinking about this from and the accuracy the reason to bring this up is because the actress is the predicted map it is
the strength of any scientific field in St Kilda further along than others and I would say they are still not very far along in our job is to bring it from
non-critical state to every predictive state is that means building models that can be falsified and they can predict things and you'll hear that to my cock is Gabriel mentioned but we
who is Bill models that can predict YouTuber heater and all activity and that's what we think is what progress looks like translate this to the prom I gave you which is the problem
Legend of more generally object recognition you could imagine there's a domain of images so just slow down you just a bit is on the same page which. Here might be all the pixels in the sea
start all the pixels in this image so there's a set of possible pixel images that you could see and we imagine that they give rise to in the brain some state space think of this is
green flower to keep it fridges fix ideas that you can imagine that this image when you're looking at it gives Rise or some pattern of activity across your whole brain and this image
we different pattern of activity across the whole brain and loosely with call is the neural representation of this thing but whenever we do is somehow when we asked you for behavioral
is a mapping between that normal state space and what we measure as the output whether you say it alright if you might say that's a face these are both faces if I asked you for an ounce
ok so this is another Domain of measurement ok so now you can see I'm setting up the notion of productivity what we want to do with we are just complex thing over here images it's somehow
animal activity and then somehow map for the thing we called reception reports and noticeability put things that we call nouns that usually associated with objects cars face dogs cats
ok so understanding this mapping and a predictive sensors is really a summary of what are part of the field is is about and again aka productivity is
product of the science that underlies our ability to build a system like person if you're interested to fix the system like there's order perhaps even augment our own system to be wanting Jacks
do you remember rise the process we have know how this works I think part of the field of vision is spent a lot of the last three decades working on the map in between images and neural activity
that's usually hot encoding predictive encoding back as and it's just driven by human resource were the people saw this is a great way for does like let's go study than the runs and
Stan what do the images of driving what is that is what what's image computable model in the ideal well that would go from images for your responses
do some linkage we think between the neural activity and his these reports and yes this is actually why most of us get into neuroscience cos 0 to win this is actually quite the
from an engineering point you go well there's gotta be some mapping activity and the button presses on my finger is Remi saying the word now do some cause of linkage between this
things that we observed objectively in a subject but if this were philosophers debate about like well you know and sometimes these two sides of the same coin with her own perception
specs of the intro activity that are the thing that we took a where in a separate section to get into all that I just want to
it's the city of the strange thing between Iran's and his reported states that many of us are fascinated by so this is predictive decoding makinson for me at organ the uprising
quotes from humans or animals and I'm not do that stuff apart but I forgot to mention that reels you like to think about those things so for a visual Arctic perception I want to point out that again the history
has been mostly here this link has been neglected or dominated by weekly predictive word marks that doesn't mean they're not useful starting points but the weekly predictive
prequel maybe infratemporal cortex a part of the brain I'm gonna tell you about the dick does object recognition that model has been around for a long time it is so pretty
as you take that out in all of the technician will get destroyed would be a prediction turns up that doesn't actually happen we can discuss that but you know it doesn't hurt tell you how it does it
signals which tasks are more less affected right so that's what I mean by weekly predicted it's a word model based around to face past that's probably true to some extent
it doesn't tell us some it's more tired it's all take this small regions in the sunset of tasks that serve of pieces I don't know I won't say anything about other task that's a somewhat
play pretty to Melbourne store free weekly predictive and my personal favourite that comes in from reviewers lies attention solves that great so so this is just a statement that
look up for rude models that I don't actually have can't and in terms of prediction right I don't know what that means I read this is Hand of God which is in it solves the problem is god of
the predictive model that can be falsified ok so I don't mean to sort of doubt important these before people talking with their attention of phenomena their faces
that we study I'm just trying to emphasise for you that we need to go beyond rude models into actual testable models that make predictions that would stand even if the person
does models no longer around it would make a prediction let me try to find it to me and I said we got to try to find stuff it's hard to find stuff it's big vision it's a big area
how do you reckon I should have said invariably and when I say the same could faces as an object the social important when you're here just from work I think but I want a kind of say to try to limit
but still a big door me and so we tried early on to reduce the problem even further I do something that is more than naturalistic that we think you're just gonna give us more
turn this pretty consent so we did you take a seem like this in your analyser you may not notice it but your your your your your rental stream really a rat
is haikyuu in and say the central 10 degrees there's an out of it I'll show you later that the ventral stream is especially interested in process in the central 10 degrees of information about to
set arms length does you in the room so you may have the sense that you know what's out there but you don't really like your kind of stitch that together and the way you still lots of people shown that's the way you stitch with the
making by rapid eye movement around concert cars by fixations which are 200 500 seconds integration you don't really see during this time here your brain shuts down
the movements to fast for a really keep up with that so you you make his rapid eye movement use to fix a fix a fix a and what you do is that brings this sort of samples
can you at the Central 10 degrees that might look something like this so I can snapshot across it's camp at an ultra play free one more time now you should notice
you know there's one and Robertson dictionary imaging probably trying to sit all the signs a person is a car you might have done two out of each one but you also extracting released into Italy
list 10 more from foreground essential objects when I showed you those images and their ability to do when I just showed you there we think it's the core of how
live stream contributes and we call it therefore we call Aqua recognition which I defined as a Central 10 degrees of visual field 102
second viewing the ration and again it's not all of object recognition but we think it's a good starting point and a way that we probably got into this is because of Rapid your visual
movies from the seventies Malik harder show this really nice Lee this is a movie that I've been trying for 15 years now this is not just a sequence of images we're just quickly one or more
Jackson you should be quickly mapping those to marry you know I'm not telling you what to expect in Tower Pisa I'm not going to tell you the Star Wars character is well I just did but you
you quickly are able to map those things to your to some noun or even a more precise subordinate now I know this is Yoda ready so we are able to do that with
very good at that not asleep to need a lot of free queuing that you're still able to do that and that is really what fascinates us about a visionary object recognition in particular you without feature
pensioner pre-cueing able to do in a remarkable amount of processing I think that's a great demonstration of that and just a quantify this for you because sometimes people say what you're showing your tooth
you're not your little sister doesn't do much is an 8-week categorisation task or show you later on the different range of Transformation just the example images of 8 different categories
it doesn't really matter when you get a very soon work Urban that is you get most of the performance gain about the first hundred Ms is accuracy but he 5%
challenging castles or she really looks easy here it's quite challenge 85% correct if I let you look at the image longer up the two seconds you can pop up to around 90 see you get there is
with longer doing the ration but you get a chance of 50 to get this huge ability in the then we're not the first show this is just to show you our own kind of task that that
you don't want to tell you about we show the image for 100 200ms this is the typical primary viewing Direction that I pin this on we use this for reasons of just efficiency will you see
what's a similar across that time you get your little sister to the latter work in that first glimpse and that's call recognition that we were trying to study here and I know it's
ignition roll a vision but it's now we think I'm much more to find a man that we can make progress on that's what we've been working on this essentially what I'm going to talk about today so think of vision
we did not Court recognition this is David Moore and even and actually a long time it's production and demons if you haven't read this book division
this book it's really classic book and I feel is the first couple of chapters that are with the party really really I mean that's the best part book and one of the things that you take from this book
nothing David Tommy hopefully a long time ago is it that there is a challenge of level that you sort of you you're you don't come into a problem like things I take from this is
you were trying to find three clean levels of practice Theory what's the goal what's appropriate what's the logic and it was
which can you carry out there's another language is ok ill let you decide to how should you represent the data how can implement an algorithm to do it and then there's actually how you run it how you build and hardware
and you know site is often come in and it's really jumping and your iPhone and send it to study transistors the often tennis of started the hardware level I think that's so the biggest
there's something going on why make some story about it if you were recording from the brand or measuring princesses and iPhone but I think they're important Point to take them this
start thinking about what the system what's the point of the system what mind if you doing how might you saw that proud that needs you and our and then you think about it a top-down approach
digging into the brain it's a hoping that the answers will emerge so I'm going to try to kind of give you that sort of top-down approach and what is probably talking about her to give you a bit of it by entry
you too The Promise a little bit more about that in step down a little bit this way and so this this this kind of a I thinking I think is is important to making progress and other bring
so it is a related say that I need a long time ago they gonna pull out for you guys really think I was bridge between the what I just said about them are levels of analysis and when you're ready or not
sinusitis air computer vision of machine learning person so what is a primary source that's the mark computational level one so combination on visions and operate Lee
you're you're here folks and machine learning MIT well there's some benchmarks that's good that's like a imaging at Challenger whatever challenge you want to stop sometimes will save all the brains salt it
define the problem neuroscientist will say well it's something like perception of behaviour so you know there's some sort of behaviour that they imagine although
rising up here is not usually the primary goal but I think that's that's there is Lee some progress on that regards there's like what is the solution look like this is
the type of language so useful image representations for machine learning features but it's not talk about explicit neuronal spiking population
he was using these words interchangeably obvious to you guys but I thought it was going through this is like Mario representation how to instantiate these
Stihl catalogue or two algorithms are mechanisms that actually build useful feature representations that will think about norrona wiring and waiting patented actually executing those algorithm
this is what we think is a ridging language there and it came up in the questions which is really how would you construct it kind of from the beginning
Laurie rules initial conditions training images of words that are used here just a learning machine here with bursitis top of plasticity architecture Xperia
ID say what you can get those of similar questions just with different language because I think of this course is to try to build these links panipat all these different level
ok so hopefully that can help to alright you too how we think about it when we just go and say I want to talk about number one what is a primary trying to solve and why is it hard so I
Arctic recognition is hard and I told you that I did that I mighty Charles and it was difficult it's hard cuz there's lots of objects
you think computers can cut a list of objects is a easy right
list of stuff he was a good at that rate is 20000 of a list of objects is not a horrid thing for a machine to do what's hard is it
and essentially infinite number of images and sent you some happy to take some samples of Throne views opposes of an object as a car under different poses
and be able to generalise a predict with a car might look like in another view and so really then have to be able to see you need some good you need this is
invariance problem due to the fact that again as I did heaps image variation the car is why the barcode reader your supermarket looks fine cause the code is only a very simple and but
you have to be able to generalise across a bunch of conditions potentially things like even background colour of the more severely occlusion things you heard from Gabriel or you made me want to generalize across the class
Descartes slightly different geometry but it still cars this is these kind of generalisations are what make the problem hard so I'm loving them all together and the invariance problem
maybe in a room no this is the heart problem and I think that hopefully that's that if you if that fixes ideas about what you should think about the number of
is the PAK'nSAVE deal with that invariance from OK this is my this is what I was talking about mouthfuls and this is so my version of that
this is to introduce you to the prom of wine at injuries from work and looks like a feels like I'm not going to give you math and had a small it it's just the geometric fuel for the problem
imagine you're a camera or your retina which is capturing an image of an object what's colour is a person I think I called him he is Joe so when you see this image
this is the redness this is a state space what's going on your right now so it's a million retinal ganglion cells think of them as being an analogue value are you sure this is a million dimensional state
so when you said image of Joe deactivate every rental yourself summer lots of a little buddy some point and dimensional space everybody with me
if everybody through all this before what's been going everywhere your hand and online ok so so the basic idea is that Joey
pause the transformation like a change in pose in it but that does is 1 degree of freedom up turning under the hood when was late variables if I had a graphics engine of changing the poop
volume 12 speaking that means there is one wine through here it's Joe projects across his different images here number
poison things just a deterministic mapping onto the random ganglion cells were and if I turn the other now because I could imagine
does Tuna have the two axes and pulled always possible and Platypus in the morning then she'll state-space would be the screwed up sheet of points we could become Joe's ID manifold
2 degrees of you change but it's up to you two points with me so far you're actually get to see all those
imaginary machine actually running the more but you don't really get this in ringgit samples and then but the some underline manifold structure here know what's interesting what's important to point out
is it this thing you know you're trying to sort out it's a little bit it's Haley complicated in this and needed pixelspace it and bending all over the place
the reason that matters in this is what what I'm sort of introduce you to is that if you want to be able to separate Joe from another objects a nacho
another person say when you need a representation so should you run game that's another imaginary state-space we can take simple tools to
brackney information and it's simple tools that we like to use our linear classifier others others simple to his home is the exact same description to you guys and his talk
do you have some we're near Dakota on the state space that can say oh these are at the can separate clearly Joe from Nigel cities manifolds and I see separated by separating paper
that's what these tools can you do is he like to cut plans as one thing they like to do anyone to find locations are regions like compact regions in the space the pain of a kind to you but
you don't want to talk to do all kinds of complicate Reece into the space or it's basically the original problem itself so what you need to have a simple toolbox between goes down stream urine
it's all in your class as an approximation is like a duck right it's a weird song which is what we think the neuroscience of downstream your arms doing it so it's a weighted sum and so
everyone and explicit representation some Narelle state-space then we need to be able to take weird storms some population representation it was separate Joe for nachos
Sam from Jill and everything from everything else that we want to separate we would call that if we had such a space of population with a good set of features or an explicit representation
pretty aficionados you're it's not just queenly linear separation it's actually been a find us with a low number of training examples
that turns out to be clear separation ideally with the low number of training examples that's kind of a good representation
and when I go in the mix up terms here when I am assuming when I took my shape that will map clearly to identity already more Bradley category
that's another topic I will talk about it and just think about the shape of Joe accepting 1gr metrie from another ok simulation that my first
Deepak is not Harbour did all this is take me said to face after render them under changes in and inview and
how the taxi simulator the manifold and 14000 dimensional space and then he wanted to cut a visualise it and because we wanted to just try to make that the point
the best biz manifold of this traffic's are highly curved and Hayley tangle this is a three-dimensional view America it's singapore2010 she'll simulation space
you that space is the three-dimensional new event and the point is that it's it's like 2 sheets of paper been or crumple up together and your kid be the nut fused
you was here because it's in three dimensions but I actually so complicated that you can easily find the separating hyperplane a separate these two arms
we call these Tangled optic Mana forms and really the job of a The Tangled image variation in cheese sauce knobs of Europe position of scale
speak to points in the space and it would be easy that's easy from of lifting objects but if they have to go under girls transformation it becomes complicated structures that need to be untangle from each other
so the women think about with the promise being sold as he has rented sampling don't like a camera on the front and the things look complicated with respect to the lane variables in this case
identity sandwich oh and that these somehow transform does hi mention that transform buy some non linear transformation some other neural population state-space shall we
where do things look more like this to leave variable structure is more explicit but you can usually take things like separating paper planes to said to identify things like shape
identity or other line parameters like position scare you maybe haven't thrown away or deleting parameters I have time or say something about that so you just get identity what have you done
all this are you and have a very nice representations regarding the regional lead frame that's the dream of what you'd like to do it sort of like reverse graphics if you will
this is what we caught on Tangled after confirmation and we think it live somewhere in the brain at least the some to me and I'll show you the evidence brunette later on so what you have done is the other pouring
is the pixel space in summer in the brain is a powerful encoding basis a good set of features and as I mentioned this as already said this must be a non linear transformation because
Transformations of patients of that original Space so now it's like this would be more like what's good in the harbour
stream so we would love to know how this brain songs that this is the this is the human brain isn't on human is not shown to scale just blown
truth is a similar structure temporal lobe frontal lobes there is a non-human primate like this model because her number reasons one reason that we like it is it
the very visual creature tricky is very well matched to ours in fact you in the round disc recognition abilities are actually quite similar to our own this may be surprising to you but I need to show you some of the
some Dita for that this is actually I'm data from a risky Rider Wingham in my lab it's as impressed with this just came out this is thing confusion Matrix patents
women's tradie discriminate different objects on your under these Transformations that issued your earlier images but they have to deal with his common variants is this is Rhesus monkey
trying to do the same thing and then you get choice images was a car in the dog retreat
many of the other ones and you have Tibetan image and is someone predictable view and unpredictable background and you have to make a choice so this is the kind of Confusion difficulty
intuitive but this message armitree similar ride camels confused with dog and you know tank is confused with truck and that's true both monkeys
the sum of the shouldn't be surprising to you you know that humans make the same different the same password if not for humans are difficult for monkeys because probably should be very similar
structure is this is not to bring you know they don't have to bring it a bunch of knowledge about tanks for driven by people that they just have to say it was a kangaroo truck
conditions in a very similar patterns of confusion and these pants are very different from those that you get when you run classifiers on pixels or low level visual stimulation simulations
so so these but they're very similar to each other to be indistinguishable monkeys and he's kind of parents of Confusion ok so that's one reason we like this subject
Adam the monkey model is that the behaviour is very well matched to the humans the other reason is that we know from a lot of previous work that I needed to that there is some sort of
Visions in these part of the brain can be the deficits in recognition task so again we know that the ventral stream we think the ventilation Souls recognition so we should know weak word
what we just don't know exactly what's going on there just to Oreo his visual but his mental areas V1 V2 before and if the temporal cortex RIT cortex
set a timer to regions involved in decision action and round the bend to the medial temporal lobe two regions involved in long formation of long-term memory
humans and Gabriel mention it in his talk we can go in and we can record from the brands and we can put her I like to be in your brains are directly we can do that in a systematic way this is the advantage of an animal
what is faster a human mile ok as it is now so now we taking it from translated to behaviour taking their behaviour into a species we can study know roughly riddle
how we want to try to understand what's going on so the ventral stream as Engineers we take the scroll of sheets and cortex and think of them as a very been showing you a surd of populations of never answer the
each of these sheets I'll give you numbers on a slide coming up their sons for processing they may become and here I put these ts and I may be some common cortical algorithm processing for
this way there is also intracortical processing and is also some feedback processing going on and it's all that schematically Illustrated in this slide that I'll keep bringing up here we talk about these different
what's on the back of stream.it Cortex here at the end why do we call it different area is one reason is a complete Renee tapping map a map of the whole visual space
different levels in right now there's one Elgin in the thalamus is another and he wants another map and B to happen before there's another map and iKey that it's less clue
when I went through that he is one area I lost maybe what time I see more about that that detail and it's too it's not that retinotopic nit accept
husaria parts about why I guess the by using the different areas so if you can't sit there for you complication is think of future leaders of
visual representation that's we transforming the data from that complicated space to some nice is space and it's doing is probably in a stepwise gradual man
80 is believed to be that powerful and coding basis that a little earlier we had his nice planned manifolds and I'll show you the evidence for that is a more
more recently from a review I did that gives more numbers on these things and I size the areas according to the relative cortical area in the monkey and his bhiwandi
48080 is a complex of areas and I'm showing you this this kind of latencies instead of the average lane cheese in the
visual areas you can see it about 50 MS from an image of the runner to get activity in the 160 and 3 to 70 out of 10 Ms step across his different his thoughts about
animal second lag between an image of here to see changes and activity at this level up through that I'm referring to I when I say I T I'm referring to a i t and c i t
together that's my usage of the right in front of your fish Barnardos in the room and that's about 10 million output and I can just a 6 numbers and you have like 30 cm
put the answer by 200 million year olds and be one similar in v to her but other parts of the visual system Mt
heard about empty so you can see it's tiny compared to somebody's areas and I'm talking about here so if it's
postcode but at least those you haven't seen it should at least the exposed so no retina you guys know in the retina there's a bunch of was a bunch of cell layers in the render and as I can't
I think there's a beautiful camera so you don't on the retina now to me the keys in the rent is the only got some cells are going to project back along the road so he's the rent
lamb sells out you lived on the surface of Lake comes through his processing in the inner layers of soil type so start the T20
the original physiology this for two functional and a Central pipes where they had this have an centre off centre let's take an answer to sell your shining light in the mid
the Spartan besides depends on where you are and then in the visual field so you shine a little bit of light in the centre of the response was up to the spike
up here in this round the response rate goes down so it hasn't on centre off surround profile and then is a flip type here so so that's the be
functional paper you think about the runners tailed with all of his Point detectors I have some nice stainless around effects there is some nice gain control for overall Illumination
and and I will be it's a bunch of nice pixel map coming back down there and organise a drop down the optic tract to the
OK I'm going to skip the LG and go straight to be 1 people have known for a long time functionally lv1 cells they have sensitivity to specially
edges they are have what's called orientation selectivity hopefully this is a new year guys here is a simple 71 if you shine a barrel
add Insiders receptive field 30 receptive field is I don't want to go OK it's OK if you ask cos I want to make sure you guys are ok so so receptive field The Shrine of our lady
turn it on turn on the radio station gets good response out at the cell move it off this position now might respond as a little bit off response here change the orientation nothing
for field elimination nothing happens OK so there's this is called selectivity that is a some portion of the image face that it cares about doesn't just
on to any light at that spot like the rat like the pixel ways the retinal ganglion cell would so now there is this this complex Shell it's also only one
which maintains or intentions activity across a change in position as shown here also cross of changes and scale but it so yeah maintains it mean
is tolerance with composition tolerance for position you can change the bar and still likes that warranted Barb when you change its angle and it goes
great so it's still maintains the sinks like to have some time together as a buildup of some more some orientation sensitivity followed by some power and threatened these they're model
weasel that are $40 first and then you don't these out of these that's the simple version and these can you build with and like
is the dog selectivity from pixel-wise cells with an and like operator lighting is up correctly pin imagine oriented Tune cells built this way as evidence for this and info
how is your constructed the tolerance of these complex sells a start to build by a combination of simple cells and is some evidence from this and the
all the way from people and weasel I want to know what price for this and related work in the 1960s and then there were a bunch of computational models that are really inspired
still the core models of how the system works some of the original ones are in the 80s and then and Tommy poggio another is built at
Max Molly was a probably heard about that some of these similar ideas much more refined and much more match them data and and so but these I just trying to point out the beach
physiological observations of what inspired class of largely feed for models that then you heard about much today ok so that that was sort of that
have a good grip 21 know what's going on in me to sofra long time people that was hard to tell the difference from B1 and B2 and I just thought id show you guys is a spider stuck
is from Arizona Charlie and Tony Marsh and I think you both have arrow teaching in the course of it later so he may say some of this but who sells have some
hippity to natural image statistics that sells don't and maybe I'll see if I can take you take you through this so so the way that
the where did the did those Aires you can simulate so this is all driven off of work that arrow and Tony have done on your share was going and texture synthesis so you have these original
is NF running through a bunch of B1 like filter banks and then you kind of take a new image of random random see which is a white noise and you try to make sure that it would activate
populations of the 1 cells in a similar way is a large images that would do that cos you just drink Sunbury statistics but these are some examples of them for this image of this is one that
look like so you can see it doesn't look anything to you doesn't look the same as this but the be one these are members of their dissimilar in the summary statistics in Dee Why and then you start
prior to busy 1 summary statistics and then you try to match those and what's everything you say to get something that looks text you wise much more like this original image in this is a deposit
at work in the reason I'm showing you this is that Tony's loud is going recorded in B1 and B2 with this kind of stimuli and the main observation they had is that
doesn't care when you show it this or this so these if you want to be one is for both the same with short as we have a summary statistics for me one right and for the average
I'm sure you heard the paper if you wanted much more detail we go to the two it is a big difference between this would be two cells respond to more and their switch to respond
and really want whatever you can just take from this is that due to reply reply repeated another and like an operator and be one it's a simple in France
to support his conjunctions of me wants to tend to be in the direction of the statistics of the natural world
holistic statistics but that's the spirit of the field is I'm trying to understand
everybody thinks that somebody with corners are more complicated structure but this is a way but current in the field to try to move his image computer models for it if you want to be too in and Tommy
when are the berries of this is what's the one of strongest differences that you see between B1 and B2 other than the receptive field size it's so quiet some exciting work if you if you don't
rd2 ok then you get up for things get much work here so what's going on it before we deserve briefly say that one of my post that says n word
just because it builds on at early reason to call Russ when she was a postdoc in the lab compared V4 she compared to a skip that but she was using these symon
scrambled images of the text images from these are the original images and ease of the tax provisions of this you looking at textured version of that you can see that these algorithms
capture the magic contacted the images and when the call actually showed is dead before doesn't like similar to what you just saw there in that really like the one
doesn't care about the differences between his response similarly as a population to this and there's an there's an there's an there's an there's an but I teach there's a lot about this V
so this is just repeating the same thing the general idea that you're you have and like operators that we think or aligned along the ventral stream that are tuned to the kind of
annual Tauranga in the world and some of the evidence of the evidence for and B2 and then later and in v for and i t in the Coles work if you peace that all together you go to Play Store
four member before is Alex three levels up and what what is beef or do you want this is Jack's working 90/96 this is from Jacqueline your day been
your people have some ideas that may be there this to do and functions of before like it and show these sending people done and B2 they would show a bunch of images like this
well is it like this petition ratings of his current ones and you know what you get out of this is you know you can trust some story about it but you'll get a bunch of responses I did the colour in case the response
and you can't look at it and people would tell some stories that I kinda like TV it's a day we don't really know what this before as we're doing this was a science paper so are you
come back and read it and then any other part of party work together a few years after that
tritoswim figure out would be tuna before around to do and they did things like take images like this which isolated and try to cut them in the parts like curb card
how many Pirates curb can't keep convex and you know this was most of it off of some the psychology literature and then we define these based on so the centre of the objects
this is an image computable mile it was just a basis that they built around these can silhouette objects and see me this piece of said about any kind of sort it out if we like
they have policies that they could fit the responses of you for the rounds in this piece of send actually this is so tempted you if they could actually fit quite well and that's kind of it's being showing here's the response
any Foreigner on a colour in the kids the depth of the response so you can see this is her like that previous like you're looking at TV is it looks complicated but under this Marvel they were able to in the sheet space explained
for the response rates of The Foreigner on that before Curves about some calm come curved comedy Curves accommodation of Perth
stop bring cart with Edwin Anna to poster ID and show that the neighbours and combinations of these new for cells could fit postal address IP response is quite well so if you read
ready for an 80-year-old come across studies their importance to look at unfortunately I'll give you some of an image computable model of what these neurones are doing but it says some of the work that you should know about
if you want to look in before it really i t so I'm telling it to you so let me go under 80 which is what I want to talk about for the rest of today
atnr let me do this just quickly say that the amount of me again suggest that the vit is the central 10 degrees and you
look at that are based on even though we won beach with you for coming the whole visual field you make injections in the for that's it is shown here we make injections
retro parts of the V4 representation which is search up here that you don't get much projection in the eyes which is Siri on see what green colour is it a projections in the centre part of the
is red side till you see much more coverage in 2 and 280 which is shown here so it's 10 degrees that's rough everything about his mercy but this is
some of the evidence beyond recordings that anatomical evidence that as you go down in the more more focused on the central 10 degrees
history of 80 recordings of what people got excited about i t in the 70s this is work by Charlie gross is one of the first people who recorded 90 cortex and
it was sure yet they did your day we're at this was an error we remember if you wish you had just done the work in the 60s and they've recorded from that the cat visual cortex and that have found
sales price without tools for a bit the heat there like let's let's recorder if you want make sells girl so they were brave enough to put electro down and i t cortex
70 and what makes this Nanango that's an encoding question what what's the what's the image contact that will drive this Nora and it's fine just look
what they're doing so they know they didn't have computer monitors are actually leaving around stimuli in front of the animals zanessa ties and what a table this is a monkey
how do you spell with a cat and a little bit too monkey the use of these stimuli was begun one day when having feel the driver unit with any light stimulus that priming spots of light edge
is a human we have been using we waved a hand at the seamless screen weird in front of them and elicited a very big response from the previously unresponsive
cancel and then we spent the next 12 hours on the table the recording from this Narayan nothing's moving you can record for a long period of time
listen to The Spikes we spent the next 12 hours testing various paper cutouts an attempt to find the trigger future so that sort of the you can see that you will weasel idea what makes the
what's the best thing what's better that's gonna become a war lagerfield spend time doing the unit we need tyre Steamers that we're amused
strength of the response that they're pretty wish we could not find a simple physical dimension the Coralie with this rank water however the rank order adequate seem like in correlate with similarity Frost
take a physically drudge to the shadow of a monkey hand so there's a cord of the stimulation to see look it looks like it's unthreaded hand that's all I know how to describe
can you find some simple thing I hear this this kind of study more than last a whole Domain with people started going to recorded is narodzenie fun interesting different types but there's a no
liquid Charlie grows later so much when I see animal control conditions yes to orangina on that respond you can see more of his hand this is a post in his time Instagram lots of spite spite spite spite
respond more of these hands and then do these other kinds of stimuli here that is so you could see these neurones have tuna specific combinations of high selectivity
has shown you report something really like faces that you could find a nuts on my hands right so so you could find your answer seem to have some interesting selective
text then Anna is later when I'm this is from the work of a number of years later just one example that this selectivity has
power is perceived the position of a stimulus that's what shown here the fact that this is bars are hi just means that tolerates movement in the world with a arthritis
degrees of a triangle Mrs position will be the stingless around so this was known for a not a number of years if there's some tolerance to position and size changes at least
I'm putting some selectivity and some tolerance and that should remind you what we already said do you want to some selectivity simple cells this intolerance complex elves
do you have the same themes you're just different kinds of types of stimuli being used then people really went on in the 80s especially in said what's let's go after this trigger feature
does Tanaka's group really Winifred is really hard they tried to the tanakh is Rupert fine what's the best dinner with that would find angle bunch of objects in front of recorded in Iran
find the best of a whole set of objects do reduction they try to figure out what time can I reduce this this is their attempt to reduce the sting as to it's features which with dog
lowering the normal response or I respond Terrace by Ty response examples
into the simplest thing that could be the response and so when he did this they were trying to take them like this and end up with stimulate it look like that ok now many you should probably
can wonder here there's lots of pass through stimulus space which night clear these are elemental when anyway there's lots of ways you can can I get easily lost in this
navigating around here this is just again history of the work this is the kind of things that people were doing and then from that they want the present what I think of is the ice cube
you guys think is actually still at very reasonable approximation been only sure that attended to like certain these kinds of relatively to reduce stimulus features
objects but the date nomia scale regions of i t that nearby neuron's within a millimetre so have similar traffic
is they don't to do not so scared willy-nilly throughout the tissue when you go recording your minor on the similar for the some mapping with nit cortex this is Schematic
this is optical imaging and cortex also from Tanaka's group that show you that done these that these different blobs of tissue Get Active
different images showing here and I'm just trying to steal on this is around a little less than a millimetre and spatial organisation
I don't really get on the beaches in elemental features Yatala at this time ok so then later something there's lots of beautiful working
I tell you all of it some of the most exciting work recently and you're her mother's from that people start use Athenry so door sound frame wall in March Livingston
the story of the news after you compare pieces vs objects this was motivator from human work by work like Nancy kamlesh allowed in others that we then with
how long was it in monkeys you could find different parts that would show up buttercup face patches we have a relative preference for faces or objects again I'm not gonna say I don't want to take all the
but you have this just here and there was really cause you going to record from these patches and then you find a very enriched locations for face right
which locations were known from another other studies but this is a nice correlation function imaging and is in Richmond of his face cells that we're shown here that is not responding
I'm mostly two faces and at some other objects sort of respond to these this kind of telling you somewhere things and also tells you that
special clumping at least 4 face like after cat a scale of a few millimetres of show the size of these patches organisation
what from my room loud that being the oldest it through this in the interest of time we can nap and record the runs very precise in math and spatially
read out with Athenry and this is just a larger field of view maps of the same idea ok so what we have then just a kind of white wrap up this
stream we have some untangle dispersive information and what I what I want to try to convince you up now is that I told you about the mental Stream by minutes
how you getting 80 cortex this is a powerful representation for encoding object information so the way and then we'll take it they will take a break as we've already probably been going well
yeah so what what I told you is I blend you up the ventral stream of giving you a bit of the history so now as talk about i t more precisely
does work from my own lab one of the things that you going to record i t you go record extra sanity in travel down and ID for tax which is down here and
you saw what you saw from the trolley gross about you sure bunch of images and your elbow tree images
Dark Souls are action potential spikes out of a particular site and you these repairable write you have you have some possum variability here but you'll see that you're more
you're a little more hair last year's images are all randomly in a leave when you collect the details of sugar in a minute and you got a different sites and it looks different images
activity should not be surprising because I already showed you this from previous work this is just a former all black you can also see how you're getting closer this the light the time La Grande
I'm home no second Stingers on here and there's a long time like I don't know
that's what the normal response is look like here I think I know what you guys think maybe I should have hooked up audio you maybe might be able to hear this is actually recording that we did
Hunger Games dead in early stage weed in the lab
hi babe sorry animal getting a board for fixing on a diet
despite those are action potentials raid and you're I don't expect you to look at anything like it safe Easter and whatever I just want you to get a
how does data were originally collected this is pretty grainy video but you're you get that kind of idea and that you collect data like that and you can you can find selectivity and those
Paris is a to show you but Gabriel and Tommy and I saw the three of us sitting on this room waybackwhen and 2005 said will look the population of ice
we have good useful information for solving this this difficult Arctic man for Tang from it might be a good explosive representation so we did a servant first Mike off early testibus
we took this back from a different categories that we have chosen and there's good stories of why which was objects if you'd like
you're down by me to say simple objects remove them across position scale and we collected your changed the responses of a of a bunch of sites to changes in
how is different visual images to show you were produced in 400ms is man this is call recognition receiver we just showing them 400ms then we should another one of those
ok and from this what you do is you could get a population set of data will you be here we recorded 250/18 say here's a sample of 63 States
what's the 7th and images the Sponsor is the nearest bar stools images of 7th of the images we show here to say other than you have is rich population
an hour question is what is this what what lives in this population in that we collect it is explicit with regard to category so we come back to what I told you earlier about those
Tangled manifolds and said the coding tools are so can a simple the coding to off work that I T population in tell me what's out there and everywhere using linear class
where is the time because we took that as you heard from home as are operational definition of what a simple tool is and if it could be code information about the object identity and would say what that means
the operational definitions this is available accessible information is generally good so if you imagine that the activity was a schematic
Gardiners Run one run to in about a bunch of biting your arms if you can separate and the object from all the other object these points represent the population response to each image of
Jack numbers many images of you and you can literally separate that that with me and if you had a hard time separating at this would be in implicit these are like Tangled
turn off all the inaccessible are bad information so we just weird I mean I just died and I did this we talk at the end we took the response
image like this one to produce the publication of actor again we recorded a bunch of Horizon recorded than sequentially and then piece together these populations actor in this new kids movies
bike simulator after the population of we can do various things in fact I think they're really did everything possible as I remember the time and wanting things we did was
spikes on the simple things of the word counter space of 100 Ms spikes that give you a number one number here counter at spikes get one number two
niraj you get you get and numbers with a point in an n-dimensional state space and when is the number of the runs and then we had already provided the images in a diff
how to grow roses from here to the categories and then we just asked how you could separate how are you could do faces versa 9 phases toys and toys
these are all slides but you get the idea that you don't need that many site already gets a very high levels of performance I bought categorisation and identification
the interesting thing about this was that this that you could solve this simple forms of this invariants problem in this representation quite easily that if you just trained on train on AC
Jack's the centre and size a simple Street agree size centre position tested on other the same thing just held out repeat of the stator you did quite well that's for baseline
what's interesting is him in position scale and then you are so early as well so you can't have naturally generalized to this other conditions by just training
simple simple condition so this is evidence that the population is a good basis sad for so long is crumbed prawns a few number training example Bombers population than
as well across the problem heart so I can we promise that a long time ago was it released episode what the phenomenology looks right for the story that
telling yourself I do this easily in earlier visual areas like the one or simulated be one of before we later show that a number please
this is consistent I'm sure you will like a few disposition Tyler and stays Tyler is the selectivity it's really just an explicit test of the idea population
so you the take on here is it is explicit object representation and I can prove you that this is the link this pretty to mild to the calling out we're going to talk about that
this was the important menology that we did tell you today hope that reduces the problem of visual object recognition and the way we restricted
recognition we talked a lot about predictive models have been the Gawler haven't presented much to yet hopefully that's the second part of the time I give you a tour of the ventral stream but I mean it was a
carport or answer everybody would say that you know you've never liked it always work there's no way I can do that off in even in even a whole week I just tried to hit some
lights for you and I told you that the population seems to have Saab a key problem this sort of invariants problem that I stayed up and one way to step back as it will be last
nearest self trolley gross or you're even human weasel we're the field of Battle stream physiology with hardly described import phenomenology
population phenomenology and so now we need this in the more advanced models of the next phase of the fuel is developing and testing is predictive models
a motivated beginning but I have too much up yeah so this was hopefully a bit of history and setcontext to where we are