the phone can't answer is provided under a Creative Commons licence your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality educational resources for free
to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of mit courses visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
I've prepared some slides of course but I don't know please interrupt it anytime and ask questions ok
I've sort of got a big Panorama things to talk about it's basically impossible to cover everything ok
basically I advertised this talk as an outlook for the future and of course that that
to bride so I picked a few things which are of special interest to me and what they are are the pathway the possible
pathways to nuclear war ok now as you know that what I what I
talk about orphan is in comparison and comparing the danger to the planet
of course it's population of climate change and nuclear war ok so climb
change is just I think the probability is pretty close to 100% it's I don't know how to Qantas
but it's it's fairly certain that we are we are into an era of
warming hand and it's consequences and this is a slow steady thing terms of probability of occurrence with all its
occasions nuclear war is much easier to avoid but if it happens and I've got
read a the probability is very low that's what I call the probability structure so the probability of a nuclear war any specific day
is lol the cumulative probability is higher of course and if that event occurs it's
just traffic so what happens is the destruction just starts in that the cat is the destruction of course is local in the place
weapon blows up the the destruction of depends how many bombs go off and how much so it goes
but we could have a Global consequences if there are enough of them so called nuclear winter
ok so having said that I just want to talk about that this is the theatre
awesome that that's what keeps some of us worrying about this problem and working on it ok so basically I want
talk about the possible pathways to nuclear war I'll talk a little bit about proliferation and the non-proliferation treaty say just a few
it's about the possibility of nuclear weapons abolition we bit about Obama's record and and
ok that's that's a pretty ambitious agenda
there are endless debates about the utility of nuclear weapons some people are
roll having them not using them but having them because of course they were Pro
and the one case that they were use and of course we use them on Hiroshima and Nagasaki
people says that actually save lives because the war ended more quicker that way I think that's why we need to be
goldbug it's a point of view which is held OK so it it actually save casualties
and a prevented World War 3 these are some of the arguments I'm not trying to give all of them but these arguments that you can find in the
and you can find books and this goes back and forth ok and of course the
the counter argument was that that the use of atomic weapons in in Japan was was not necessary
what was really necessary was to agree that the emperor could stay on and that turned out to be the key
ok that people argue and certainly almost everyone agrees that the use of the second born in Nagasaki
was something that should not have been done ok I think there's much more agreement to that
a box that this use was actually the first step of the Cold War ok of course
Japanese civilians were killed 700000 and 2 cities with destroyed on the other hand we destroyed almost all
major cities in Japan by conventional weapons and and of course Japan did not have an unblemished record in Korean Chinese
I'm not going to go into that but the moral dimensions of World War 2 a pretty horrible OK let's start
ok are the Inner Vision about killing civilians are pretty much disappeared in World War 1 and was just told
ignored in World War 2 I would say ok and in the post
error the argument is that you didn't need nuclear weapons to prevent a war between the United States and the Soviet Union
ok I pretty much think that's the case myself so the question here is
questions are there they have no nuclear Wars are since the first two weapons were used of
how many explosions but they were test ok so was that the torrents there's a theory about nuclear taboo because
morally so awful I'm a bit sceptical but it's a theory that out there by an important yelsos
our just is it luck of the reasons and so forth so many
well I'll give you some of my conclusion that the end but the crucial question is does the possession of nuclear weapons make a country more secure
you heard this in the case of Ukraine when when the Russians are took the Crimea when they basically have their stealth
vision of the Ukraine how OK which is going on as we speak wood
are Ukrainian nuclear weapon the term of them and when the Soviet Union broke up in the
1991 there was a lot of discussion about what would happen to all the nuclear weapons they were mostly in Russia
rain and kazakistan and we managed to persuade the ukranians they were the toughest and
marquees to give all those weapons to Russia but in fact or one of the things
there's a lot of History here but one of the best articles that I've read and I think it's obviously true I stayed
that that in fact the Ukraine And Kazakhstan never really own those weapons ok they were really owned by the
Union the Ukrainian army was not prepared to take them in any way they really didn't have an army they have
have an army now 20 years later or something ok so there's no realistic way
the ukranians had a nuclear weapon that could be used they had possession of nuclear weapons but not the actual ability to use
ok so it's a very funny thing it's a very special case and it's a very funny thank but
how do I recommend this Herd I would say more important or at least as important as is the presents
Malaysian stable this is a key question ok many people doubt it that are good fortune and
having any nuclear exchanges since 1945 is purely the torrents if there isn't an element of lock
the issues involved and each specific case is different so it's hard to generalise
I mean one of the issues what are the differences between physics arms control is how the LAC
controllers is the lack really of science how much you know more difficult the situation is to evaluate
ok and of course now or with with relationships between the United
states in Russia in fact the whole West and Russia at a low Point probably a few decade-old low Point
future of arms control seems bleak at this moment I have to say it's hard to maintain optimism
ok I'm finally versus perennial question about abolishing nuclear weapons which is certainly more and more remote as time goes on but I think
as academics we should think about it because there's a very important issues OK so we should think long range is
saying it's not going to happen quickly obviously if it all but is it desirable there are two separate questions
desirable and is it going to happen ok so immediately after
the development of the atomic bomb there were intense discussions inside of the Manhattan Project before the public knew about it
ok and there was this famous Frank report and the conclusions of the Frank report
use the bomb for a demonstration not on cities share the secret the secret not nursery the details
make it I don't think anyone ever propose that what what's meant here is Cher the secret of it's existence before it's use
that's what they're talking about because the use without notice particularly without notice to the Soviet
would ensure the start of a Call of a war a cold war and a nuclear arms race and that's exactly what
scientists predicted very sophisticated people Frank was a Nobel Laureate from Germany to escape from Hitler
ok and the there were many other things that happened the scientist
send it together they formed the the bulletin of the atomic scientists the Federation of atomic scientists which still goes on although it's not a straw
is it was and they develop this actions for Lillian plan William floor plan
which oppenheim I played a major role and then ended up as the brook plan which was not really what was proposed and
it was turn down immediately by the Soviet Union ok for various reasons I can go into them but I won't
so the error of possible arms control in in 45 19459
46 collapsed ok and in the beginning of the Cold War period and
what the scientists fear the most happened and the other thing is and you hear this from the people who
first developed the bomb and then work is actively as they could against it and many of them were at MIT some of the name
you know very well Victor vice cough there was Hans Bader from Cornell and there was just a whole group people very proud
scientists and Hans Bader both Vicky vice cough and hands played told me purse
they said it many times and public then when we realise then about 19:46 that there was no agreement was going to happen
house elf what is the worst thing that could happen and they said we would build 100 weapons
100 and the Russians would build 100 weapons and then we would face each other down with 100 weapons that was the
take the sophisticated right man for imagine in 1946
what did people expect first the atomic scientists they thought that the nuclear weapon was so high
Bollywood change the behaviour of mankind and politicians like Churchill and Roosevelt believed
that this powerful weapon would allow England and the United States with the Monopoly to 2B
be able to say the way the world evolved ok so both sides were wrong
typical ok so are the influence that it had has been reasonably smart we never
stop the Russians to agreed almost anything we wanted them to do for example that took over Eastern Europe we hated that
let you know it just goes on and on the Communist China we hated that you know we're just
the things you know I just mention a few major ones ok so that's what I mean by it's course of influence its possession became as
a symbol almost straight away and but there is some the torrents in it it isn't the torrents
sleep well useless the torrents and a pirate's a combination of the two of my think works the some extent so there's been a nine news
now I want you to look at this graph this is the buildup of nuclear weapons between us and
Soviet Union and you'll notice this scale 5000-10000
100 is down here ok the Soviet Union blew up their first bomb for
is after we dead ok as predicted not only was it predicted that they would get the bomb but that they were
take them 3 to 5 years that was the number that was given by the atomic scientists and it was hotly disputed and watching than that so
and again we built up to astronomical numbers tens of thousands of weapons and finally we have a
the climb through nuclear arms control agreements and through terrifying events like the Cuban missile crisis
and other spirit of that build up is I think exemplified in this great cartoon ok
you can read for yourself from the middle of the Cold War ok and I think this says the story
here here well I mean they developed all kinds of fancy strategies but at the heart of it was fear
just plain fear of a devastating First Strike and then you had the build up counterforce capabilities
absorb the First Strike and the able to destroy the enemy after the First Strike of but the astronomical number
was mad and it was called mad mutually assured destruction it was literally
mad I was looking from the outside but we won't really on the outside because we would have been the victims so it was
but you're not logic logic is is in a certain sense of relevant in this situation I am in this such
a grip of fear on both sides and it's really true I sat through the Cuban missile crisis person
with a dedicated Russian Communist so it actually come to work in my laboratory was a very interesting experience
before was all the fault of the United States most of the people thought it was the 4th of the
Soviet Union lots of people here but I thought they were both it for you no
natewa equally nice people but that you know they were just upgrading from too much fear so they overdid it
do you know this business of 100 when they often our students and class how many weapons are enough and nobody
how to answer that question but then I say well how many cities are you willing to give up you know the case of the rushes masca leningrad that's Two Cities
and there's a famous exchange between Jerome reasoner who is ex president of mit and also science
the Canada with gorbaczow or he asked him exactly this question and and Gorbachev was just amazed
so well that there you go so I think it's fear and distrust
cause fear in this plus they go together that's very important I just want to point out that one of my nuclear submarines
this is the maximum loading by the weather load it a little less now but it doesn't matter I don't I don't change the slide but
quickly they have 100 and 300kw Warheads so an order of magnitude larger than the Hiroshima weapon or not
lucky weapon and each submarine has a maximum loading it should say of 96 Warheads
independently targeted you can destroy 96 targets after firing it takes 10 or 15 minutes to reach
OK so you could it's kind of staggering ok so the total explosive power is 3
times that of World War 2 1 submarine it's incredible ok
this is the present Global inventory more or less you can see this is the number that counts
these is the strategic why is ok and you can see there the order of 1500 which is this new Star Trek
we're just about it that limit anyway and that all the other countries have typically a few hundred at the most are these are all this is
gas work as to the numbers nobody it's well it's not known know I think 10 for North Korea's probably
factor of 2 over 3 high but gives order of magnitude this is gas work frankly cause these are all secret
people do the best they can let this is a table from Hans Christian Cinema Federation of American scientists who keeps track of these thing
well as he can all they look at the literature and they look at budgets and they look at satellite pic
they do their best I think they have the right order of magnitude but nobody claims they know the exact number I mean if you talk to her
question says very good and who knows what he's doing he's very smart and competent he'll tell you
educated guesswork ok but it's more or less it's enough you you know I mean 90 100 weapons
it's all 100 weapons is overkill
they want it to be highest
except for Israel which doesn't want to admit as any but they want it known anyway so it's a complex game but for most
other countries they say it's for the torrents so it's better to let your adversary know what you've got
a chain is also very quiet about the numbers because they have relatively few numbers and they want to keep this positions
greater than all of that so they don't want to have and they don't keep the missiles on alert either Chinese a very
country with respect and nuclear weapons ok and pops exception
so the pathways the nuclear escalation and war as as I stressed is
is fear fear to me is the biggest Factor ok I'm sure people will argue with me or every point I'm making it some
what was controversial by the way I don't you know I'm not trying to hide it but just I can't give you every nuance
that's 1 hr people write books about each subject so you know you have to oversimplified
anyway I consider the two possible pathways to war one is an accidental launch
between the United States and Russia and the other is escalation from conventional war and Indian Pakistan ok
now somewhat less likely is North Korea's use of a weapon but I suspect they won't because I think they
are constrained by other military reasons in on the Korean Peninsula
North Korea wants to rattle the sword so to speak but they I think really want it for both the turns
as far as I can tell and for the survivability of the regime which is a whole other you know but that comes into all these think that's why you cases
North Korea is a very special case is a very odd government than and so forth so so
ok now we had the pin the rain talked about escalation from conventional war and he talked about the deployment one of the things
he talks about which I think it's very sound is that this whole issue when you talk about the torrents it isn't just numbers there's a whole
the mansion at least and one is the the deployment posture ok and Pakistan has a very aggressive
posture because they feel inferior and conventional weapons to India and that they feel threatened by India
anyways ok and they've already been partitioned by India went when when the country broke up into the East
pipe Bangladesh and India so so there are there's a historic enmity between the tool which needs to be
I don't want it needs to be fixed and I have to say personally that I was very disappointed with a bomb
visit to India in many respects and I woke you know I look at the nuclear issue and one of the length it's
my lenses and I looked it isn't my solondz but it it's it's an important Focus for me and what I see is over
talks about the climate which is excellent then he's gets on this very poor policy of selling
nuclear nuclear energy nuclear reactors to India and
exempting India from the restrictions that used to be in place before bush before the bush administration
I've exempting India from the restrictions we placed on them because they violated than that the non proliferation treating and
weapons of course Pakistan did so also but the point is that we just aggravate the Indian Pakistan
tension as far as I can tell and I just read the New York Times
you know and listen to the BBC is far as I can tell the subject of
reading Pakistan of of diffusing the tension with Pakistan did not arise as far as I can tell this there was no pub
mention of it and I was very disappointed and they're trying to draw Obama's also trying to draw Hindi asthma
turn with China then with Pakistan this is this is a sort of three-way dance if you want to put it that way
and it's so it's more complicated than a bipolar interaction so three-way game where where China
is India India fragrance Pakistan in China ends up helping Pakistan with nuclear issues and
weapons that should say originally gave Pakistan the design for the bomb so this is something that
India wants to solve this issue of Pakistan's aggressive deployment they either have to do it by force
work because India husband deterred or they have to do it through the plumber saying and it always end
what does massage ok you can use for switch won't work while you can use the plumber see which has a chance which is difficult but as a
those are the two ways to solve the problem OK so how could a war start by ACS
between us and Russia ok well basically it's the most likely
is a malfunctioning of the early warning systems so
here's here's a chilling quote from vice president train when he was vice president
you read it for a minute ok
famous football he's talking about ok or black box
this is carried around wherever the president of the United States goes there's somebody a few doors down
24/7 who can say Mr President were under fire here's the button
OK now we're actually isn't the physical button but that doesn't matter that's that's
irrelevant it's the equivalent of a physical button ok it's a virtual button
ok so I just chilling and you ask what about the constitution what about consulting what about anything know because of the
10 minute to 13 minute lunchtime and the 10 minute warning time ok so
we have roughly 1000 missiles and so does Russia on hair trigger alert that ready to be fired at minutes note
the numbers probably closer to 900 but so are ok as I say mentioned
delivery times and decision times ok so the probability of an era is not negligible OK it is
is the complex physical emotional sister it's a human system
Seer I keep emphasizing this because there is fear of at very basic fear
and it said what what Hawks don't realise is that on each side is vulnerable to the other system UK
not stop the attack all you can do is retaliate another words it's
term or Revenge those of the two modes of operation this is chilling but that is the world Within
for 50 years literally people on think about it but it's pretty awful ok never
is that the Russian system is less robust so we are actually more vulnerable than they except that will fire if they do
sell and of course why does it go on its side does it cost the other does it
this is not logic this is not normal logic this is a tight circle
ok and so the latest that is surfaced in the last few years a cyber attack ok so
you ask how this can happen well a cyber attack just imagine somebody hacks into the system somebody who really want
the United States and Russia to destroy each other into the early war
system of either side just imagine that that's a nightmare
the only as I mentioned is that the safety of each side depends on the other side not launching ok and then
does the political question why do we persist Obama promise to do something about it when he came to office but he is
shut up is clearly given it up without explanation but it was one of his
of course the more attention that
the more scary this is it's last scary when there's no tension obviously it's it's feerick
and all the things that go with fear fear yeah I'm taking almost this Anonymous
distrust because the other side has the capability to destroy you and a second strike capability and
language of Cold War you know your house why it happens with all this strategic doktrin but a second strike capability and launch on
I physically identical with a First Strike posture so you can
I mean the other side tells you we love you but it's like having a guest over for dinner when the guests comes
Holden not just up not just the pistol high-powered rap
and says all yes we're Pals I'm here for dinner what kind of
it's a little naughty but maybe who am I to judge ok so
I want to talk a little bit about the non-proliferation treaty because I think it's one of the things that very important in
world is is that nuclear weapons don't spread you know the other countries at the cornerstone of that is the name proliferation 3D
and honestly I think in the nuclear power in the nuclear weapons States particularly United States
Russia v npt is not taken as seriously as it should be ok and I think it's very important the
BTS take and seriously for hair of what it does namely it says that people
not require nuclear weapons but it is not taken seriously because it obligates the 5 nuclear powers
watch nuclear Powers to give up their nuclear weapons and this is really the heart of abolition of nuclear weapon
built-in it's article 6 of the 9 proliferation treaty it obligates us to do it and so there's a tremendous 10
come back to this and a minute but the tension is between the nuclear between the countries who gave up aspirations for nuclear
saying to the nuclear weapons Powers ok you are obligated to do it but the nuclear
finns country say well we're doing it very gradually and responsibly and now I'll talk more about this
the nun nuclear weapons States want really a timetable OK so there's a lot of tension
I'll come to this in a minute ok so the cornerstones as I mention article 6 non-proliferation this armour
and I I write disarmament and in Blackall oh they're all extremely important I do this for
audience ok but the last point is that there's a 5 year review every
reviews there's a review the next one or been this may and they're going to be fireworks so I'll talk about that
OK so how effective is the npt ok so
four States outside the treaty is real India Pakistan North Korea there was this ECU
network from Pakistan which was shut down it's never been absolutely clear how much the Pakistan is state
involved or this was a private venture Scott Camp talk interestingly about how the
12 material that was sold by the AQ Khan network actually setback countries like a ran ok
when they're nuclear in the development of sent a few because what was sold was a technology which
was absolute and inefficient ok so it's very ironic
so a few countries have given up their bombs or excuse me and many countries have given up nuclear
men's programs I've listed some of them there are many nuclear capable countries that don't have weapons Japan as one of them of course
not surprisingly Canada are friends and Canada but even South Korea that feels very
buy North Korea has no but they are quite capable ok and
main point they want to make it that fewer countries have nuclear weapons that we're predicted in the early 60s like famous
Kennedy JFK set allowed that in a few years
team the 25 countries would have nuclear weapons and he was reflecting what the US intelligence agencies told him ok he was
making this up it wasn't just a speech he was reflecting what he was told ok and right now the political Norm
pronounce nuclear weapons and press the ones that have it'd the Disarm ok and that is a big Plus
and one that needs encouragement there are problems with the npt of course
life isn't perfect North Korea in my view is the most serious problem well Pakistan I haven't even written it down here but Bacchus
then India bigger problems because of the power possible pathways to war I already said that I didn't want to repeat it that's why it's not on the slow
what the whole issue with a ran there's no question that are rands in Richmond capabilities Excel
what I can do for power another words that very well suited for making weapons and not for power because they don't produce
offer power they don't produce enough enriched uranium for power needs but they do produce enough for weapons and that's been clear since the beginning
of the program despite what it said and so there's a
set a tremendous tension there I just want to talk a little bit about the I'm going the go see Asians that making a lot of
news now ok it's very important because we have an interim agreement and this is the
I'm 6 months it's really 4 months on the political level and 6 months on the technical level to reach a final agreement that's what was
I mean the first one was supposed to be 6 months in was extended well excuse me the first phase agreement was
6 months then it's been extended it's not on here but it's been extended for 6 more months so the deadline for the political agree
is is a in March and then in June I think it's the deadline the official deadline people ask
call but I don't know ok there are some technical issues the Iraq reactor can produce both plutonium but
simple solutions to that there are simple technical fixes and they ran has agreed to them as I understand so so that the amount of food
production from the Iraq reactor will be small ok
interim agreement that they're not supposed to be any additional sanctions that's very important in terms of the US congress because bills have circulate
demanding new sanctions but they're probably and obedience fortunately VR
for the really for parties involved feed the two official parties and then
add line is on both sides so this is a complex negotiation within each side it's complex ok I'm
count go into all of it and I think people know what's going on better on
on the American side but the real issue is far as I can see it in terms of a ran
ran wants is the have I think the ayatollah said something like 15000 centrifuge
the worst the Hard Light the most hide line people in the west said 0 ok
for example 0 is the only acceptable number of centrifuges so every and that's why he's campaigning so
but against it because he knows that there will be no deal with 0 centrifuges we already knows and advanced that
see why it is not possible so well they knew
probably 20000 advanced ones advanced ones not what they have the so-called pee ones ok ones that work
ok I can give you a car but you know I don't know what the top of my head but the supply what is it but she
is that the right pronunciation the bus near reactor which they don't need by the way because rush is going to supply the fuel but they don't why trust
of course for reasonable reasons I think but but anyway this whole business is so murky
my personal opinion ok it's hard to tell facts from motive in my opinion I don't think
can do it honestly all talk with you privately if you want but you know I don't think I can really evaluate it in a
that I would consider satisfactory I can tell you I can speculate that's what I can do but
the point is you know if there's a there's an old saying that that the ideal solution gets in the way of a good so
the good solution in my opinion is pretty much to continue the interim agreement that we have
why is that good because what people are not talking about in the United States is the best thing about
call negotiation namely that are ran keep saying they don't want to develop nuclear weapon
and there's a fat war that's excellent second what
and says that they want to be part of the npt they are in during and I'm going to use that word and doing
rigorous inspection regime that the iaea that's the international agency that in specs
international atomic energy agency they are in doing the most rigorous inspections that any country ever indoor
that was a two excellent think there are people on the ground all the time people say well they can break out
yes they can break out if they want to they will only they will only agree to all of this if it's in
self-interest nobody can expect anything more of them or us
so I think what we've got is the best possible solution that part that's feasible and if
they kick inspectors out in the side to go for a bond because they it was it close to impossible for them to do a
alarm with our picking The Inspectors out and well
what's faster then develop so many thousand more centrifuges and have that material and no news could leak out and all of that stuff their opposition
we found out about some of the sites I forget which one the one that's on the ground I forgot the name of it through through the centres in a
it always can happen the Soviet Union found out about the Manhattan Project in and most
what are talk about that for a minute because that's really important in 1940 a Soviet nuclear physicist
good morning flower of realise that all the publications about fishing in the United States England and France at start
and he went to Stalin and said the west is developing an atomic bomb based on what was
not appearing in the literature this is remarkable and it's a fact of course the Soviet Union
spies and they found out about the Manhattan Project through the spies but flare of just reading the physical review
OK this is a remarkable story which should not be ignored ok
I think we find out maybe slowly but you know and and if they really
the weapon is at the torrent they've got it show us that they have it like North Korea's there are all kinds of steps and 1
open isn't good enough I mean I wrote in our bed with Jim Walsh that that this whole Breakout time thing is too short you know the calculator
I said as soon as one weapon do I have an iPad Android is about this so all kinds of armour time you could argue forever I mean I mean
people who I would call hardliners to adjust agree with me cos I've published in our bed but but I'm just saying that you know
it's not so simple this is one I'm saying you know there are you but you have to decide which is right
this is a very complicated issues so anyway we have on
is Kirk Bill which is in the Senate it seems to be an old bands for a couple of months there's a Grace period people are working hard against it so
it's a very political thing in both countries I know it ok so
I saw it one together the discussion of two things are ran and the npt ok so I want to come
to the npt cos I am bettered the Iranian discussion in the npt discussion because it came up naturally that's why but so they come
there's the next thing that's going to happen and I'm just quoting here Stormy Weather predicted for the npt review
ok so I'm actually quoting an article from I Daryl Kimball of the arms control Association I didn't have time to make
Hoyts but in 2005 we had a disastrous and PT review that was under George Bush and
and the non-aligned countries are Egypt and Sweden and Denmark and Ireland and a whole bunch of countries
very angry particularly at the United States enjoyed wash it was a disastrous conference
10 Barack Obama had delivered his speech that he wanted to eliminate nuclear weapons the United States cut with was very welcome
and and there was a productive conference and they had 22 interrelated this on that steps I'm not even going to try to
the two major ones were that the nuclear weapons countries should give a timetable for
going to 0 time table and the second thing is that the should be they should convene
a conference in the Middle East looking towards a nuclear free zone in the Middle East
that's very delicate because getting is real to come getting around is real to the table at the same time is difficult the whole thing is
and not just the ram
they were in my personal
humble opinion Israel's interest a best served by a nuclear free zone in the Middle East if you are
hi Terry 0 weight in this cabinet ok I probably Gary know that
exaggeration of 0 way better than
so anyway I'm not even going to go through any of those but the following
under these steps have been disappointing they basically banana existent OK there's been basically no follow through
under 22 points and so that's one of the reasons everyone who who knows anything about this is predicting that there going to be a storm
ok especially for the nuclear weapon States so you can look forward to some interesting news in May
ok I'm kind of running out of time so basically Obama raise the lot of
with is Prague speech and 2009 talking about the possibility of an a nuclear Free World
of course he he had bright away it won't be rich quickly and the us as long as the weapons exist we're going to have our little toys to
ok so but anyway it was still the most why freight statement
since 1945 ok I mean so it was a breath of fresh air and
he won the Nobel Peace Prize ok probably premature early but who am I the quiver
ok so there are many arguments against nuclear weapons abolition I just going to pick
I'm ok because it it eliminates the torrents and to me that's the biggest argument
ok and it cannot be a cheat that's that's a different kinds of argument but in my opinion that's even stronger
it's it's x I wouldn't say cannot but my personal statement is it's unlikely ok but that doesn't mean it's not design
and that doesn't mean that academics and particular shouldn't talk about it that's one of the things that I have in mind and we should have a long range
academics that's one of my lodge ariz we can try to look at head and so that there are really 2 questions is 1
the desirable in view of all of the difficulties with it conceptual
and then is it achievable if it is desirable it's only you should only ask the second question if the answer to
does yes it's desirable ok and I can't go through all the arguments but the terms is
very interesting question I think I'm going to convene a little working group on it ok I've been thinking about it a lot for the last few
I'm ready to do some more serious research in this Arena ok but the point is that
it's never worked in the sense of Coke coercing others to do what you want which is the way it's offer news
and us diplomatic circles I don't know about Russian but but it certainly used in the US and
another problem with it as we heard about India and Pakistan it enables brinkmanship low-level
OK which is it it it another word introduces instabilities
I'm sad the Torrance isn't what it's cracked out to be ok because by having the weapons you also went
instabilities in the system especially if you have a gressive basing mechanisms is very important
Pakistan certainly is an example of that they have the turn in the but with a very aggressive pacing mode and threatening
so yes they've the term but is it stable how will it last are they they have delegated km
and in control of these local tactical weapons to come field commanders suppose you get a
field Commander wants the create mischief ok like you had somebody from Pakistan goes to Mum
rain and nnn shoots everyone in the hotel so for write off
the end of the Indian pilot few years before that so these are actions which don't introduce love or stability
countries ok putting it mildly ok and of course the torrents requires rationality which is
what supply view ok accidental use as which which we talked about and
cost of one work against Terrace they want a real Terrace who's a suicide bombadier want step
structure ok so boy that that's it bad mixture ok
and I think one of the points that people should not forget his deterrents requires a small number of weapon
well I would say 100 is overkill so it's less than 100 in my view I've been giving a number and I'll I'll keep giving it ok
I have 0 wait and Washington home basket that's what I think
so should we try to abolish nuclear weapons so really is it a good idea
so there's no risk free world what you have to do when you look at the arguments against ABBA
I've done my best to look at what I consider the serious ones they papers
quickly criticise going to 0 because it's risky but the question is that what they never
is talk about the relative risks another one's minimising risks how do you minimise the risk you're never gonna live
risks it's impossible so how do you make the right question is not to eliminate risks you have to ask
question you every Side Of The Snows that you and the right question here is minimization of risk that's the right butcher
how do you minimise risk do you stay on the present course or do you Friday do something more creative and this
one of the creative things ok and so the other thing is that
in and by itself is an important goal and if we want the npt the bee healthy with better be serious about it
how's the fireworks that I'm talking about OK and the nuclear weapons States had better take this into account you know
lock long-range how patients are the NPC PT States going to be it's very important
ok so yeah Obama has a mixed record he's inspired great hopes he's done the news
are treaty he's improved nucleus security he's tried he tried to engage Russian for it in furthest
actually that's that's a David slide those Atherton have dad the Russians effectively said no by the way so that
Obama you know convito negotiation as you know ok the nuclear
pastor review in my view is the very important decide deployment strategy was only slightly modified from Rowley a years
we still have too many warnings on you know hair trigger alert
respect the North Korea he talks about strategic patience which is head in the sand as far as I'm concerned ok I'm very critical
up the North Korean lack of Engagement there I'm very critical of Obama
yes they're asking again and we're ignoring that and I think it's dumb and the last thing again this has a lot to do with
is there modernizing nuclear weapons which again in the npt review is going to come up for tremendous predecessor
and it's good and in this day and age of budgetary restraints it should be criticise and in terms of strategic stability
be criticized so there's 0 to buzz words one is modernization and the other
maintenance so you have if you have nuclear weapons you have to maintain that they're usable and safe that's mate
without test that's important and the other is tomato night is the weapons making more accurate
and so forth and that really should not be done and the to get fused together and it's very hard to tell the detail because
it's it's all classified it's it it's the typical track of large bureaucracies
ok so anyway I find some reason for optimism the CT video I want to talk about that I just want to see if you
that is the what is it the I forgot what it stands for it's the worldwide monitoring system for Tess
play it's it's it's basically an international thing it's it's technically fabulous I mean I am really impressed
they have a seismic detectors they look for radioactivity in the air and they they look for
there's one more thing I'm sorry I'm blanking but anyway they detected a half kiloton blast
in North Korea an unannounced house gallatin stations triangular needed it they can tell it from earthquakes and and
conventional exploded the seismic what happens just briefly is that the seismix it's the rise time in the seismic 6
seafront from a chemical type explosion it's slower and the instruments have a fast enough response time so you could see the
you know overpressure it's it's quite wonderful and in several I think two out of the three of them
Korean test wall unannounced they detected radioactivity in the air I think one of the z9 isotopes front from the
which is long-lived ok and so finally and I outlined this public opinion does count
that's one of the things I take some comfort from there are many arms control organisations
I'm on the board of the council for a little war of the arms control Association it's is a wonderful organisation
you know in terms of giving out information and their journal is quite excellent ok and
peace action as a grass route to all other the good ok I think I've given the answers you know
is the present situation stable in my answer is with luck ok
a I gave my answer about abolition of nuclear weapons ok so anyway this
me to do and why when I just stop you can look at it I'm sure this is only a partial list of all
can be done some of it can't be done without Russia ok but some can
ok for example we could reduce more rapidly to the level
Russia has of launches end and the new start training Russia for example just as an example of Russia is below the limits imposed by the new
start reading those those limits going to affect when and something like 6 or 8 years or something I forget do you remember feel when they
the fact that we can accelerate those numbers you're not like typical arms control affect almost the day they are
so it's always too slow for arms control people you know it's always welcome but always too slow
but you know your take what you can get but again I want to just repeat one thing the new start reading
the big thing about the big success of the new start reading in my view which was not stress by the newspapers for the comment
is the fact that the inspections are going on and the inspections in my view on much more critical than the number
that's such overkill whether it's 1000 or 1500 weapons I mean again this 100 number is overkill so Khmer
it's almost a relevant except symbolically whether you have 1000 or 1500 the lowest thousand you get into
with how many does China have and how many Union are in South what they showed you so so thousands roughly that the critical point in which
war of the nuclear Powers nuclear weapons States I should say have two you know negotiate with each other not just the year
of course Rogers critical they're ok I'm going to stop and of course there's been a lot of questions but I'm happy for more of this
whatever yeah
another way of
well first of all we already have it and it's conventional smart Warfare
haven't talked about it United States cause it's Global Strike which were developing and that's a whole other dimension it's not a nuclear arms
but it was too much for me to get into that but yes you're asking a very good question and or conventional military
hours are incredible and we can do now in many respects with conventional weapons what we could have done only
nuclear weapons 20 years ago even 10 years ago and this Global Strike which is a way to
right across the world with Precision with conventional weapons with missiles with a Cruise missiles
and so forth is incredible and it's all sophisticated command-and-control stuff what's guidance yeah
well replace it in the sense that you don't have nuclear weapons
other people are just as scared as before so it's it's it's it's awesome an aggressive military posture and
in the day and age when we're really trying to replace that then we can no longer distinguish between
conventional arms control in nuclear arms control they will become merged I think as a subject as an intellectual subject as well as a practice
but I'm looking at head probably at least 10 years but in my view that they will come so you really asking a great question
yes disturbing the peace action will have plenty of work for plenty of
I'm afraid OK but can I say that I'm not happy about that but it's a fact
do you know who in India Pakistan process that natural body no
is it ok in India lock Here's what I know I don't know more than
you know what I think is true in India is that the Armed Forces are under civilian control
but but are in Pakistan that is not true so Pakistan is not what you would
a unitary state ok there is no single command the third I mean there is officially but de facto
we know that the Pakistani military is at least equal to the civilian branch but this
play whatever it is the security thing it seems to be quasi-independent I'm not sure
can see I mean my but one I'm afraid of us with this address I said it before but I just repeat it is this aggressive first
strike military nucleus posture of Pakistan is leading
delegation of authority to lower levels where there's a great danger of a road Commander so I see Pakistan
place with the most danger of a rogue Commander ok and I think I'm not the only one who thinks this
by the way roughly to 150
200 it's more than 100 now ok they're making more all the time they make
fast as they can as far as we can tell OK no India seems to be more relaxed
loud it both in terms of their aggressive-passive they say they won't fire first in the has a much more reasonable stated policy of use
they they're much more laid-back they they say they won't use them first they
say the Pakistan is a just going much much too far but on the Indian side the problem that I
is there not trying for the political solution another words they're past their deployment posture is more sensible
but they're focused on China Sea so but they are not India my big criticism of India is
I'm not solving the problem ok man I come back to that right
the Bing much too slow in in trying to heal problems like Cashmere and other
points in the relationship ok I mean they're not gonna disappear overnight but they could they could do things
ok and I can point the some literature but I'm I'm not a real expert by the way they're not being the United States of not being even-handed
anatom mistake that's a basic American mistake so you know
critical since the beginning I'm not the only one you know on this basis but I think the predictable is happening
just wondering Pakistan into a more frenzied state of the value of nuclear weapons development ok it's on for
but we're doing something we don't want to see happen ok we deployment one 1 hour and and
encourage it in directly on the other so it's a contradictory policy unfortunate
they should no better but they have their the learning commercial interest override
you know that this tug of war write that Tasmania
so
underbrush somehow right it's
well we also make military hardware sales turn to India which is increasing that was all
it was one of the other things from the Obama visit the sale of conventional military equipment 2nd is going up
ok for the first time in a long time so that was a big success I guess yes
yes I forgot to mention that ok you reminded me
call Cathy ok thank you thank you for coming