ok good morning everybody the we're going to continue
today developing a model of again this is called the equivalent Circuit model in it was developed by Alan Hart
Huxley in the 40s and 50s give a brief recap of what we've covered in the last couple
so weapon analysing a n or an with an imagining a an experiment in which we have a nor on in a dish
Northwest extracellular solution which is a salt solution we have a electrode in the cell that's measuring the voltage difference between
inside in the outside of the salsa we have the electrode connected to an amplifier a different lamprophyre and a wire in the bath connected to the other side
and we have a current source which are injects current into the cell and we imagine that as the experimenter we have our
a knob that we can adjust the amount of current that's been injected into the south we describe the ne on basically as a capacitor because it
it's 2 conductors separated by an insulator so we have a conductor one conductor inside the cell which is the conductive intracellular salts
another conductor outside the south which is the conductive extracellular solution and those two conductors are separated by an insulator which is a fast forward
down the equivalent Circuit for this which for this situation right here it has a voltage measure
device that represents the Membrane potential as the difference between the intracellular voltage and the extracellular bolted voltage we have
sorry is here and we've represented owner on so far as a capacitor then introduce the idea of
channels are conductances of pores in the Membrane that allow ions to pass through the Membrane through this little pores and we describe the eyes
we talked about the idea that there are many different kinds of ions ion channels that have different interesting prop
so with an extended our analysis of an Iran in the dish to include these ion channels
down by putting by representing ion channels as a resistance that connects the intracellular space in the extracellular space this
sister is in parallel with our capacitor and we represented the current going through that resistance which we called the leak resistance art
we represented the current as a leak current Isa Bell are noted that we were going
are all this week resistance using Ohm's law so we wrote down that current that leak current as the Membrane potential v device
by the leak resistance this is just Onslow and we also rewrote are the quality one over R1 over the
resistance as the leak conductance so delete current is just delete conductance time's the Membrane potential
also introduced the idea of an IV curve which plots the amount of current flowing through this through our leak conductance
as a function of the Membrane potential is v and for the case of a resistor for the case for modelling
Elite conductance with Ohm's law that the current as a function of voltage is a straight line going through the origin whose slope is just
we conducted questions about that ok then we derive the simply quote
for how The Membrane potential evolves over time as a function of the injected current and we did that using kirkovski
I would says that the sum of all the currents into a node has two equal the sum of currents out of a node or node here means a wire
tell the some of these currencies = 0 is a minus sign here because this current the electrode injected current as
time does positive going into the cell and these currents are to find a positive when they go out of the south substituted for
current the expression from Onslow so into this part of the equation here this term we substitute VM over arse about
can I apologise for the slight inconsistency in notation here sometimes I'm using VM and sometimes I'm using v altrider fix that
boat VR miss the same as v and in what you've seen so far and we also have an expression here for
the capacitive current capacity capacity of current through this capacitor is just CDT the we put those two expressions those
substitutions and we have this expression are that relates the voltage in the cell to the injected current weary wrote this a little bit by multiplying
by the leak resistance and we are rewrote this again making a couple substitutions we use
how are in place of RC so that becomes a time constant and the infinity is this expression on the right are leak
the injected current so the equation that we now have the differential equation that we now have for the dependence of the Membrane potential on injected current looks like
we pass powder VT is equal to the infinity when we inject current into the cell or changing the infinity
and then the voltage evolves as described by this different workwear Asian
alright so we're going to plot a bunch of things the infinity and the voltage in the
as we interact the pulse of currents are we start out with injected current equal to 0 with Step Up 2 I not hold a car
injector current I not for some period of time and then reset the current back to 0 so what does the infinity do as a function of time
anybody remember it does the same thing but
pied by our saval very good ok and what does what does the Membrane potential do so let's start the Membrane potential is 0
starting here what does the Membrane potential do as a function of what's your name
yes there's a 0 good it what's the what
say how do we say exponentially toward the infinity very good so it relaxes exponentially toward the infinity which is here and then what happens
and it does it relaxes with a time constant of RC and what that means is that the time it takes for
the one over ear bits original distance from the infinity is is given by towel
and you can solve this differential equation that was on the previous slide for periods worthy inject
is constant where the infinity is constant and what you can see is that the voltage difference from the current v Infinity relaxes
sleep 20 boats out at the initial voltage minus the infinity and you multiply that difference times and
the Dickies 20 and so the voltage difference between the voltage and the Infinity the game
we are we then introduced the idea that Lauren's have batteries where do the batteries of Anna Ron come from anybody remember Stacey I Remember You
the batteries of an Iran come from that's what the battery producers
the battery producers of voltage difference but by physically what causes that voltage different
ion selective pours good that's one component and there's another important component somewhere else want to answer but excellent so we
components ion concentration gradients and ion selective pours so basically if you have a high concentration of
ask him inside the cell when you open up a potassium selective ion channel the potassium ions diffuse out of the cell
an excess of negative charges inside the cell that causes the voltage inside the cell to go down until
there is a sufficient voltage gradient that the drift of potassium ions back into the cell driven by the voltage gradient is equal to the diffusion
read of ions out of the cell produced by the protected by the concentration gradient OK at equilibrium
at the equilibrium potential there is a particular voltage at which there's no net current into potassium current into or out of the cell
ok and that's what we mean by equilibrium potential otherwise known as the nernst potential last time we derive the nurse potential using the ball
equation we are the boltzmann equation gives us the ratio of the probability of finding an iron inside or outside of the South
and that's equal to eat to the minus energy difference of an ion inside and outside of the cells / Katie the energy difference is given by the
how much time is the voltage difference to charge of the ion that were considering x the voltage difference so we took the log of both sides of four VN -
and we found that the voltage difference at equilibrium this is at thermal equilibrium that's what the boltzmann equation tells us at thermal equilibrium what's the ratio
abilities at thermal equilibrium and the voltage difference is 25 ml bolts x the log the natural log of the concentration of
freshens and that's ok is the if you put in the the the potassium concentrations here that give
equilibrium potential for potassium or the north potential for potassium so so
Iran's here on earth are kinda like it's on that caesium irons on the alien planet potassium potassium
sensation inside of a cell is around 400 mm and I think this is for squid giant axon she's a little bit earlier but
yes guy so so if
about the probability of finding a potassium ion inside of a cell and finding a potassium ion outside
the ratio of probabilities is going to be proportional to the ratio of concentrations does that make sense
ok so given these concentrations a high concentration of positive potassium ions inside the cell a low
outside the cell we can take the ratio of those concentrations take the natural log of that that's about 3 log units
the sign is negative because this is this ratio is smaller than 1 so the equilibrium potential for potassium that's about 25
waltz Katie of acute for a monovalent is $25 volts so that nerds potential
5 mil millivolts x -3 so that equilibrium potential is about -75 in 10
ok so let's now look at a different iron sodium so sodium has a very low
inside a cell compared to outside that ratio is about a factor of 10 but not
father of 10 is about to log units right so what's the equilibrium potential for sodium
yep + 4 - so it's
it's about to login it's x 25 North Ryde so it's plus plus 50 years so how about chloride so this is
chloride is a negative ion it has a high concentration outside the cell and a low concentration inside the cell so when when we open up a chloride Chan
what happens to the chloride ions which way do they go into the cellar out of the song
are there negative so what is that going to do to the voltage inside the cell or negative good
turn the ratio of concentrations here is about 10 so like of 10 it's 2ish so what's that
about -50 exactly if you plug in the actual numbers it's -60 great
here's an interesting one calcium-calcium is a captain in extremely low concentration inside of cells because it's use
signalling molecule when calcium comes into a cell it actually does things important so the so the cell buffers calcium it it's a quest
calcium into the endoplasmic reticulum and keeps the concentration in the cytoplasm very low the concentration outside the cell is about to the ratio
is a pretty big number so if you are ok why is why is the
coffee machine hair Katie over Q why is that 12 mm bolts here instead of 25
excellent so it's Katie over 2 times the electron charge pay so that's $12 very good and so the equilibrium potential for calcium
is very positive great any questions about that so these are
most important ions that we have to think about in terms of ionic conductances across across the Membrane
question ok so let's go back to our Lauren in the dish and we're going to
consider on that has a a potassium conductance and a high potassium concentration inside the cell remember we can write down that the
magnitude of that conductances ji-sub Kay and now we're going to do an experiment or going to measure the voltage in our sell the Steady State
as a function of the amount of current that is either being injected or passing through the Membrane ok it's steady-state those two things are the same
sorry going to plot the potassium current through the Membrane as a function of the voltage of the South
so let's say that we inject 0 current what's the Steady State voltage in the cell going to be
just went through the
I have to call ok I have a volunteer about you
are white white 25 ml bolts and with will assume the channels open
so what is the answer is that if you inject 0 current the the voltage is going to be the north potential
ask him and dad is correct but what is the actual number it's going to be around -75
Sophie inject 0 current voltage of an Iran is going to be around UK or -75 novels
let's start injecting current into the cell until the voltage gets to 0 K now
going to be injecting positive current into the shopping - what do we have to do injector positive or negative current to make the voltage get up to 0
positive right because the voltage inside is negative so we need to inject positive charges and how much current do we need to inject
the conductance SG how much current to interact
v v is the voltage inside of a cell so you're getting there you're really close what's the answer
hey x g ok so we're going to end the current into herself until the voltage gets to 0 and if we inject different amounts of current into the cell
and measure what the voltage is we get kind of a straight line for potassium
if you hold the voltage positive above the equilibrium potential potassium ions are going to flow out through the member
is that clear let's hold the let's hold the voltage at 0 which way are ions flowing so the ions are going to be
out hold the voltage at EK what happens to the potassium current
because you're now it's enormous potential and if you hold the voltage below that the inside of the
is now a negative relative to the nearest potential and currents gonna flow in the notice that the current actually were vs sign around EK
ok and so sometimes this voltage is called the reversal potential ok so you're here me sometimes referred to the reversal potential and that
what's the same as the Norris potential or the equilibrium potential ok so the equation for something
like this a straight line That's offset from zero is Justice so this expression right here is going to be our basic model for Howie
the current through an iron as a function of the voltage of the Membrane so current the potassium current is just the potassium conductance
* the difference of the Membrane potential from the river so potential ok so i k it was GK x
minor CK we also have a circuit a little simple equivalent Circuit that describes this relation and this
it looks like we have a what we're going to do to discussed include the effects of this
iron this iron specific conductance in the presence of a concentration gradient is to take our conductor
this to hear a conductance and put it in series with a battery so that's the basic Circuit element that describes this kind of ivy
why is that ok so let's break this down a little bit basically what we're going to do is we're going to equate this membrane potential difference
clean the inside in the outside of the cell is potential difference to the sum of the voltage drops across these two elements is it 1
bolts the same as the battery in here what is it
exactly so the voltage drop across this battery is EK what's the voltage drop across this resistor this potassium conductance
what is it depend on what is the current is 0 what's the voltage drop across a resistor whose current is 0
Onslow rate what is it at arbitrary current what's the voltage drop across resistor as a
good can somebody tell me what it is in terms of the quantities that we have looking for a
severe crosshair ok so VM the Membrane potential has two just equal the sum of those two voltage
severe me cos EK plus IKEA Ridge EK and now it's just saw this for ok
this little Circuit element describes our the conductance that's the equation that goes with it question
alright what's push on this quantity right here by the way V - EK is called the driving
FV is equal to EK than the driving potential is 0 and there's no cracked
the current through the channel is proportional to the driving potential
alright let's let's just so there is our new circuit diagram for our cell that's a capacitor who's
rain has little leaks in it where there is a ion-specific permeability of the poor and iron
fresh ingredients to produce a battery Circuit you can see that we're getting off Lee close now to the hole
equivalent Circuit model that hodgkin-huxley wrote down ok so let's let's just flat out this equation here
what is Isa k k is just hopefully my CK very good
that the resistance RK is just one over GK and towel again is RK x c so let's massage that's a little bit more
we're going to write this down as v + DVD t = EK +
what is that that is very good
who won CY that's the infinity because if you set divinity equal to 0
virsa call to ik arcade Eyecare Plus rkip if you inject a constant current
at Steady State DVD take 40 you can see that the injected current is just equal to the potassium current leaking out through the
that all makes great sense so that's the infinity the voltage is just the difference equation is v Plus
the infinity exactly the same equation we had before so you know that every moment v is going to be doing what
everybody together relaxing toward the infinity right ok where that's our
Infinity the we're going to play the Rihanna do the same experiment again here's our pulse of injected Kurt v Infinity is now starting at
jumps up to EK plus rki not and it goes back down and voltage of the cell is relaxing toward the in
adding that just shifted
this voltage Trace down from 0 number this before this was sitting at 0 and now it's sitting at -75 ml bolts
any questions
alright so we're going to come back in a minute
finished washing out this model
where are we make those conductances depend on time as a way of describing the spikes that in Iran produces
but before we do that we're going to talk about it a much simpler model of how how was spiking around behave basically what word
still as we're going to instead of write down a biophysical model of action potentials which is where we're heading
we're just going to ask some simple questions about our spiking around behaves notice that action
a really important right that there are the way Normans communicate with other Norris they send a signal down your axon to listen or transmitter another na runs but
what's the time in Iran is not spiking what is it doing
well could be another thoughts certainly sometimes it could be
great it's well and and how did you do that
it's part of it but yes integrating is inputs
and it integrates is important and eventually it's bikes ok so so we're going to develop a model or look at a model now
cob not surprisingly integrate-and-fire ok that captures exactly that idea that are more on spends most of
I'm integrating it's input making a decision about when the Spike and then spiking over again
other a crucial piece of this is that for most types of Nerang the spikes are really all the same
the spike waveform don't carry extra information Beyond the fact that there's a spike we're going to treat our spikes as Delta functions just disco
events at single time and the spikes are going to occur when the voltage in the Run
which is a particular membrane potential called this bike threshold no that's a reasonable approximation for many Lawrence it's not absolute
Facebook Medina on spike when the Northern reaches of particular voltage threshold and that's captured in this model called
Dr integrate-and-fire know what we're going to do if we're going to take our hodgkin-huxley model and we're going to replace this
sodium and potassium conductance is that actually generate the spike work in a replace that with a very simplified model of a spike generator look like
basically the idea is that the south gets input from either an electrode or from a
chicken pot and it integrates that import until it reaches a voltage called the threshold and once it reaches
baffled we simply reset the voltage back down to so about you called the reset ok and then we just
do you want to we can test draw a line at a time and that's the spike what really happens to the voltage
set once the voltage hits be threshold begets reset back down to any questions
that kind of behaviour is not it's fairly common or on so there's
example of does the voltage in a cell in motor cortex of the Songbird in this is from a paper from Rich movies lab back in the back in 9
2 and you can see that if you inject current the voltage in the cell ramps up until it hits a threshold voltage it makes a spike which is very narrow in time but then
multifaceted down to a lower voltage just repeats over and over again
what we're going to do is work going to calculate the rate at which another on fires as a function of how much
gets injected into the see how much import a cell cats start by considering the case where the
I has no leaks and it's Moreno conductances alright so let's plot voltage as a function of time so this is voltage as a function of time when we
act a step of current into the song so what's going to happen and the current turns on
some fresh
excellent bike that
then what's going to happen
excellent like that and then what's going to happen
current into our cell in our cell is going to generate bikes action potentials at regular intervals
and the interval between those spikes is going to be controlled by how long it takes that passador to charge up from the reset
to the threshold so we can actually just very simply calculate the firing rate of this Laurent as a function of how much current we injector
so the firing rate is just one over that interval between the spikes
so now what do we do gas what the next step is
how do we figure out how long it takes we know this distance
some third grade word problem here come on somebody help me out across the river your paddling you know one that can
the river is 10 metres across
how about Racer
wait shirt what do you think it's not worth trying to calculate
time it takes for the voltage to go from here to here
what would it depend on
what what are you doing
but what are you cut your calculating white and you're using what about this line
welp exactly great so if we knew the slope of this line we can calculate how long it takes to go from here to here
great let's do that so we have this equation CD DVD was Isa me what's the slope of this line
it's just DVD tea good so
Stevie t that's Delta v over delta t delta v is just this voltage difference right and delta T is what we're trying to calculate
are we just solved which is plug this into here and we just saw for one over delta T and that's just seed out
times the injected current that's probably what you were saying write any questions about that
ok so let's look at what that looks like the firing rate is proportional to the Detectives
because 2080 injected current the voltage is constant and the Nerang never fire but if we inject a tiny bit of current the vault
slowly ramp up and it will eventually hit the threshold and then reset the vault the fire rate is proportional to the injected current Club one over
Delta v if the capacitor is much bigger what happens to the foreign rate close down because as you were
current the voltage increases more slowly because the capacitance is bigger right now
let's add our our a leak conductance back in
Stockton we're going to think of it as a potassium conductance ok so I'm gonna call Angelique because I'm going to use something
at leader in the hodgkin-huxley model but you should think about it just as a potassium conduct alright so what
let's go to work at a voltage as a function of time during our injected current let's say that we start at the reset
our our voltage of the reset
so let's start it now what happened yes
the voltage starts here cos there's 0 injected current as soon as you inject current the infinity
it's up to hear would say the voltage relaxes exponentially toward the infinity until it hits the threshold very good
then what happened somebody else but you in the grey shirt
Sophie know the answer raise your hand will go much faster ok so at this point it will jump back down
great and then why else if you know the answer is your hand just ok let's just do an exercise
raise your hand everybody who knows your hand up high ok now one of you say it
everybody sad music to my ears ok it relaxes exponentially back to the in
ok and tell it's threshold and it comes back ok keeps no what happens here the car
turns off what happens that question it out
back to why is it
VE reset snow cone injected battery Infinity so that's why it relaxes back to to Ely
any question it's pretty simple right ok so it's pretty simple and we can
derive the expression now for this delta-t and therefore we can drive the equation for the firing rate as a function of injected it's a little more complicated
turn the other one I'm going to go through it in a little bit less detailed ok because the answer turns out to actually be pretty simple
so we're going to calculate the phone rate which is just one over this delta-t here before we actually get into the math what happens if the infinity is die
I know the answer to that question is your hands
I want spike right good ok so the infinity actually has to be above the threshold in order for that
spike that make sense ok so something is different already because because before we found it currently in Jack
the soul would eventually spike but now what we see as when we have A-League the v-infinity actually has to be above the threshold and so that means there is going to be so
shuffle current below which the Nerang wants bike that's pretty cool we can see that right away so I just I just define one
decode the rear base ok and that is that current at which the Nerang begins to spike so if we start our soul
at the reset because I said just spiked it relaxes exponentially toward me infinity but let's say that the infinity is right at 3
you can see that the time to reach the threshold is actually very long it if the infinity is equal to the threshold it will never actually reach it even
Infinity is equal to view threshold the phone Raiders zero because if you inject just a tiny bit more current now it'll be in the spike right
we can calculate the injector current required to reach threshold that's called the real base we just set v-infinity equal to the threshold right
and we use our equation for that's the infinity and we just said it equal the threshold now we just drive the injected can't we just saw
I see that's the injected current required to make the infinity reach the threshold and you can see that it's just Julie
time to be threshold - all that I threshold
what's the firing rate of this Lauren is 04 low current as you inject more current the infinity increases but
I still can't reach the threshold until you inject an amount of current such that the infinity reaches be threshold and then it begins to
and the phone rate increases rapidly have that
I've having a threshold current above which you have to below which the someone's bike
so now that's actually derive this equation for this
as a function of injected current going to do that and we're going to calculate the amount of time before the cell spikes
so we're gonna start the voltage at be reset we know that at some injected current above threshold the cell relaxes exponentially to the infinity and
can you calculate how long it takes equal to threshold so you know that that's an exponential right in fact we wrote down the solution to that exponential a bunch of times
the difference from v to be Infinity decreases exponentially but we know a bunch of these values right we know where we know that we're calculating these
wentao = sorry 20 = delta T at we know the initial voltage that's be reset
we know the voltage at time delta T and has just equal to the threshold so we can just substitute those quantities into this equation
now we have the pub minus the infinity equals we reset - be infinity x eater the - delta T over town that make sense
I just did you just calculating this time that it takes the Nerang to relax exponentially from the reset to be threshold
we know all these quantities so we just stick them into this equation and what are we sell for
so we take the natural log of while we divide through by the the reset - the infinity take the natural log
Alpha delta T so delta T = minor style natural log the infinity minus threshold over the infinity minus be reset
it's kind of messy I don't know the shape of that doesn't really lip to my mind ok so we're going to
is actually just simplify this expression in a limit in the limit that the in
is lard what what happens here when the injected Crown is large what what gets big me in
get back when you inject a lot of current the infinity is very high and went the infinity is really big this is
action approach is white and what is the log of 1
expression this expression approaches one and this expression the log of that approach is 0 ok so we can do is do a linear
summation of this work in the limited the infinity is much bigger than be reset R&B
we're going to use the approximation that log of 1 + Alpha is just Alpha
approaches one you can write it is 1 + Alpha call thing there are approximately 2 Alpha ok and when you do that and you solve for the phone
what you find is that the firing rate is just one over see Delta v times the injected current minus the threshold Perth
show current is just the rear base that we calculated before what does that look like but what is the first of all this is I can't
simplified this abet what is the fire rate when the current is below a threshold and then if it's a bar
hi thresholds for this expression that I wrote right here is true only injected current greater than a threshold 0 below that so now what is this look like
pirate is 0 until you hit threshold and then what
this equation is linearly in the injected current are at the slope is actually exactly the same as it was for the case where there was no
Mick ok so the phone rate is 0 once you hit the threshold the the final rate of
increases approximately linearly ok for large currents and if you look down here what you see is that
the current actually the actual solution is that the phone Ray jumps up at threshold and then tracks along the linear approximation
that the dash line there is the actual solution that the solid line is that the new approximate ok and that right there it is really
a very good model for a lot of Nora sort of saturated a little bit though
define that kind of flattens out a little bit as you go to very high farm rates but that's a pretty good approximation yes
heavy is the is the difference from v reset to v threshold
the model was another question here
anything else that's the integrated that's probably the most
commonly used model of Lawrence in neuroscience simple
I should say that's the most commonly used model of spiking mirror actually taken around that behave like this
assemble them into complex networks and study how network interactions occur with a spiking model and this
this model captures most of the interesting important behaviour of of spiking neurones
Russian Daniel Miller questions
ok alright let's come back to our
Huxley model equivalent Circuit so we just described was a model Nerang in which will replace these
potassium conductance is that actually produced his action potentials with a very simple spike generator but now we're going to do is we're going to come
to our model and we're going to flush out the biophysical details that allow these to conductances her to producer
potential fact most most of the time when we model network
simplify the spike generator to something like a integrate-and-fire spike generator Park than hodgkin-huxley develop
describing time-dependent and voltage-dependent conductance is so powerful and commonly used
describe conductance is that it's really worth understanding that that mathematical description that physical description of
ionic conductance is in highly dependent voltage and type
sing we do if we noticed that in the hodgkin-huxley model we have three conductances we have conductance which is
very much like the leak conductance that we just used in the integrated fire model ok it has a reversal potential of around minor
50 mil bolts and it's just always on it's just a constant conductance we have this to other conductances are sodium candle
potassium conductance that are both time-dependent and voltage-dependent each one of those conductances has a current affair
the weather currents flowing through ion channel the total membrane is just the sum of all of those currents that's just
ionic membrane current it's just the sum of contributions from sodium channels potassium channels and
equation for a hodgkin-huxley model using kirkus current like the sum of all the
into these no testicles zero so the Membrane ionic current plus the capacitive current equals the injected electric car
each one of these conductances each one of these currents can be written down in the same form that we developed
for potassium conductance ok it's just a sorry for the potassium current so the sodium current is just a c
skin conductance x what what is that driving potential the driving potential for sodium but
the saw doctors now is voltage and time-dependent and it's that voltage and time-dependent that gives sodium can soda
channel properties that they need to generate action potential it's just an Alex to what we already did before
super casting conductor ok and potassium current it's just GK times to driving potential for potassium and the potassium
Arkansas voltage and time-dependent 75 DNA is plus 55 conductance
delete current rather is just the leak conductance time's the driving potential for the leak current the difference is that in this model
now the Lee conductances just constant is no time to Pennant it's always there and it's voltage are any questions but
the name of the game here in understanding how this thing works is to figure out
where this time dependence and voltage-dependent comes from
you're very close
equilibrium potential is always very close to -75 in Sumner aren't it might be as low as -95 but it
in that range the sodium reversal potential is so with you know + 58
well it's highly consistent across mammal and the numbers for squid are pretty close to the
I think these are the numbers for squid came from that come from how to get huxleys
ok now how do these things generate
action potential just in principle how do you think about conductances like this generator
action potential here 020
mean like variable or adjustable so we can imagine that we have a knob a hand on the knob and let's just turn off both down to 0 so what
the voltage in the sound going to be what is the sound
just not saying it
so roughly the it's it's closer it's -
OK good so if these conductances are 0 then the cell is going to be sitting at the of this battery
0.30 state 0 current the voltage drop across here is 0 cos there's 0 current and saw the inside of the cell at better be sitting at
voltage of flat battery which is -50 what happens if we suddenly turn on a conductance
turn by turn on a conductance we make the resistance really small or we make the conductance really big right so what are we doing let's turn that conductor
as much as possible which means resetting that resistor 20 if this resistance is 0
then the voltage drop across that the voltage inside has to just be
it has to be set to that the voltage of that battery that makes it
if we have no conductance here then the inside the cell wall relaxed toward
but if we now turn on this conductance we set that resistor 20 voltage
jump up Baltic that resistor back up to some big value what's the voltage gonna do
arcs back to us about this nice simulation of what happened so here is what is going to happen these conductances are going to
0 we're going to awake these conductances are going to start at zero and then we're going to make this
small 0 but small or big and we're going to make that resistor small
so the conductances are going to be parted along the bottom and the voltage of the cell is going to be parted as a function of time
add the green and red show the reversal potentials for the sodium and potassium
where are the sodium conductance just got turned on in what happened the voltage of the South
turn on the potassium conductance and we turn off the sodium conductance and the voltage gets dragged down
and when we turn off the potassium conductance the voltage relaxes back up to
are just knobs that allow the cell to control is vaulted
weight of planet you can control the voltage of the Sower just by setting those
our use of those resistors if you make this resistor really small and that resistor big the voltage jumps up toward DNA
why is that because you're connecting the inside of the cell to that battery turn that off and then turn on this setting that
Mr to be very small now you're connecting the inside yourself to this battery which is negative don't here you can just control of the Sower up and
just by twiddling these knobs ok to think about it is this if this resistor is big
Dan if you set that resistor to be really small than this the voltage here dominus
over the time scale of any process that were considering hear the ionic concentration
inside the sign outside of the salt don't change that make sense
so you said both of these 20
the conductance is really high that means setting the resistor is really small that that's a great question what happens
that's exactly right if you said both of these if you turn on both of these conductances then the voltage goes somewhere in the middle and the voltage that it
what's 2 is actually you have to potential that we calculated is
is calculated only for the case where you have one iron if you want to calculate the equilibrium potential when you have multiple pores open
then you have to use you have to use a different method of calculating actually calculate the currents flowing and it's one of those channels
and based on the permeabilities of the channels and you get a different expression are called the Goldman Hodgkin
equation ok but the bottom line is if you open up both of those princess it's somewhere in the middle and if you want to get the exact right answers
is the jet courier quote
almost we're not quite there yet we're going to get there but you can see what happens here is that
these conductances are actually voltage-dependent so for example the sodium conductance turns on at higher voltages when this
Stockton starts getting bigger what happens to the voltage in the cell it's going up right but if this is voltage-dependent and it turns on at higher voltage
what happens to the conductance when the voltage gets a little bit bigger what happens to the conductive to the voltage makes it go up
faster this runaway process where where the boat were the disc inductance turns on very quickly in the voltage jump start
ok that's the essence of the action potential ok but the essential picture that I wanted you to get from this from this slide
these are just knobs and when you turn the knobs you can change the vote that controls the voltage in the cell
which one of these is causing the cell to be dragged toward it's reversal potential
inductance is big this conductances big that voltage in the south-west drag tour DNA
voltage in the cell gets dragged 40K next time we're going to go through
the are the process for a describe the process to drive the voltage dependence of
I am check the sodium and potassium ion channels to derive the voltage dependent and the time dependence that explains how you get this action potential
so that's next Tuesday