the phone can't answer is provided under a Creative Commons licence your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality
national resources for free to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of mit courses visit MIT opencourseware at ocw
am i t daddy you what I'm going to be talking about some of the fundamental work that has been done trying to understand neural basis
4 ft memory and spatial perception and cognition that come from
from behavioral and electrophysiological studies in the brain system that shown here at the hippocampus and as I was mentioned before we start
this year's Nobel Prize was given to Johnny O'Keefe who discovered the properties of individual neurones in the hippocampus by applying
these methods for recording the discharge of single cells by putting a why is under the brain so-called extracellular recording to put in a wire the tip
electrode can record electrical discharge cells you measure the discharge of cells animals move around in space and you tried it
try to figure out what this part of the brain does now where the observation part of science comes in this case is interesting because it relates to another aspect
neuroscience and that is the relationship between the neurobiology and behaviour and this is an
large by profession as studying the brain systems in the context in which they actually the you're the evolved and
were used in so that could apply to the use of song as a as a mechanism of communication and birds that can come
waiting for finding pre in the dark when it comes to look all the good localisation owls in the case of Rodents
O'Keefe appreciated the fact that they have a campus in Ruins really has a primary role in space
that animals that have damaged hippocampus have problems with special navigation and the hippocampus had been studied up to that point using animals that were
head fixed so you take when you take a little rat you fix her the reason for fixing it's head is for convenience largely so that when you placed his electorate
brain doesn't like you can keep good recordings so you need to have any to keep the preparation fixed so you fix animals head then you figure out ways to hack
how to study the system given the constraints of the methodology and that involve largely for Johnny O'Keefe
using methods of classical conditioning so familiar with basic learning theory and you know how do we learn how to do things was
sickly together stingless response associations you see something you do something you got water for doing that you're more likely do the
basic pavlovian conditioning a real value of food KU so save the food answer that was the thinking that all
cognition can be built up from basic stimulus-response Association but there was this movement around the time that I'll keep was doing this work that the proposed
that that was insufficient that's simple be here or simple stimulus response alone is insufficient that there was some kind of internal foundation upon which
was I was applied and this was the social cognitive theory of learning and memory and it campus
deposit to be the side of one property of this cognitive learning as applied to space and the observation was actually
if you take a rat does he want to wear something that is it you want for the renter I know what you know associated associate
do you want to train it to go over and the oppressor lever for food you want to learn something and you do this in an environment that put in a box
put it in outbox I see the day before you just let it was around there's nothing it's just explore space and take it out and now we take to rise one that's been in the box before and one of the
what the weather's been in the box before will learn faster than the end was not in the box as he why would why we just passed exposure that box enhance
learning and this was leaving learning the am I had learn something that it could then apply to this new learning even though it
instruct it nothing it wasn't awarded for do anything it just explore answer this idea that there was some sort of legal capacity to enhance learning
was motivated the study of the hippocampus in the context of Nan head fixed
recording and so keeps real and side effect of paper that was cited for for the Nobel Prize was the paper in which he first recorded from
just take me and was able to talk download beers and just let it run around on a table top just like this act as a table at university College
but the size where the trash just kind of wanted around he made after patients or he was a cell that fires when the animal goes over the left-hand side
descriptive but the key inside was to study the hippocampus when rats are doing what rats normally do exploring space OC
The Logical approach and what he discovered was that sells in the hippocampus and the cross-section
here to the medial temporal lobes it's the name of the campus comes from the Greek receipt Corso and humans it so looks like a seahorse
the region's here the terminology ca this there these different fields of hippocampus
because it looks like a round Lawrence you think about the little round Torrens Road here put them in temple loves you moving in the hippocampus it's just like this
make a cross section slice do that this is the circuit so information comes in from across the brain converges
the primary input to the hippocampus that's called the enteral cortex which is with the other the other Nobel Prize
what did the the husband and wife team that had identified discover and identify the properties of cells in the NRL
this awful red cells that seem to carry information about actual seem like cartesian like spatial information
stuff comes in from the brain converges in the NRL cortex and then goes around the loop from these these three primary subfields the dentate gyrus
sequel Money3 ca1 super coming back on again so he goes to The Sloop class with the
synaptic loop once and then pca3 c01 and the back out recordings in this part of the hip
reveal the properties were time which I mentioned that is the cells respond to locations in space but prior to that
there's like a physiological work in rodents human or a psychological work in particular the seminal case of the patient hm
study for many decades before we just recently passed away and Elias and as he is as his Nowra
I'm so recently revealed to be a patient who
Thunder gone bilateral reception cut out parts of the hippocampus and other associated Middle Camberwell
Freedom track epilepsy and lost ability for many memories so had permanent permanent anterior grade couldn't for many memories
going for the future and lost some of his awesome was all the memories memories and humans again space also humans have a
special deficit so there's some connection between space and memory and questions what is it would link spatial navigation and memory but I just
add a memory we fritters episodic memory memory for events experiences and so the working hypothesis is that these two things are really connected by a need a computational
maintain information about pine order and that is if you're going to use experience the guy future behaviour you need to figure out what the cause of
ships are between events in the world in a why did you know I if I if I see a and b what I really want to figure out what you want to record the fact that you can be happy together
I want to try to understand the relationship between Eden and be did a Coors beer what you know how might I actually predict be given a
and the way I would do that would be to construct some kind of simple internal model a predictive model is based on experience and so the idea is hippocampus
is experience and then stop through some process which will her to is the process of consolidation translates experience into some working model that can
advance and can be used to guide behaviour in decision making and critical that is just the idea of time and a particular time order
I mentioned the use of very simple technology in this case extracellular
recording taking a tiny wire this wire exactly for small wires each one about 10 microns across you twisting together
and all the bundle is about 35 microns human hair is on the order but 50 to 50 microns of these are wires or electrodes multi-contact lecturers butter
the hair human hair with red these things through the little oil rig drilling device here which is which manipulators
allow this wire to be driven down through spirits more guy can you inside out the bottle will be a number of these in the
individual electrodes each Control by the spider on micromanipulator so we can send these electrodes down this entire device in this case
I'm like 12 to 12 to 20 g and this can be placed on an animals head permanently or chronically and that is that it was
design doesn't come off so they all have this this lol helmet like being on the head small opening was made in the in the
the wires are sent through and Paul surgical procedure text maybe 30 or 45 minutes it's like out-patient thing
take longer to have your wisdom teeth pulled in the healthy brain implant installed them once this is installed these electrodes can be driven down and
apparently it gives you the ability to a minor pattern activity crossword populations over long periods of time
please weeks months so you have a tapped into activity in this brain area and you can monitors animals
learn in recall this looks like this a cartoon of the electrode for contacts daddy with the four contact
forgive you to Billy the triangle eat location watches stereoscopic contacts will give you a villa
triangular things and three-dimensional space on the properties of the hippocampal circuit
distributed across this cross the hippocampus in the rat there are on the order of maybe 200000 cells
area ca1 and the entire hippocampus there on the order of me wants to million selves and if you drop it like you're any
hippocampus you will find cells that have this going to special property and see what that says is that special information is distributed not in a
topographic wait another is not one location space is mapped into one location on the brain in the in the hippocampus
make some of the sensor areas that you might that have is kinda topographer in sprints and see if you record in the in the visual cortex where there is there would be some course planner
twin location in visual field and the location of cells in the cortex responded that so-called retinotopic map
visual film out onto the anatomy same thing with like the somatosensory system as a moving and I touched your part of the body to cells respond that will be mapped out
any sort of largely one-to-one correspondence between the adjacency of stimuli in the inputs
Jason c of the representation of the narrow space that does not occur in the hippocampus to cells that are right next to one another or no more like
to respond to nearby locations in space into cells that are different from one another so it will discuss the principal
information representation hippocampus appears to be one of kind of sparse distributed patterning that you have lots of cells
that will going to respond to different environments and individual cells don't have a unique relationship
pattern across cells that keeps you are unique signature of Coke taking advantage of the fact that you don't necessarily have to place the
at the proper place an order see these get responses in some location space anywhere you put these like those in their campus
at a certain fraction 30% of the cells will respond in a given environment and this is what does responses look like I'm go to the tech
tails but this just shows how advanced action potentials that are detected in here
you're voltage trees pick up the amplitude of these of these little voltage transients
action potentials in the cell the amplitude across different channels in this way it's point is an action potential on what you see is that the
cluster of that in a way that reflect the relative positional location of cells the sources relative to these wires with the using the base
cancel that if you're close the door wire the signals gonna get stronger so amplitude is essentially inversely related to
so what does so here this is the amplitude of an action potential plot across two channels these points or large on Channel One
to that means it's close to channel 1 bar from channel 2 in the different cells will have different relation this will be loaded on Channel 2 small channel one set of so
figure out where the cells are in space means you can before lots of to pick up lots of cells from in this case maybe 12 or 18 elektros
can give you 54 hundred and myself and looking at activity themselves and simplebox this is a little black swan wall remove ceiling
simple architectural design clean simple clean simple map
especially locations into these no responses to these panels represent the activity of individual cell
this is about 80 simultaneously recorded cells colour of the heat map indicates the the the firing rate of these individual cell
red and the kids high firing rate blue indicates no firing so this is a top-down view of their parks so this sell for instance when the animals wandering around
Marcs sale in all the blue areas and we're goes in the lower right hand corner of The Sapphires vigorously so silent by us because we just want fires on
a while this one also fires in the lower right hand side so in the sort of points out this the comments for real nature of the spatial representation that is that
in the lower right hand corner of this particular box you will get these two cells to fire I take me and my put into a different box all of these
answers will be scramble up there's nothing that says the seller fire in the lower right hand corner of another box and certainly you if it does fire in the lower right hand corner
12 l isn't going to fire along with it and it in given location there roughly 1 to 5% of the cells that are firing so it any given location there about
5000 cells in hippocampus the rack so the location the unique location and unique contacts environments can beacon
across a pattern of a uni powder for $5,000 out of 100 to 100000 cells that is large comment oil space in which one can represent uni
unique locations for potentially unique experiences within different locations
on average by 30% of the cells respond in a given environment the silence as will see they can be detected when the animals are not in them running
spirits in space but when they're asleep on the visa offline states when the hippocampus is actually evaluating thinking about other stuff
about a bit and then here you can also see a small number of these cells in this case you know about that
Bob in 5 to 10% of the cells seem to have elevated firing rate across the entire space is there actually different classes
excitatory neurones inhibitory neurones in a bichon the idea that you have circuits that they can both excite and inhibit and this is used as
is a circuit property to descoped computation is something that will also discuss so this balance between
the principle that you used and have a fire all over the place they're not really communicating information they're really modulating the processing
and another property of these cells that that'll keep from play cells is that when animals are constrained to move along
a long is limited in this case this is a linear tract as referred to it so I can look order and was moving down the corridor when we've done a corridor
Molly play Over the Emily is but also the direction is going so this is the first indication the cells and not just again that's just the GPS telling you where you are
it's at least telling you where you're going maybe what you're doing so here by look at this yellow cell I can tell the piano was not all in this location was moving
this this linear tract in this direction so there's going to be a unique sequence when Emma walks along this path yellow cell
Sal green salsa the difference as a colour code here so if you look over time you'll see that there will be a unique sequence of active
play hippocampus that reflect the animals actual behaviour experience in that space so here it is just a movie that shows raw this isn't this is what you actually see if you
experiment with all pop down view Green Circle shows where the rat actually is the colour coding is a cells that we picking up over here this is
theatre as would be coming out of setup Wi-Fi is here the dark blue sapphires here to sell like yourself this is a special firing
play cells was stuff lots of activities
activity stop again little bit later
how is moving if you listen carefully you're here this
Rhythm is a modulation background modulation activity which is associated with locomotion
there really two modes your actively engaged or you're taking information in you get this with them when your inattentive not engaged not taking information in but infinitely evaluator
was awake is replaced by these bursts of activity and so these two modes active attentive
what's the thing for me from coming in inattentive you're evaluating information to Georgia taking your thinking about stuff can be reflected in these two
acoustic mode which you can literally you can hear them you can hear the difference between the two very easy for me to pick up might be hard for
listen to a little bit and it's very easy to distinguish these two different brand of the another view of that day the same data only now instead of showing you the
I better where is the corner where is the firing this one thing about it that's so compelling and that was literally Rod day that he was coming out this like this nope
sing at all and you can see the colour you can see the special Coral out which tells you you know this is that something that requires you know I have to do
multiple multiple regressions in the show you all of the Universe give you some sort of statistical
this is what happens when you can literally see it in individual cells the special quality is extremely robust compelling consistent
pause one selected if you require any of the cells that the campus you're all doing that yes that over 95% of the cells and she got the wrong hippocampus
properties so it's really fundamental property of simple
beef and estimation algorithm to ask the question ok if if we know which cells are firing can we guess
occasion the van would likely be we know the firing as a function of the location we can use for bayesian inference two
probably a location given firing and that's all going to do here just asking if we know which cells are fire in Princes if that blue sellers firing you
what's up the animals probably over here so recording across looking at Pat across many cells and there were coming up every 100 MS
coming up with a probability that that pattern could have occured the animals at any location on the track in the probabilities can be shown by triangle be trying on this high probability
what's your C is when you do this estimation in the animals moving you see the triangle the triangle basically the
was it only signalling when the animal was actually moving and all the other locations
what is the Centrelink typical representation is tracking location the animal
are you at the triangle an animal stops trying on the lord Portsmouth Road animal is back and get the train jumping around the track so going to be sumo
and representations have you two properties moving oscillation track her location stopping
the way representation are jumps across the flat
that also occur and I just want to enable stuff briefly want to actually go to sleep too here in the inset this is the animal has been taken off the track all together it's just sitting in a little box somewhere else
pulled up and sleep you get the same bird and when you decode activity fine you can decode the position on the track and if you look
can you see the position actually follow is a sequence of trajectory along the tracking and we'll go into that little bit more detail
so you think they're being is two states the offline and the online in the online with animals moving the characteristic mode of activity
the campus is an oscillatory mode which is a temporary solution when an animal stops in becomes quiet
them I have a second oscillation goes away and was replaced by these large trancy any periodic events his so-called sure
so your electrical that you measure see these large deflections and then if you do me and I'll show you
shortly very high frequency oscillations about wonder 200hz writing on top of it is referred to as
he described this short wave ripple activity course planner
offline state quiet week fall and some sleep States
at this oscillatory States owner was actually moving and I thought id show you the special Coral this place sells but there's another property of these cells
what can you also discovered but this was in early 99 is around 1991 and that is he noted if you are still look at the discharge of single spikes
with respect to this oscillation first of all the spikes are actually phase-locked it was here spikes fire when oscillation this theatre Rhythm is there
so the idea is this oscillation really reflects plain bearing excitability sometimes were cells likely to fire other times when it's
you can think of this oscillation in excitability has been an oscillation in relative excitability or in a different
mission elevation is high low it's high is low when inhibitions low so fires when is high sell doesn't part so this is modulation excitability
is it is here buddy not another thing and that is if you look at the precise phase so here yourself tender fire kind of the pig but here this innovate
what animal would be a constant velocity space and time are interchangeable so as the animals moving through it's Place feel the spikes
start the fire earlier on earlier there's a phase code spatial location so you can tell based upon the relative phase with
I was just entering the field spikes player Elite you're close to the peak v further end of the field with a fire a little bit earlier
there's a relationship between distance into the field and relative phase phase possession in this is a representation of that this is actual Dita
Middle Street basic principle is the idea that if I have a place sell by look at the marginal distribution as a function of location this will be the place feel that way just collapse
yes this is the spiking now as a function of position and be if I just looked exploiting as appointment position is just a density of firing
what are we get as a place for you not many spikes here is there an electricity old lots of spikes here as you getting this would be the classic specialist
banana Fe introduce phase as well as a systematic relationship as well between phase and location in fact bees
the better predictor of relative location then firing rate when do the spike occur if they hear late
please that I know the animals just entering the feel of early in phase I know that the end of it feel and
interesting and this is a simple model that says well you see where explaining that is if you've had this excitability model that this was one of the questions that I guess
what about this weeping in a bichon so we just imagine that you have an input excited for the input shown in blue and then inhibitory input Sean and red
in the vision is oscillating and you you you apply a very simple by physical model it says a spike action potential
when excitation a blue exceeds in a bichon in red excitation and emission just like so here as in this oscillation anywhere
red traces high in the blue Trace no spiking in this case when excitation is low you have to wait until inhibitions dropped all the way to here
to get a spike this is late fees so we get citation means you have to wait until Inner Vision is low the sweeping inhibition you'll have to wait till
excitation strong I don't need to wait so long you can play it earlier so the principal here is that there's a relationship between magnitude latency stronger
that's wife is principal very simple stronger or weaker later that will give you this space possession property
fashion I think of is biophysical curiosity but when you think about how that would apply when you have more than one place sell it back I have to
that was here one in blue one here and purple where play someone is to the left of Place L2 so the owner was going through here for the blue Solar Fire and the
the purple cellar fire and if you look at the excited excited for a drive showing here's a wrap and blue ramp and purple and now you ask
is the blue Sal going to fire the purple signifier during each one of these oscillatory cycles in the sod1 because the Blues the excited for drive the booth
higher than the purple sell blue is always going to fire before purple and recycle it will be blue purple blue purple purple so this
super bowl of fees possession of these coding for single cells actually give you sequence encoding across the population
play on kitchen every cycle have a sequence the code in the hippocampus that location it's actually a sequence of trajectory and
Friday but I'm going to quickly go this is just the speaking looks like and you can see if you looking and you'll see these going to spike sequence is but the property is more clearly
do you want to do this decoding so what's your what I'm showing here this again Rod eater but now it's showing the spiking I'm showing you the the result of doing this decoding
leaving the coding with us a probability estimate that given spiking activity in each one of a set of successive 20 millisecond
Windows some walking on now in the fire and air find a temple resolution every 20 milliseconds I'm doing the same decoding probabilities indicated in Grace
so you can see how the dark this is like high-probability this powder the and would have been in this location or to get this pattern of activity in this $20 so I can be in
here is the probability these beating decoded probabilities form short sequences every single day cycle
bidet sequences in the theatre sequence is actually move from just behind the animal that otherwise ready and we actually is assessment goes and just behind the animal just front of them
10 times a second hippocampus is actually expressing a representation of speaker sequence the goes from behind to infront the animal
behind in a front as also reflecting the recent past in the near future so there is this relative predictive
differentiation of response as a function of oscillatory phase so if I want to look at
where did I just come from I just have to look at activity here at the slightly earlier phase if I want to ask the question do you wear my likely to go
it's about to shift the phase the channel I look out here and I can see where the likely future location is so you can think that there is actually a
the location of the relative causal relationship between locations in the face and we'll see the weekend
mentally test this idea that's that's not a let you know if I can order fact or decoding but the animals are actually using information of these dish
eases to drive special navigation in particular ways by using some of the tools for men
activity in the close the closed-loop up gnx4 so we can manipulate activity specifically manipulate activity be careful activity different phases ensure
different phases actually carry different functional consequences that this sequence is captured during these oscillations are this exactly meaning for
some indication that this that the 80 oscillations in the sequences are meaningful first come from the observation that is a as imagine actually successful using mm
information of the campus requires the track that communicate this to exactly two structures that can guide behaviour make decisions that went through the prefrontal cortex portion of the prefrontal
text Olympic Circuit what is the limbic prefrontal cortex which have direct connect
the hippocampus in hippocampus have deficits in spatial working memory prefrontal cortex you said think of this is as
deficits in working memory and retrieval executive control decision-making but
sing these two things working together providing information for the prefrontal cortex can use an order to
bedroom decision making and you damage you do one of these things and rats can't find the way around space or damage you either one of these in humans you're going to get you're going to get memory deficits
rethink dementia is being a Proms cognition and memory you can get them temporal lobe dementia frontal lobe dementia
they're the really very closely related and so we can look at a simple task
is a simple task testing a soccer working memory just what did you do last just as it's just a simple alternation when you turn left
if a large Villiers like lock I just got screwed over here when I check out the other place around I will check up places where I didn't get food this is this
the so-called windshift strategy I got something at this time and go someplace else as opposed to like a reference memory strategy would be but if it is a
that's really good spot home I love going home cos you know I got my my TV I got my microwave I'm going to stick with that place mince
keep going back at the place that you know the words you can say good think about that again both these things have ecological value home is a good place that's reference place for foraging
when Chef don't go back the place I just leave it rate and Sophie again these two
classically you think of the prefrontal cortex with working memory cells this is the short-term the idea of shorts
so prefrontal cortex tip is meant by diverse subserving working memory or working memory is about holding informational short delays
overlap and terminology for working memory in the prefrontal cortex really thinking but I'm working memory differ campus through thinking
the context in which is used relative specific information specific information
so I can go to the two systems and an interesting property in that if you look
penis Lee what you're playing is that the same idea about oscillatory phase governing the firing cells Nipper campus also
prefrontal cortex that sells the prefrontal cortex like to fire it's certain phase of the hippocampal theta really care about their listening to
rhythm in the hippocampus so we can look at a task this is basically the same kind of house we know it is a back to back to me so I can be 2t mazes
was going to a simple variation on that working memory task in which
animals going to stop on his two arms I can walk down this arm and then it has to go to the arm that's on the same side that it started from
remember where did I start from I left the side I have to go to turn around and come back when I'm here and we're going to force it into one of These Arms
two back to back teenagers in this direction animal chooses in this direction we tubes Direction that working memory
I have to remember where it came from in this direction don't have to remember anything was making a difference so behaviour is symmetric but cognitively your this working memory
then he does not want to look at all these things oscillations biking and the with the oscillation
look up a keep time with the firing respect that firing spiking as a function of this oscillation both structures and
the bottom line is what you find is that this is a measure of this is a measure of relative phase locking and there's how well
do prefrontal cells actually lock2lock to this state oscillation
what you find is that the degree to which they like the theatre of them is a function of whether or not the owner will have to choose for the red ones are when animals go
on the arm and scatter choose the grey one is when we when it doesn't have to choose which use then in addition the solid red is when the animal
use to get it right and still red is when had to choose in a got it wrong so the degree to which the proof
cortex actually locks successfully locks to the hippocampal theta rhythm predicts whether the animal actually makes the correct Rosa not so it says that
all that is necessary for effectively communicating information between the two structures and the nun
in the blocking of the spikes spikes in the prefrontal cortex the rhythm hippocampus it also comes in the blocking of the rhythms
so you can think of being this is the this is the the theatre rhythm that you can detecting the prefrontal cortex in the campus and what you can
add two conditions one your the animals actually choosing it's running down was making a choice in the by the house second before the animal makes a choice you see these two rhythms
they become cool here it so transient coherence is predictive of correct choice behaviour
the thinking is that the rhythm themselves can be generating coordinated through the regulation of his local inhibitory Circuit
dressed for instance in the relationship of local inhibitory control and neuropsychiatric diseases and disorders
disrupting local inhibitor rhythms and particular some like Francis the theatre rhythms in prefrontal cortex can be associated with the
play schizophrenia friends and for the inability to effectively imposed these modes and then synchronise these mode can be seen as can introduce
ability to communicate or use memory cognitive disruption coming through disruption of these oscillations through disruption
inhibition in his local circuits are you actually coordinators to subjective you know what states are we been looking
at the role of like midline thalamic nuclei so the thalamus is being a set of structure is the have widespread conductivity tall is water clear
that they have much of their connectivity is inhibitory and so they have the ability to actually coordonate modulator and coordinated
the is oscillatory modes like we've even just recently published on individual cells we found some of these Midlife olimpiai that
present for branch single cells or branch in Target cells in hippocampus and the prefrontal cortex so they would be ideally positioned to enter
how to select in a post the synchronisation they think about a lot of this dynamic connectivity
established presumably through some sort of the lameck regulation and then you think about the thalamus is being regulated by there's a so-called the
reticular nucleus that that regulates the thalamus and it can set up these modes there's also lot of interest now in the fire protect their nucleus in
diseases and disorders a lot of those sort of the genetic screening has identified Targets in
I think about again it's like the like the oscillator in your computer your you know what your radio that breaks down
information computer but you can tune into it so it's fundamental to niigata have the modes and you got to be a block of these frequencies and then beyond that as well see
it's not just the frequencies but it's also the precise phase within those those outlet Ormeau that carry different information that we actually
by taking advantage of these techniques Apple genetic techniques for targeting manipulation so you were in fact the inhibitory neurones and hippocampus
with this up genetic genetically encoded and controllable channel so that we can optically
site inhibitory cells so we can practice excitatory channel into inhibitory cells and then we can transmit only giving very
pulses of Laserlite we can activate Drive inhibitory cells and then because the local Circuit those inhibitory cells will inhibit
excitatory cells so we have my 2025 Ms control and now we can lock or control
Innovation based upon the phase of this oscillation so the ideas were going to selectively
Rob or inactivate the hippocampus a different phases we're going to ask you those phases that a different terms of their
contribution to behaviour performance to hear the lock in addition to the peak of the trough of the state oscillation and so in the staff
and we're going to do this manipulation and that is selectively inhibit hippocampal output for the peak of the trough the theatre rhythm it should behaviour phases so the staff
animals can start One of These Arms going to run up it's going to choose so we're going to think about the Stirling Arms as this is the encoding faces we have to keep
where you are and then here in the central are more retrieval phases we have to remember all where did I come from and then use that to decide where you going to go
and we found was pretty surprising and that is that you might think well if you shut off hippocampal out for a turn off the
you're going to get an impairment it's just like a few examples that I gave suggest need to cancel prefrontal cortex and almost looks come from leaving studies you damn that the campus and what can't find
so I can read up after genetically vision turn off hippocampus he might imagine ok and not be able to find their way around so
you could ask this experiment is going to identify which fees and in a which behavioral phase
are most effective in disrupting performance but we actually found was when you selectively inhibit activity different bases
set in a housemate get better and it depended there wasn't just one thing as a good phase in a bad place but both of the peak and the trough
put effective in enhancing performance but only when applied at certain behavioral phases but there is a double dissociation and that
that Prof stimulation when applied here so when you stimulate in the craft
in the retrieval segment and will start better when you stimulated the peak and then Cody saying it and was got better so it was
kickers god of the trough as good as the peak the peak is good during retrieval in the Prof is good
ring according to what it says is the peak in the troll have two different functions and if you actually think about what I was showing before the sequence is the sequences that are
just behind just in front of the am what it says it oh yeah these different phases pcontrol you can think of is like past and future and so if I'm sick
here in this encoding segment I'm really trying to do as I'm just trying to keep track of where am I right now no I'm a simultaneously also be think
where am I going to go but for this task that really helpful it's not really useful at this point I need to focus on where I am right now so you can think
simultaneous lyrics of these two channels where am I where am I going to go and I can enhance performance by shutting off for inhibiting the non-relevant one
so when I keep a shut off the retrieval channeling and then coding I get better like focusing attention it's like you know like pay attention to what you doing now stop thinking about stuff
similarly when I'm here in the retrieval segment I'm also on Kodi I'm trying to keep track of where I am as well as think about where I'm going to
is keeping track of where I am here that relevant for the task it might be broadly roller for the animal but it's just want to shut all by
turn off that including channel enhance the retrieval information that goes out though it says it doesn't
it's not the singer so this is how we can improve memory by selectively shutting off the hippocampus well this is not a strategy for Kylie Jenner
hippocampus working much better when all these days are an operation and that's because the campus is not designed to solve this task if it can
play the song The Bright attack is trying to figure out this task relevant to all the other things that I have to do it was your try and integrate this information in
the other information you have and that requires connecting so to connecting the encoding retrieval you really need to have all those piece of information available
point out that one can actually dissociative function of information these two different phases the phase actually matters in it matters at the level of
decision making not just it's just a idiosyncrasy artefact of excitability as a function of phase
really how information is being used