the phone can't answer is provided under a Creative Commons licence your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality
resources for free to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of mit courses visit MIT opencourseware at ocw
am i t daddy you are going to shift more towards this decoding space that we we talked about the linkage between neural activity and behaviour report
8 introduce that a bit you just sort it there's some population powerful activity and ID and I'm going to expand on that a bit here but stepping back
when you think about it again what icon end and understanding from the image of the right to me to the perception report one of the things we want to do it again it's just define a.de coping mechanism
uses for supporters perceptual report activity or directly responsible for his Tas and I'll come back to later this encoding site is let you know I know
preemies in this order rates I want to know what the relevant aspects of their activity are in itu wherever you think they are then that sets at Target for what is the image
neural transformation that you're trying to explain that prick any no response to those particular aspects of the normal response that's what I mean by the relevant ventral stream parents of activity
so we start here we work to here and then we work to hear rather than this on their way around ok so I'm going to try it again keep with the domino set up a talk and I'll call recognition and
define task I'm going to talk about specific tasks that are for now let's call them basic level nouns I'm actually going to relax that to Savannah Tas in a minute
here they are car clock at these are not the actual amount of sugar the ones we use but just to fix ideas for managing a space of all possible nouns that you might use to describe
you just saw and I'm going to have a generated image of me so I know that's :-( piece of images here I'm not just going to drop these off to where we're going to generator only image Domain that we think engage
from the give us control the latent variables do I'm sure you that now so that we were going to do this is by generating one foreground object and each image that we're going to show
and we just do this by taking three models like this this is my love a car we can control the other latent variables beyond It's identity so this is a car as a pretty
tape for there's a couple leave variables about a dinner here that relate to the Geometry then there's these position position size and post that I mentioned that are on
does it make the problem challenging and we can then dislike render this thing and we could place it on any more background we wanted to and what we did was intended to place them on on
naturalistic backgrounds that creatures are weirdest looking images some of the mailbox or an actual hence book this looks pretty unnatural but the reason we did this
do this so we didn't because we can had a general space and because it was listening know what's going on with The Incredibles
and we also when we built this it was challenging for computer vision systems to deal with this is not humans good naturally you know they did have advantage of any contextual Kiwis you because by definite
struction is there are uncorrelated we just natural images and randomly put Alex on them but this was enough to follow the computer vision systems of the time and tend to rely
contextual cues like blue in the background singles of being an airplane we didn't want those kinds of things being done we wanted the actual extraction of humans could you were quite well
so that's where we ended up in this maybe this no mans land imagebase which is not very simple but not image that just pulled off off the web
so that's how we got there and just to give you some this is actually quite doable for him as Australia morning until you at the army to do them for 100ms you can kind of shout out what object
rates Aussie it's pretty straightforward they look weird you can do that quote
and you're here is the kind of images that we would generate this is this would be so when we think of image bad thing of partitions of image-based this is some images that would correspond a face
is there any images of faces on your son Transformations in different backgrounds these are not faces is there other objects again on the Transformations and we can have as many of these as we want
we call this one this Distinction mention 400ms is 1 core recognition test screening face or not face here is a subordinate ass is Beatles
what is a particular type of car you can see it's more challenging these images like this this is just to show you the set which on them one at a time and Solar mean
add and say we're going to try to make a predictive model using that kind of image space to see if we can understand what are the relevant aspects of neural activity that can predict
I am in space I want to say we I mean I need a massage and Hong hu post graduate student that we're in the loud that bled this experimental work and Ethan
my name is also contributed to the work so what we did was to try to record a bunch of IC activity to measure what's going on in
relation is actually Urban now in this more defined space were going to collect the bunch of human behaviour the compare possible ways of reading a with the behaviour of the human
this is how we started when our doing monkeys we're recording in the monkeys doing a task but we did hear was we just passively fixating monkeys compared with the
resume it's your monkeys and humans have very similar pattern to behave so what we recorded from mighty this case we using a recording electrodes these are
take me and plan at the shows them here you plant them doing a surgery kind of a show here that down in the cortex you can get the size here there about 100 like there's actually 96 electrodes and
typically you'll about half of the electrodes having active neuron's on them so you get you on the order of the 150 recording sites and you can leave them out you can like
Tivoli loud three of them across inb4 to record a population sample out.of.it across multiple monkeys and
sample of the kind of day we dead this is 168/18 recording sites this is similar to wait to show you earlier this is the mean response in a critically time window
Summer when I showed ruin it starting with Gabriel and what we do here is I'm just showing you have you feel that's one image Years War
images of the population factors in a graphic form and what we actually collected nearly 25 this is 2560 images assisted the me response date of this
your eyes and now you have it again this rich population that and you can ask what's available in there for a support these task and how hot is a predict human patterns of
pause cast asking to do with trying to do more and more recently but let me show you all we were trying to do is to say look wondering we are
even though you saw that car you can do cars you but your face is it seem like you're doing a hundred percent turns out you're a better at some things in other SodaStream this is a deep fryer
human soap red means good performance Heidi crime in a deep Prime of 3 years something like this in the room a correct me I did primer 3
90 song 95% correct in that range is a very high performance levels when you get up to 50 is chance so 50%
this is a Way Castle one of three percent correct something for doing Eatery Quay basic level Tas or eight wait for the cars are equally faces
please add Prime of different amounts of variation of the other Lane variables position size in clothes don't worry about those details what I want you to see is the colour here so look at some
discriminating tables from Woolies or objects you do that at a very high D Prime discriminant Beatles from other cars with slightly lower defryme
you can see this that special high variation you actually starting to get down to lower before it's and faces one face vs another face you're actually quite poor
a little bit better than chance but it's actually quite challenging in a hot and or seconds without hair and glasses to discriminate those 3D kind of face models I should use a major early as exam
you're actually quite quite challenging to do that for humans and that demand of faces so what I want to show you this pattern of behavioral performance you have always IKEA
this is humans vs monkeys and what we wanted to do is to see what we can use this pattern this is very repeatable across humans can we use this repeatable behaviour parent
what's 10 what aspects of this activity could map to that and I get this car is reliable I just said that and it's not as if you can predict this pattern by just running classifiers
pixels rd1 Invercargill show you that minute but we thought there's some aspects of Ikea activity that would predict this and we wanted to try to find those aspects to sew
this is motivated by this video should you earlier so which part of the itu population activity could predict this behaviour overall recognition test receiving a general the code
that would work here are some specific task but would like it to be work over any tasks that we could imagine testing he was within the still meme of taking 3D models putting them on a variation
add a tired or me that was what we were hoping to do so I can take you through it cos I already showed you earlier than we previously shown that you could kind of take this kind of state space
say hey can you separate images of faces from 9 faces using the symbol in your classified as which century weird storms on the activity and now we wanted
who does predict human behavioural face performs and monkey cause again they're very similar and Natalie Wood this class of barbercode email that was motivated by the earlier
predict this house but would predict car detection with the same model predict r1vs cartoon that's a subordinate ass and also cats again over the whole
can you take a sim the cording strategy and take the don't send me to learn on a certain number training samples build a classifier and then I'll say that's my model of how
does everyone at his house and if that's true then it should probably predict that kind of performance they just showed you earlier so here was again this was the
pharmacist castle your books by crates using single fix time scale Aerospace industry because a sample of writing are single Elvis sing a fixed number of non-human
cortex of single number of neurones and learnt a reasonable number of training examples so all of that is a decoding class and models that we fart
if this is correct this is what I just said it to predict the behaviour of that we collect for example that the time that I just showed you but also more fine-grained data in
so I wanted to step back to make it clear that it's not obvious that this should work right I mean it depends were in the audience I get people and completely different
weather this should working out so you know one thing is like well I get spacily about your Daryl say well you didn't like passive Tas when I agree with that in the ideal world there will be
are we doing the cash and then you say I measure William was doing that ass it's going to be your best chance of production but we also earlier that the passing of monkeys still you know anywhere I got a parcel
rattle Dieter is is not going to be somewhat applicable division and you know the question is how much are those arousal effects show up in a place like i t cortex which is
which is higher up in the ventral stream so you know you could argue both sides of this but it's possible that it was only needed to make this a good predictive linkage between
tips to activate a t in the crew way if you like it it's good predictions
critical some people and point out that you have two kinds of different parts of this particular roles which is a prior and the coding space for instance
you could believe that biologically in animals boring is some tissue that's going to be dedicated to faces you have to wire the neuron's downstream to that tissue and that means you're going to restrict the
rather just letting them learn from the space of ideas if they collected samples of iolite so I think some people possibly believe that even if it's not stated quite that way
80 is not directly on your address you could imagine that I mean it's night for sure no one in some regions of I don't produce deficits in recognition of the possibility maybe
any train examples monkey Rocco's cannot explain human behaviour reasons that you might say this is -
working probably of gas and telling all in this simple thing works quite well for the grain of the hated that shown you so far and here is my evidence of ads
actual behaviour performance out of humans and shoulder releases Mandy prime this is the predicted behavioral performance of taking a classifier reading from that I can population day today
volume is the predicted the prime we first chosen Dakota it we had a match things like the number of niraj get it get it in the ballpark so because I'm going as a free variables or should you
best wine but for now it's think of matching the number of Mirrors to get you near the diagonal so that you have sufficient number of neural recordings to say how well do you do on a face 22
and then he was all the other tasks this is a 64 points and showed you earlier some examples like fruit vs other things card verses on things and you should see that
boys going to light up along this diagonal which was well this is actually quite predicted that I can take the simple thing and put it all the stuff that we collected so far and so let me
be more concrete about what what is The Infernal mechanism network testing here well this is for each new object we think we
is this some downstream observer a downstream randomly samples roughly 50000 single species distributed over all of 18 at bias to any compartments
ejt site out that my say listen in this case we could average or behind a MS when I sure about this is just the version that shown here learn and
needed some of the psyche spiking and then listen to 10% that's basically once you learn this heavily weighted about 10% of the 18 of the 18 as a heavily weighted for each of the
what does an observation that we have in our day but this is trying to map it to neuroscientist language from this decoder vs out.of.it so what that is a model that says
weird songs of 2003 marriage 100ms single unit responses distributor all 80 adventure stuff in here is what your your your mouth instead of encapsulated that's still
slimy the acronym out of that and that can't lasa rabb.it decoding mechanism so this is just the same as a hypothesis of how everything might work
can we make predictions for other objects and could potentially be falsified so I'm so far this model works quite well over these Tas
equations point a till you mate look at doesn't see all it's not perfect but it turns out that that's about the level at which humans differ from each other so it's passing a Turing test
mechanism red half of the monkey 80 is tides in the distribution of the human population that are asking also perform the same password can be distinguished from being human
and I wasn't doesn't pass that test passes Justice to book or recognition
so that was a touring test of that so it's ok so this is here is a qualified so this is a human human consistency that's the range I just mention that you know you're going to get
power so touring test on this and that said the coffee makers and I just showed you this other ways of reading out of i t that don't pass this ways are reading out of e42 recorded
none of them with tried are able to get you to this here that doesn't mean before isn't involved before is the feeder to i t it just means you can't take simple the codes off of me for in
actually pretty powder like pixels rb1 representation so lower-level representation don't naturally predict this pattern a behaviour and even some computer
weak acid at the time you can see if those you know he's older computer vision models didn't didn't do this but more more recent hearing actually do
sure you back yeah ok so this is a little bit pretty aficionados to tell you how we got there as we increase the number of units and i t that
performance up so he read more more you decided by T you get better better performance that's also true out of you for but I'm trying to show you this year as it's like not the apps
performance that is the good thing to compare a model with actual behaviour alldata it's the pattern of performance which we call it consistency with the Hume
correlation along at dargaville they should arrive at Casa De hard for humans test easy for humans are also easy for the models and you could imagine doing
image love all is well and anyway that's what's quantified here in see that we could get up to around you know about a high should your 168
corners out of 80 that this point there is about 580 features in and taking it through some things that made it would have time for that's actually Howie approximately
thousand single 18-year-old number that's an inference from our data based on a record $50,000 on spot from these kind of plants were able to make it
good gas that this is the best this kind of all right here would pretty good with land right there to be consistent with humans and woodmatt would get the absolute level performance
it's matched to be for example of them they can get peformance but they can never they don't match this pattern a performance night with a over before
contact an underperforming reveal themselves as not being human-like by being too good at some things right so that's a way to fail the Turing test
ok maybe I'll get through this through the same thing this is about 20 examples of care about this I can cut it take you through how it is actually of meth
scan Solutions in there and I just tell you about one of them for Simplicity so let me then just take it down to another grains that was the pattern of performance is actually naturally
by the first the coding mechanism that we try but what about the confusion parents are now just the absolute deprimes reach these tears because finer-grained 80 like how often an enema
is confused with the fruit around was due to the face these are the confusion pate de here I'm sorry I don't have the colour bars up all I'm going to need you to do is take the confusion patterns that we
are predicted and this is this is the predicted confusion man if I gave that the machine the i.t. these these ground truth tables
this is what I actually happen if you and eating whatever you decide look at this in this and see they're actually look quite similar the noise cricket correlation is pt-91 so it's still quite good at footy
vision powder this do not hold up for Leonie at Point 16th only some people would say that success roller 0.68 high variation
feel your hear them all that isn't should be at 1 because it's noise correct it so there's something about this it's not quite right at predicting the confusion patterns of humans of high variation images
that's an opening to push forward rates of this is a strategy going for it is we have an initial gas of how you read out of i t in looks pretty good for
screen task for now we can turn the crank harder we need more all day that we need more I'm psychophysics finer-grained measurements to distinguish among the better
can you forward other representations but what exactly about the ID representation is it 100 Ms what time steel maybe those synchronous codes do some of those things I put on
might start a matter we push the code push this even further so what I take on here is that you don't quite well with his first order rate code
start of 80 but now there's an opportunity to try to dig in and say what what what point do they break down and what kind of the coding Miles but you going to replace them with and that's what were
trying to do I told you that I T does good at identity but rumour has it really around ratios manifold this is other related variables like position in scale
get thrown away but just get unwrap try to remember that manifold Pictionary short earlier and so one of these we've been doing recently is asking because we built these images
variables like position pause that was one of the advantages of building images this way and we've been asking how well i t includes because other related variables about the poop
the object the position of the object to make a skip through the to make a long story short ATX encodes Natalie has information
these kind of variables which is really not surprising because other is have shown that there's information about those kinds of things before but that's so what time you're in everything
V4 simulated the one in pixels and you're always everything up along the ventral stream for the other variables which may be non-intuitive to some of you because position
VY the position of the object in a complex background is very nice that's one example but his labels go up along the ventral streaming
decoding but what I'm most excited about is that if you do this comparison with humans again you actually get this again pretty decent back why does tide coral
between the human behaviour actual estimates of other variables and the predicted behaviour of performance out.of.it in a much better
it's not perfect so we can do some gas through some failure of understand but much better than if you read out of me for the 1 or pixel so it says that the representation of
just an identity thing it seems like this could be representation under a light somebody's other judgement at least at the Central 10 degrees for foreground objects as me
that's the don't worry about the details on here that's the upshot of what I'm trying to say with this slide but I just wanted to put that out if you didn't forget that you don't throw away all this
interesting stuff about what's out there in the city ok let me kind of survey Luda to this a bit I want to come back to car now this is my level 3
so you have no idea what you're trying to soul you have a decoder of an algorithm that's a decoder on a basis that's try that looks like a predicts pretty well it's not perfect
yeah but it actually does quite well what does it mean and the physical hardware level 3 so you think he is how I visualise you have a cortex which I need
what's the 80s it's about 150 square millimetres in a monkey and remember I told you there was about 1 mm scale of organisation I should do that or earlier and
Israeli or two letters surface regions of the scale here this is the schematic that they're slightly bigger organization's 4 to 5 mm
you think of ideas being a sort of like 100 200 little this is not a new conceptual idea but there is just the simple version the each year
it does exactly the same thing is a feature and if you sample off of that you take $5,000 for the really sampling for only about 158 feet
at 1 mm scale remember I don't like that but I should 150 100 150 I should your home 6818 Iran's predict
Karen a human performance I showed that a few slides ago but I told her the real number of Lawrence is probably 50000 mils of redundant copies of that home 68 dimensional feet
ATO we think about it so you could imagine he's just a redundant set up about I like to think about 100 features and I teeth which was sampled maybe randomly
stream Iran's better than learnt so when you weren't faces vs other things hey there's lots of good information about faces versus other things in his face patches that's harder define
your eyes are going to lean heavily on this downstream runs going to be heavily on I was in your arms and then these do that would make these regions closely involves that doesn't mean you had to pry
then anything here downstream version you get something that looks like explain our date so we like that cuz captures that case but also captures the more General case
car is going to Singapore from a different sunset in your eyes but you're following the same learning rule that's what I said really right so you end up we think this is the initial state
objects and so what we think is a post learning what you have it again about 100 to 150 80 subregions 1 mm scale that are supporting a number of
house red off this common bases here that's that's the model that we like given the kind of didn't even showing you the pools learning email as we call
for the nearest Midas to fix ideas about how we think of it as a basis set and this is this I think I'm too service of nicely is employed somewhere things it's somebody down
ok but now we have a more Australia have a more concrete male we now I'm trying to try to be physical about about the size of these regions connecting to really a day how many there are
so we're getting influence on that from his different experiments and now if you believe it starts to make a prediction of what's now we can causality it's only mentioned that earlier and someone of
doing recently so we can start a silent look at the way of dramas this bit of tissue for this is a schematic is someone born in this test and that task-based asked and car test
desperate issue only pay staff and that better tissue only car task in this presentation either you believe that you had the tools you got to go and it starts Silence
what devices are used to get predictive or parents out of the behavioral deficits at the end when you make those manipulations right and follow that ok
give you a framework for builders predictions and also estimate the manga to the does a fact that you should see it so that's what we've been doing more recently and I'll just get your taste of this because this is really
going but if you connect to what Gabriel Satria but now he's tools available to do that I'll put that in from a trolley attack work OK Google has I think of Inception and I don't know
you can't do Inception last you actually in a brain so sorry going to try to insert the wizard this is my students working out really wants to inject signals
the dream about the MRI could you come in jackets percept and to do that I need to do experiments like this and understand this Harvard interact with it something to talk about
so I actually on it and I was like there's some cool acceptance of my memory but this is considering an object person so do that
can we reliably disrupt performance by suppressing 1 mm bits of 80 so to do that what we're doing is testing a large battery of
and a battery suppression pants and I just said everything can we affect Feast house at 11:01 imagine we test a battery of tas and then we are in the idea we have a hole
and we do every bit of 81 by 1 in combination and we should get all that didn't figure out what's going on mate that's the dream rates were trying to build towards that dream guys get it
I don't remember motivated by this kind of idea great so so we starting I just thought id give you a quick tour of we have tools to start to do this I mean
I am recording we can localizable recording to very fine grain using x-rays I'm so we know exactly work when I teach you like about 300 micron resolution
I'm putting this light up going if I silence this bit of a or in that bit of ideas that you actually do this experiment what happens behave
an eraser fries is a poo stuck in the lab started these actual experiments and one of the things of rushed did was the first say let's see if we can get this Silence
genetics tool to work in our hands on the reason we were so excited about that it's cos we think we can make temporary reef silencing but that might that would be the
more reliable disruption of behaviour that that then if we started to try with Jack singles which would be our dream but that seems to risky to us we just
what are the temporary legion of each bit of 80 do and after genetics is cool because there's no other techniques that can refli silence temporarily silence active
euphonik logical manipulations of those last 4 hours so this really sounds good survive him that's what we're excited about it we also did pharmacological manipulation as as a
to get started but what we're doing is trying to silence 1 mm regions of 80 using light deliver to optical fibres is the recording electrode and the
what's a bit of your ass here and so what arrived did was rickshaw you've actually Stylinson runs in this way to go haven't seen optogenetics plants this is needed for labour
cool about this again is you have the same images of being presented to this Green Line should be up here but I rushed trains delays around right here Shane's light on there and there's some absence Express
that local area and you can see attached to shut the thing down inside delete Roblox that you ever seen him put coming in but you can delete it here is another example
freestyle example it's not always this strong but that this is again you can see you can return back to normal raidaway right so this is a 200ms sounds you couldn't
narrower than that this is what we have done so far and again what we've never say what this is a risky tools and I can work it also a rush just wanted to test something that was
are likely to work and so we picked a feast house because it was a lot of evidence of those special classroom of faces that you your gear from dinner can you also know
so what we were rushed it was a say ID pick the task in the screaming meals from females we put in an ocean of invariant it's not just do this image access do you have to do it across
want to press relations in this case it's identity is a transformation to using all of these are supposed to be called mail on all these are come female me wanted you to distinguish this from that's that's what he trained
do and just to give me the up shot is that you know you always work with Hans a bit of Cortex and here's the big take home and get it 2% deficit of single one
you're silencing a bit of a cortex cortex not all about cortex 6%
Innaloo trouser some local bit of 80% deficit that strongly in the country out of feel not the ipsilateral feel pretty aficionados you might look at this 2%
that's exactly what's predicted by the right in the range of what should happen and so this to us is really quite call this is how
now we are in position to go to see your kitties tools work they do supposed to and now we can start to expand that passed space this result has been published recently
you're interested in this and here is one of the ways we're going for is at Rishi wrestling on the wind doing this pass in the month of silence in different parts of i t this is now in Noosa Mall
different bit survive is a different cast lead to different pattern that's what these dots are here different patterns of deficits and he got back to the same location you get the same pattern of datasets
call me can't ask but I think it will give you the spirit of what were trying to do and and again this is only used Mr which is known as in Hamilton
quieter rebuilding towards here it's just giving you the circuit that's a state-of-the-art so any Miss to measure the specific part of behavioural change and used by aesop
each idea subregion Zealand testing many of them and compared with the model predictions I am saying this to main and I want to set a simple the whole Domain so far and giving only just samples
what's the door mean what will the train into find domain and and I'm just gonna go get through this just to give you the punchlines that we you a whole bunch of the hero measurements
translate this is now up to 3 million mechanical it seems to ask that we can embed all objects even supported objects of the type of Testament telling you in roughly
20 dimensional space so there's 20 dimensions meet the humans are projecting for about 20 dimensions to do these kinds of the taps and showing here which is
smaller but you really close to that in the Coromandel to that 100 also features that I've been talking about some that regardless of whether this is these are some of the men
projecting them that I can I want to take you through this cos I think we've are used up enough time and I'll get on to this part but would try to find a domain of all Tas will be considered
would happen if anything within that dominant that raises questions of the dimensionality of that demand and it would behavioral methods to do that and we've been doing some work on that so
leave it at that and if you guys are questions we can talk about that someone I want to sit in the time I really have left us to talk about the encoding side of things cos I promise you guys I would get to this unless
any more brain functions on this decoding site by the link between i t and perception now I'm going to switch gears and talk about this other side which is so I talked about this and that
what's the mean rates n i t r something that seemed to be hardly predicted I showed you this one mile there's a lot of ratitie model for now it's ok now we can turn it the codings and Cody science
predict the main race survive and that should be our goal if you want explain images to 80 activity so there's need to be predictive and Cody mechanisms so
what now you guys are who become Lucian on that works you what you if you know about them already you're probably about them some more so we started messing around in 2008 this is a nylon spy
nature this family models before you born Resort Fukushima and there's a whole page Max family and model it really was the inspiration of this is larger this large family and models
Bob is repeating structure that there are now really this reminder publishing out what's really good out of all this really work and so we started Explorer
nearly in 2008 and just this is a sly that you've worries Christina version of this from Gabrielle you know for you take an image you pass it through a set of operated so your
where is the diesel dash products or restricted special restricted region like receptive field threshold and saturation you're pulling up rate
when you have a normalizacion to have all these operations happen here and that produces a stack so think of like it there for filters heroic orientations you get for images
Virginia for images out we get penalties and get $10 out then you repeat this here right as soon as you keep adding more filters a stack just keeps getting bigger and bigger and it keeps because
especially pulling a keeps getting marinere to go from this image to this a veggie stack of features that has less retina tap is a little bit around the tapping
and that you can see is exactly a very good male white people like that what help people think about the ventral stream so these models typically have thousands of feet visual
the features of the top level just give you a sense of scale off when you're how they're run and just to take you through the you know I just did you hear about the SIM not already
element has like a filter as a large fan in like this like neuroscience related things they have none in the areas like threshold of Iran's nuclear is convolutional
which means you apply the same filters across visual space which is like Reddit app that is a few wines cellar door and hear the BMW want cell that's that's another spatial position same orientation
casual position that's what the car will come loose implementation of that idea copy machine filter type across the retina and is a deep stack
all things that I think of commensurate with the with the ventral stream Anatomy and physiology so but one of the key things
models no is that they have lots of unknown parameters are not determined from the neurobiology even though the family might as well describe what are the exact filter weights
what are the threshold parameter is how exactly do you pull hard in normal eyes there's lots of parameters when you build these things such a thousands of parameters most of the hidden in the weights
which one do you think about the first layer that would be like should I choose Gabor filter as I should I do some other in home with parking lot random weights right so this choice is there the lot of parameters
what is a big that's why I called a family of Marvel's and how you choose which one is the right one so the speaker is there right one I never whole family is wrong
interesting discussions so we what I like about it at least when you said it's a model and make predictions and then you can test it so it's at least the Lilo and it predicted
entire you know he start the map is he say this is me why this is me to this is before it predict the formula population response to any image across is the area so I
wrongly predictive model one still so that's nice but now you have to determine how am I going to build it how do I set the parameters so how do we do that
well there's lots of ways you could do it and I'll tell you the way we choose to do it which was too just not use a normal Dieter it was just to use optimisation methods to find specific model
the parameters inside as model class and we chose an optimisation Target this is a little bit of get inspired from the top-down view of what the system is doing what
Casa we suppose the ventral stream was supposed to solve which I already told you we think it's in very an object recognition that's what makes the problem hard so we tried after my smiles for sword
century we doing that kind of doing the same thing that computer vision is trying to do a couple doing it in our own demand of images and Tas that we set up we it's actually there is a meeting between computers
what we were trying to do with here and I say weird this is work by their name and post-graduate students and what we did was to
simulator going to dinner early we took these simple 3D objects you could render them just as before placing my naturalistic background and then we just don't models that will try to discriminative
bully from flowers from Guns still there would have good future said that we discriminate between the sink and these are essentially trained by various forms of supervision
you can train his models I wish I could tell you but how we did it and how others have done it I think those details are beyond when I want to talk about today but just to supervise class
we're not learn in the same way brain is where most people don't think so but the everything is the end stated his models might look very much like the current
that's what I want to try to tell you next show you that we built this mother's was in 2012 we had a particular optimisation approach that we called each and that was trying to solve
is Kiama prom social kind of images and I tried your idea was pretty good with humans I tell you it's performance was almost up the humans in which US 268 samples
spell the male here we're able able to do much better and some of my previous models that only seem kind of casley told you we construct it cos it mean you it made these things
models not do so well so we got these hi invariants task to push these models down and then we had space to do the model that would that we could do better on and then we built
1.0 and then we weren't started to say now we have the smile that was going to optimise performance let's see how well it does comparing with no
Chinese look like the neural beta so here is the model we build a timber 1.0 it's a deep convolutional network and has different layers it had four levels had a bunch of parameters that we set
position but I just tell you what we optimise it in tell you not tell you any of the parameters and now we come back to see what we can share the same images to the model that we show to the neurontin
compare how well these populations look like that population of his population looks like that and so what we did was we as how well can play for predict 81st
what was the first thing you wanted you take a top loader this model and the last layer before the linear read out of this model to do that you might be disabled wait a minute
have mappings it has some na on simulated here around 12 or something and it's only recorded but there's no linkage between that and Iran and that you're on right you have
make that Maps so what we do is we take each 18 Iran and treat this as it as sort of a generative space you can Jerry's many stimulating around as you want you just have
take us to write Excel data and try to build a linear regression to listen to this as a basis to explain that in the right and that's then test the predictive power on the held out
that's what I'm ready yet Christ valid linear regression so I'm going to see your predictions on held out day it was some of the data were used to make the mapping and what is
Louise we chose the we could make the mapping and we did essentially all of them that I could talk about that if you want but that's the central idea take some yourdata say is this in the linear
span by this piece of set for can I connect fit that well with this with this when you're racist here from this basis and here is what we actually here's what it looks like here is
Tina Iris part of one simulator once actual I can run in black this is not time is there images as I think it's like 1600 images here so each beer
lying down you can barely see is the response the me response to different images and you'll see me group them by categories just so just to help you kind of understand the date
just be a big mass because I can ask you can have a bit of category selectivity and then this with no one seems to like cherry images but not all cheering
play Lakes boats and some plans a little bed and the red line is the prediction of the model once it's fit 2 part of it to this Iran this is the prediction of the hell out of date
you can see the RSL where it is point for it to happen explainable response where it is explained by this model and predictions the
will never seen the objects even remember seen by this Marvel before before it makes these predictions here so this is just saying that they
urbanspace actually quite well captured by the top level in this case on this first HR moment we built through some other models in a minute because of
the lake faces of the other categories so I might pass the test it out the definition of a face there on this model of this ground was well predicted again
it's preferred number for face images by this hmo mulugeta slightly 0.5 there isn't that you look at the category structure and
UK police iliac arteries really still here but you don't see you soon blocks you just see the images that likes and some it doesn't hurt you and know what's driving this number
quite well predicted I think I'm going to have the ice cream but it's similar it's about half the explainable variance just another example and he was a sort of Sunbury here if you take
distribution of explainable variance for the top level the model fitting about I think is 168 sides some sites are fit really well near 100% summer outfit
the average is about 50% which is shown here so this is the median of that distribution here so the summary take comment about 50% of Samira sponsoring
is the big improvement of a previous Miles Australian minute the other levels of the model don't pretty really well so the first level doesn't pretty well saying all the fourth level the
if you take other models do some animals actually are they don't fit nearly as well here is there distributions and here is there average that meet their million explained variance
just to fix the just fix ideas you might take well that we build a model that's a good categoriser so of course if it said he runs well because I seen as a cat
here is a model that actually has explicit knowledge of the categories not an image computable Malone it's not an easy one but it's just given it to have an Oracle that's given the category
how it explains ITM UC explained 18 much worse than the actual so this implies a male is limited by the real lot and the architecture puts constr
animal on how it at various that that this is just a night in other categories does not easily capture so so that kind of
that sort of inspired us to say ok what about if we go down as soon as I can but let's go to be for cuz we had a bunch of me for date and so we play the same game and be for real estate
3mc we can predict before and here's the itdata just show you a minute ago and here is the new Ford day that so the v4na answer Hayley predicted in the middle layer
where's the best picture of me forever players actually not so predicted less predictive of the 4th and the middle light years and the first day is not so well predictive and get the other models are
now you can see they're getting a relatively better you could be going to the lower level models and in there they're getting better which is what you expect but interestingly
exciting to ask because what does my was not optimise the fit any normal D2 other than that last mapping step what is a bone spur algorithm class which is
neuroscience view of the fee for class of the field and test the Wii another's hypothesize are important that the burger should might be up to
the song of an actual optimisation procedure that we applied and that leads to Nora like encoding functions at the top and in the middle layer so you don't you know you this
so this service to funny things like saying what is V4 do the answer here would be well it's an intermediate layer in a network milk been to optimise these things that's the way to describe Whitby
does according to this kind of modelling approach now and want to point out is it only happens if it's far from perfect the room to improve your but it's Billy dramatic
we got out of these kinds of Miles you take this you take this back to in a big picture where do we do here
what we doing as we have performance of a Marlin hi Andrew it's recognition cash received this is what we have been trying to optimise we noticed is that if you plant these data samples out of
the family is black dots or other models I should use to control models that we're in the fuel at the time and this is the ability of the top of them are the top level of the any of the models to
80 responses so you know how good they are predicting the this is the median variance explained of single ID responsive and use it as a correlation here you're better at this
predicting that and all we did was optimise this way which we think it was like evolution of developments around fitting all day was optimising forecast performance and that lead
12 to a model that I just showed you explained about half of the i t response very well it looks like it's continuing up this way ok so what you believe that store
then that says it we can optimise further on these kinds of task maybe we can explain more variance and it turned out we didn't actually need to do
because again I said computer vision was already working on this and there's a lot more resources they already doing it there any better than us on its original model
Topo stuck in the lab these remote Kmart the times is Christian scared of supervision of August 2013 there are better than the model that we have built now we're in assisted image
you know we got the reason why we can see that better regards think you're better at our own tast than the models that we had built right so they were already ahead of us on the task that
designs and so they're up here then are up here and so if you father prediction that means these models might be better predictors of Ronaldo
optimise performance on task but we could take their features from the Northern to play the same game and we actually explain our spot are they better than
Alex planner on this is a nice statement that it is not even NRL ladder just continued after position for those kinds of tasks with the features that are good for dictors of the
keep responses and that's what you were here so that's why I just said there so that trolls take this further analyse awesome order
the summary were presented in the second half now showing that I think phone with her future learnt object judgements naturally predicting the monkey performance as well with the
does a rat ATO pick a particular molar which is 100 or second reading this time window 50000 around 100 training examples that's one particular choice
cold mile that's just a is a current current state of Dakota mullet fits data banana a day too and we also want to get finer grained
The Entrance is this might be this specific error code and decoding mechanism of the brain uses support his task that's we like to think but now which one do systematic
kasumi talk a lot about trying to summon spits of 80 is one example of that and the tools are still not like them to be but you see were making progress there
the second was so should optimisation of deep CNN models for a very optic recognition castle entry dramatic improvements and our ability to pretty Katie and your response as I told you are my way to Melbourne
car wash on average in the field of our superstar predictive ability Anna uninstall the influences that these encoding mechanisms in these models might be SIM
does it work in the streaming in now you know there's a whole set of area we can start to think about doing physiology on the model so speak and that comes almost as hard as doing
I'm the only girl I'm ready and so this is allowing if you're designing exploring the me what's unique and Powerful that
what's the weather in Krabi recognition of a house having to extend out of that I think it is now people are trying to do so big picture of us for the future I've talked about this last
can we pretend here and get a fax you that a predictable can we predict for each image coding model at hand for the article the manipulations we talked about
Dynamics and feedback something that were interested in but I haven't talked much at all about I think that's a good discussion topic I can see how weird
we have some some slime alfredson that regard I talked on the encoding side of these kinds of deep convolutional networks that map from images but the dash
give me the only 50% predicted both of these cases there in the NAB perfect right so there's work to be done there and one of the real exciting things is here is how these models were in this
we are learning his miles is almost surely not what's going on in the brain so finding more or less super magical motivated learning of these models a good is
step I think for much of the field but it's nice is have an end that that's much better than any previous and stayed we had before so that that's that's a Target at Watson
might look like you know maybe we can think about expanding beyond call recognition in the question period about that what we when is the right time to catch
working with Anna Domenica recognition of the Saturday set up vs expanding the honour cos lots of aspects of object recognition that I didn't touch on here and that comes up
I think there's lots of work to be done within the Domain but it's also enjoy captions extend outside of that domain