the phone can't answer is provided under a Creative Commons licence your support will help MIT opencourseware continue to offer high quality
resources for free to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of mit courses visit MIT opencourseware at ocw
am i t daddy you so I'm going to talk today about a couple of things I had a hell of a time constructing a nice clean narrative arc for everything
say it so far only just decided to hell with that I'm just going to be honest of several different pieces they're not make a narrative arc that's life I want to address what I say
microscopic view of the organisation of the human brain is giving us a kind of picture of what I'm going to call the architecture of human intelligence
telligence in this class and so I think the overall organisation of the human brain in which we've made a lot of progress in the last 20 years gives us a kind of
picture of what the pieces of the system are so ill talk about that and then oh also if I've talked fast enough do a kind of whirlwind
through the basic methods of human cognitive neuroscience using voice recognition as an example to illustrate what each of the methods can and cannot do it so that's it
it could be pretty basic so if you've heard me speak before he probably put a lot of this so anyway the key question were trying to address in this course is how does a
produce intelligent behaviour and how many we be able to replicate that intelligence in machines ok that's all there is of course a Million Different Ways to go out
question and you can go out at from computational Angela coding Prospector from a fine grain mill Circuit prospective
do something that's kind of in between the things we can approach in human brains and it's really human intelligence understand I say some
intelligence is lot of it is things that we share with animals but some of it is not and so I think it's important to be able to approach this not just
the perspectives of animal research magnificent as those methods are but also see what we can learn about human brains ok so I'll talk
functional architecture of the human brain what are the basic pieces of the system in the whole get into some some different methods and what they tell us about Facebook
ok so at the most general level we can ask whether human intelligence as people of an asking for century is actually weather human intelligence
the product of a bunch of very special purpose components each optimised to solve a specific problem kind of like this device here
you have a saw for cutting wood scissors for cutting paper swords don't work that well on paper and scissors not work that well on Wood or
human intelligence is the product of some work in a generic all-purpose computational power that makes us generically smart without
optimising ask for any particular tasks and just a force out of the answer as an old questions in psychology the answer is both but will do that in some detail
before we get into that cares and ID say first of all this kind of macro-level question about functional components of the human mind & brain matter
bunch of reasons first of all I just think it's one of the most basic questions we can ask about about ourselves about who we are is to ask what the base of pieces
how far of my second were pragmatically this kind of divide-and-conquer research strategy has been effective in love
Fields that are trying to understand the complex system will you do with this incredibly complex system we just can't even figure out how to get started one sense forward it started is 4
figure out what it's pieces are and then maybe try to figure out help me to the pieces work and then they beat Sunday maybe not in my lifetime figure out how they all work together and some
play the fashion of the pieces are the computations
performed in each of those pieces what the representations extracted in each piece are and I think even just a functional characterization of the scope
particular brand region kinds of computations that go on there it's only find that is a part of the brain that's primarily involved in face for him
night in reading visually presented words recognising centre recognising objects that already gives us some clues about the kinds of complications that would be
appropriate for that scope of task if you tried to write the code to do that you'll be riding three different cone if it only had to do face recognition vs if it also Heads
you recognise so that's my list of the main reasons they prefer heaps so different ways
to investigate this question and mention some of those in the second half but I want to start with spear
who publisher paper in 1904 in the American Journal of psychology this article was sandwiched between a discussion of the saw
an article on the psychology of the English sparrow and in this article Spearman did the following low-tech but fascinating thing
test a whole bunch of kids into different school on a wide variety of different tasks and this included Scholastic achievement type things he got exam grades
student and a bunch of different classes and he measured a whole bunch of other kinds of psychological abilities including some very can soak a physical perceptual discrimination bill
how well can people discriminate the brightness of the loudness of two different tones the brightness of two different flashes of white the weight of 2 different
pieces of stuff and what he found well before it to me what he found it would you expect with us should we expect a correlation between your ability to
two different Wellness is and say you're a math score in grade 5 on a math exam result is
most pairs of housework or later with each other that is if you're good at 1 you're good at the others even pass that seemingly and very little to do with each other
pieces of a whole idea of g which is the general factor in which is the whole idea of IQ and I can testing and in America
the idea of IQ problem with this idea that are very enthusiastic the idea and we have been but aside from all
social uses and miss uses of IQ test the point it was actually a deep Discovery about psychology that Spearman made from the fact that all of these hasrecordid
with each other he didn't know what it was kind of like Gregor Mendel in food chains without knowing anything about molecular biology spearmint just inferred there's something general
the human intellect such that there is a strong correlation spots across ok but less well-known about spearmint
is he also talked about the specific Factor and S with the fact that I will the broad result of his experiments was it most
house for correlated strongly correlated with others and a good fact with those out and discover some mental abilities that weren't just in a Broadleaf
cross subjects and I think this kind of everything that we see with functional MRI there is a lot of specific acids and there's also some
you can see those in different brain regions as I will detail next was invented by from here
think mental faculties that live in different parts of the brain are you but you know call lived in the 1700s and didn't have an MRI machine
so he did the best ticket which wasn't so hard he invented the infamous method of chronology he felt the bombs on the school and tried to release there's two specific
different individuals and from this inferred 27 mental faculties my favourites are amativeness filial piety
cancel all of the right idea but kind of the wrong method and another method that was
a very early one was the method of studying the loss of specific mental abilities after brain damage and so
often credited as being the first experiment whole neuroscientist around making lesions in pigeons and rabbits
I didn't sin then testing them on various things and he didn't really fine much difference in what part of the brain he took out for the mental abilities me that's because he wasn't such a
experimental in only didn't have great experimental methods in any case he argued that all sensory and volitional fact of these exist in the circle
serious and must be regarded as occupying concurrently the same seat at those fractures right and otherwise everything is on top of everything else in the brain
what sort of you know Dominic do for a while people thought gold was kind of a crackpot even though he wrote very popular books and when it
giving popular electricity huge numbers of people attended the respectable intellectual Society didn't take them seriously and
play dear of liquidation of function wasn't taken seriously until Paul broker member of the the French Academy stood up in front of the
Society of anthropology in Paris in 1861 and announced that the left frontal lobe is a sheet of speech in this was based on his patient
was brain is shown here was named and because that was all he could say after damage to his left inferior frontal lobe and broken
the 10 had lots of other mental faculties preserved in it was simply speech that was disrupted in from this was kind of one of the first respectable
are you for localisation of function research and by the end of the 20th century this pretty much of
be sick sensory and motor functions do exhibit localisation of function in the brain there different regions for basic visual processing auditory
and so forth and that was no longer controversial but the functions were localised in distinct parts of the brain
was controversial then and remains controversial now and so is on its function
display the huge role in addressing this question at this kind of macroscopic level and I think you guys know whenever I machinist
how do you spell on Morris for a while it's important measure is a very indirect measure of neural activity by we have a long causal chain
neuron's fire you in metabolic cost and what flow changes to that region blood flow increase
compensates for oxygen use producing a local decrease rather than expected increase in the oxyhaemoglobin relative
what's the humour Goulburn those two are magnetically different that's what the MRI machine to text it's very indirect so it's remarkable it works as well as it does in its current
the best non-invasive method we have in humans are in terms of both special having both Facial Oil special resolution
so worried diving into the details of some of the day to be collected but I'm kissing another projects and are
coming from other Fields of basic form out of the data in a typical functional MRI study is you have tens of thousands of three-dimensional pixels or voxels
that you scan and those typically is sample a whole set once every 2 seconds or so you can put it in
every second or less under special circumstances you can have more voxels by sampling at higher resolution for that's a ballpark of the format of the kind of
you can get a brain activity ok so a few things about the method and it's limitations cause really important in terms of what you can learn from
Samurai and what you can't so first of all this is a timeline my x-axis in those invisible is time in seconds and so if you imagine looking at V1
in presenting a brief seat 10th of the 2nd high contrast flash of a chequerboard neurophysiology is that
within 100 Ms of official onset information gets rid of their really fast the Bold which stands for what oxygenation
dependent or functional MRI response is we lag behind this ok so the Normans are firing way over here in this graph essentially at time
but the MRI response is 6 seconds later ok so it's really slow and that has a bar
supplications about what we can and cannot warrant from it because it's so slow we we can't resolve
steps in a computation for fast systems like vision and hearing and language understanding systems for which we have dedicated
can you read the Tiley efficient where you can recognise the gist of a scene with an a quarter of a second one it flashes on a screen in front of you that and and similarly you
meaning of a sentence or rapidly that you've already purchased might of the sentence in a well before the sentence is over right so these are extremely efficient
mental processes that means the components steps in those mental processes happen over a few tens of MS and were off
play off and temporal resolution with some SlimRight all those things are squashed together on top of each other that's a drag that's just like we can't see those individual components snaps
the second thing is that the special resolution it's the best that we have in humans 9 these of we right now but it's
call compared to what you can do an animals so I miss timber Carlos top yesterday but but those methods are spectacular you can record from individual
Place activity with beautiful time information and contrast functional Andreas like you know the Dark Ages we have
hundreds of thousands of Lawrence in each bottle so the real Miracle of functionally Mariah is we ever see anything at all rather than just
it's because you're something over so many her on that once and it's just a lucky fact of the organisation of the human free and that you have cluster Rings of neuron's with similar
responsible activities and similar functions at such a macro brand that you can see some stuff with functional MRI although you miss a lot as well
important limit the function lamerough that comes out of just a consideration of the the method measures is that you can
really see differences between conditions with Vauxhall Andre the magnitude of the MRI response in a voxel at a time point is meaningless it might be
563 that's all it means nothing is nothing it's just the breaking of the intensity of mama I said no the only way to make it mean something is
imperator something else usually two different house or two different stimuli and so you can go far with that but it's important to realise you can train it translated into any
absolute measure of neural activity it's only a relative measure of strength of neural activity between two different two or more different conditions
turn the final in a deep limitation that function on the right is that we don't use this convenient phrase normal activity is very convenient cuz it's extremely
fittingly so because we don't know exactly what kind of neural activity is driving the ball response it could be spikes for action potentials it could be sacked it's
activity that doesn't lead to spikes it could be tonic inhibition it could be all kinds of different things anything that's metabolically expensive is likely to increase
what's the response in practice when people have looked at it it's very nicely correlated with firing rate it with some you no bumps
Caviar so you can never be totally sure but there's it's a pretty good proxy for firing rate you just need to remember the back of your mind that it could be other stuff too
very important caveat is that function and write like like most other methods were just recording the royal activity in a variety of different ways your chest
you're not intervening and that means you're not measuring the causal role of the things you measure and that's very important because it could be that everything you measure is just
the Abbey phenomenon has absolutely nothing to do with behaviour so I'm practice it's unlikely that you have all the systematic stuff for no reason but you need to come
find that functioning right is not a forwards no window at all into the causal role of different regions for that you need to compliment with other methods
despite all these limitations I think he has had a huge impact on the field and in admittedly I'm biased but I think it's one of these things were as it happened
you know we can still use to a result the minute it gets published as I go yeah right reviews to step back so
me to point of pictures to to show you why I think this is important ok here is Penfield map functional map of the human brain published in 1957
I was born and he has sex Callum sex functional regions labelled in their you probably can't see them but it's the basic sensory and motor regions
cortex auditory cortex motor cortex speech and broca's area in then my favourite is this word that is appreciative
OK anyway this is Beast on electrical recording and stimulation in patients with epilepsy undergoing brands
actually a very powerful method but that's where it's at he published this near the end of his career and that's nice but it's pretty rudimentary ok now
what's a 1990 immediately before the advent advent of Funk Samurai and I really could the black outlines are the basic sensory and motor regions
my bad at a couple of big colour logs for regions of head that identified by setting patients with brain damage so you know even from Broken wernicke was known
regions were involved in language cause people with damage their lost the language abilities you get waxed in your pride a little you have weird attention problems like
turn the left out of space and stuff like if you have damaged somewhere of the back end of the right hemisphere as you might lose face recognition ability these things were known by around 1990
might else that's basically the functional map of the brain 1990 ok that's probably a lot of you but not for me ok here we are today
what particular part of the human brain which have been who's function
it's been quite precisely in the sense that we know the precise circuits in there or that we can very precise the characterized the representations are
what are the events that we know that our region may be very selectively involved for example in thinking about what other people are thinking of
remarkable result that Rebecca saxe we discovered it will tell you about when she's here next week ok so that was completely unknown even 15 years ago
lower back in 1990 and likewise most of these other regions were known only in either known in the blue area sense or not with this Precision so I think even though
is very limited in its kind of step 0 in trying to understand the human brain I think it's important progress and I think to push the little farther
see this as an admittedly very blurry but still a picture of the architecture of human intelligence what are the basic pieces what is it we have in here to work with when we think
we have this basic pieces up once more that hasn't been discovered yet and a lot more than we need to know about each of these and how they interact and all of that but you know a reasonable
so that's my story year or pay for fun this is me with a bunch of functional regions identified in my
cancel there are you man I'm making here is of the human mind and bring contains a set of Highly specialised components each solving a different specific problem
and that each of these regions is present in essentially every normal person is just part of the basic architecture of the human mind and brain
this view is pretty simple but none the last it's often confused with a whole bunch of other things that people think of the same thing and that
so it's starting to drive me and since I'm going to take 5 minutes and go through the things this does not mean and ok I hope this doesn't insults
it's amazing how in the current literature in the field people complete these things ok so I'm talking about functional specificity which is depression of whether this particular region
is engaged in pretty selectively and just that particular mental process and not lots of other mental processes that's what I mean by function specificity that's a different
an anatomical specificity and a timer called specificity would say it is only this region that's involved and nothing else isn't form that's a different question
how specific is this region vs are the other regions that do something similar also an interesting question but a different one
so if any of it doesn't make sense just freezer handle ok another ideas the necessity of a brain region for a particular from
that's actually what we really want to know where the functional specificity question is not just doesn't only turn on when you do x but do you absolutely need it for xx
that's actually a Central question that's that closely connected to it really part of functional specificity is a causal question
different for the question of sufficiency and Regent sufficient for a mental process
it's just kind of a confused idea that would mean we excise my face area we put it in a dish keep all the door answer lifeforce pretend we could do that I'm sure it
to figure out how to do that in a weekend we have this thing alive and it's fish can it do face recognition the information
information doesn't get out and inform the rest of a brand it's not doesn't hell is a face person rates of you need things to be connected up
parts of the brain regions to be involved so let's distinguish with a different region is functionally specific for a process from whether it's sufficient for the whole process of course
I need you guys would never say anything so dumb question of conductivity rates
people often say oh well this this region is part of a network period my reaction is like
everything is part of a network in no way does that engage with the question of whether that region is foxley specific great a functional specific region of course is
turn that worker talk to other brain regions those other bring readers made play an important role in it's processing sure at the very least the necessary for getting the information in and out
music the final thing that people confuse with functional specificity is an anus
it's a very different concept just because we have some printicular part of the brain for which we make it really strong evidence that it's very specifically involved in
that's cool that's important that's completely orthogonal to how it got wired up and whether it's innately specified in the Genome bad hole
or whether that circuit is instructed by experienced overdevelopment or as in the usual case very complicated combinations of this still ok so just
Tulip functional specificity is a different question from the neatness are in one where you can see that very clearly is to consider the case of the visual word form area
but which I'll show you some theatre in the moment the visual word for area responds selectively to words and letter strings in orthography you know
not an orthography you don't know it's very anatomically stereotyped mine is approximately right there and so was yours and your brain
and it response to orthographies you know if you can read Arabic in Hebrew your result response when you look at words and Arabic and Hebrew if you can it doesn't for
the whole lot less ok so that's a function of your individual experience not your answers experience it has strong functional specificity and yet it's function space
is not in this idea that I'm taking out here has become a popular 322 of course we have specialist components
off all I hear is from my textbook started on this very stupid idea that very complex traits for associated with the script free regions
modern research was really nice that a single bring me bring regionally participated more than one function built in the Hedge workmate so we can really have a fight but it was founded
is different view Lisa Feldman Barrett I haven't met her but she's driving me insane most recently by proclaiming all kinds of things at the
times just a few weeks ago quote in general the given region has a distinct psychological purpose
great while she's got heads for it's in general I will have his words but she's basically which is reasoning from the fact that her dad are suggested specific
turn the store in habit specific brain regions from the idea that the whole brain has no localisation of function
I hope that you will stop is past of these arguments because my favourite this old coot all I know this can be on the way but here I am carrying on is
let's go cracks me up every kind of going after a functional brain
green images that report single areas of activation exclusively associated with a particular cognitive process should be our Fury considered to be artefact of the arbitrary threshold set by
together and seriously question is just
the we shouldn't get in the theatre proclaimer opinions that are that speak to it so let me show you some of mine
ok so what would the evidence of functional specificity of ways of doing it the way I like to do it is something called the functional region of interest
the the problem is that over there a very systematic regularities in the functional organisation of the brain each of these regions
approximately the same location in each normal subject the actual location varies a bit from subject to subject so if you do the standard thing of a whining
the average of the Cross of you get a lot of much and there isn't much much in each subject individually and so the deal with that problem it's a girl with a bunch of other problems
something called the functional region of interest method and that means if you want to study a given region you'll find it in that subject individually and then once you found it it with
what country do you want to find a face region you find a region that responds when people look at this is them when they look it up Jax now you've found it in that subject it's these 85 boxes right there and that's
now we run a new experiment to test more interesting questions about it and we measure the response in those ones that also has the advantage that the date are you play
look at is independent of the way you found this one source a very important problem in a lot of functional neuroimaging where people have non-independent statistical problems with the datanalysis
if you have a functional region of interest that's localised independently of the day to look at in it you get out of that problem it's also a huge benefit as one of the
problems with functional brain imaging which I think is led to the fact that a large percentage of the publisher imaging findings are probably noise is
is too many degrees of freedom you have tens of thousands of assholes you have a lose of different places to look and ways to analyse your data one of the things I love dearly about the
region of interest method is that you tie your hands in a really good way right so your ears specifying Avance exactly where you're going to look
any specify exactly how you're going to quantify the response and see you have no degrees of freedom and I'll give you a huge detestable advantage and it means they're less likely to be in it
publishing papers on noise here is just with loads of these experiments here just from a current experiment
nothing conducted by Zeinab vegan she's actually looking at conductivity of different brand regions using a different method I probably won't have time to talk about it's very cool but in the process
all motor functions localises in so we can look in her Dieter at the response of the fusiform face area conditions ok so these are a bunch of auditory language
cancel Ok not too surprising it doesn't respond very much to those who presented auditorily for these are all this will stimuli here the two yellow bars are faces
drawings of faces this is video clips colour video clips of faces from responses to both and all of these other conditions
movies of objects movies of see in scrambled objects word scrambles words body's response is so
I would say this is pretty strong selectivity it's fantastic against the last of alternatives only a tiny percent of which are shown here as I mentioned before
more or less the same place and pretty much every normal subject I think it's just basic kiss of mental architecture now this is a very simple universe
we're just measuring the very cruising of the overall magnitude of samurai response in that region to these conditions there are legitimate counter arguments
call Midas you I put in force and we should consider them I think the most important one comes from pattern analysis methods which I will talk about if I get there
and importantly these data don't tell us about the possible that region will return to those however
pointers before we lightly say it's not fashionable to talk about punctual specificity we need counter arguments today like this the pretty strong
that's just one example to show you just a few others from paper ok so this is what I just showed you but I'm in the sea
experiment we can look at other brain regions of this is a bottom surface of the of the brain there so this is a acceptable pool
add bottom of the temporal lobe that these areas are region in yellow in the subject this purple region is that there's a word for area that I mentioned and here is it's response magnitude
alcohol might of subjects localising in an independently testing the purple bars are when subjects are looking at who presented words and again all the
conditions faces objects bodies scenes listening to words all of those things much lower response ok in the same
we can also look at a set of regions that respond to speech I mentioned was very briefly in my introduction few days ago these are regions a number of people have found
in this case what was the immediately below lateral to primary auditory cortex in humans interesting
which way to break between primary auditory cortex and language sensitive regions break between is a set of regions that respond to the sounds of speech Ok
sense of language for the sounds of speech and so this is when people are just people are saying stuff like bother Garbutt
St Andrews when they're tapping their fingers in a systematic order here is when they're listening to sentences
importantly this is when they're listening to Jabberwocky darling it's meaningless ok so no meaning but phonemes same response that's what tells us
sweeteners involved in processing the sounds of speed not the content of language and load everything else so other things moving outside of perception
you might ok fine perception is an inherently modular processes different kinds of perceptual problems that make sense of all cognition we wouldn't really have
function specificity for that but oh yes we do here are some language regions there's a bunch of them in the temporal and frontal lobe that I've been known since
broker but now with functional MRI we can identify them in individual subjects and go back and repeatedly query them and say are they involved in all of these other mental prayer
so this is now the response in a language reason so identified her as a response when you're listening to sentences this is when you're listening to
Rocky Johnson strings here is when you're saying but I gotta go it's not a speech sounds here is when you're listening to synthetically decompose
speech sounds that are acoustically very similar to the Jabberwocky speech it's just not interested in those things it seems to be interested in something more like the meaning of a sentence
is to show you some other data we have on this this is Dave from if Federico who has tested this region Elsa sort of roughly broca's area
on the main mental functions that people have argued overlap in the brain with language nearly sorry so probably
see hear a bit arithmetic so we have difficult and easy mental arithmetic intact and scrambled music in pink a bunch of
memory tasks special working memory and verbal working memory and a bunch of cognitive control of attention demanding pass where you have to switch between
stop my fat and here is the response profile in that region reading sentences reading all of those other tasks but the difficult
easy version that's extreme functional specificity everything to be done but
where is Paz querying of those language engage in all these other things that people fortnite overlap with language the answer is no
an interest and I think that's really deep and an interesting cause it means that you know this this basic question that we all do not start asking ourselves when we were young
what is the relationship between language and fight with me somewhere on this that's good she's very articulate and she doesn't feel the difference between an ID
and it's articulation I'm less articulate it's very obvious to me the different things and discuss but
I think there is a vast golf between the two and that all many different aspects of cognition procedures fine without language regions
stronger evidence for that comes not from these functions Lima I did it's breaking as I think they are but from patient data so Rosemary Varley in England
contesting Pistols with will the theatre this is a very tragic horrible thing that happens in patients who have massive left hemisphere strokes but pretty much take out
change the Oliveira language abilities those people she has shown are intact in their navigation abilities their arithmetic abilities
ability to solve logic problems their ability to think about what other people are thinking their ability to appreciate music and so on and so far
I think this is really a very big difference between a major part of the system that you need to understand the meaning of a sentence and all of those other aspects of
this is just showing you what I mean by functional specificity what the evidence for the basic 4th order evidence is and these are just the Regency we happen have in the
make a new favourite for want of other perceptual and cognitive functions people have down quite specific brain regions for perceiving bodies and scenes
pause motion the area code for a long time regions that are quite Hoyt specifically involved in processing shape we've been studying colour processing
Kitchens recently there's not a selected for colour or some of these other regions with the very anatomically consistent and
before my brief introduction are regions that are specifically involved in processing pitch information music information and it still here next week from a Rebecca
are period mind or thinking about other people farts and so there's quite a litany of of mental functions that have brain
quote specifically engaged that mental function and each of these two very in degrees but you know some appreciable degree have corroborating evidence
how's that specific deficit so that shows that you should these has is likely to be activated during but causally involved in
mental functions and there are actually good counter arguments to some of the things I've been making that are worth discussing I think the pattern analysis stata
is the strongest that's to say
where we are now the counter arguments but list talk about all there's no localisation of function in the brain you got engaged with this effort and give me a serious counter argument
ok I want to say that it's not like that there are there the big red patches we haven't figured out
what's the weather on so substantial patches that are already been shown to be in some sense the opposite of this region in almost any different
you do apple and I think there's a very interesting part of the whole story of the architecture of intelligence I'm going to take 5 minutes and tell you about it this work is primarily the word
Duncan in England and he's been pointing out for about 15 years that there are regions in the frontal lobe
that are engaged in pretty much any difficult task until any time you increase the difficulty of a task whether it's perceptual or high-level cognitive
does Regents turn on differentially all different kinds of demand
Duncan are related to fluid intelligence so remember Spearman why started with who talks about the the general fact
thanks that basically this is the seat of g these regions here to him for his argument
and what is strongly activated when you do a classic g loading house that's not that surprising their activity and all that remains of house more interesting
you did a large piece of study where they found easier so patients in their Northside patients in the database and they identified the low
Locus of the brain damage in each of those patients post-injury IQ they estimated from a variety of sources pre-injury Ike
they asked how much does your IQ go down after brain damage as a function of 1 the volume of tissue you lost brain damage and two
Lucas if you're in these regions your IQ goes down if you will
where you may become paralysed or a physical or Proserpine nosek you don't lose your IQ does not go down
ghoulish calculation that you lose points for every 10 cubic centimetres of this region of Cortex
and almost nothing for for the rest of the brain so you can get some but I think it's
intriguing and so his suggestion is that in addition to these highly specialised cortical regions that we use for these these particular important house we also have this
general purpose machinery that makes us generically smart and we've tested this more seriously analyses for channel
in collaboration with him with individuals direct analyses the most precise measurements we could make and boy as he right I mean he's even to the box or you can find these
engaged in 708 very very different kinds of cognitive demand all activate the same fossil differentially so the basics
7/4 without the whole thing that is that is that macroscale the architecture of human intelligence
special purpose beds for a small if number of important mental functions are not all of them and maybe some of them addition we have some general purpose
there's no more that we don't know from the precise computations that go on in these things to their conductivity to
you know the actual precise representations that you can see with an error code if you could measure it which we can't in humans to the timing of the interactions which of them
play Human which of them are also present in monkeys and I don't but what are the things we've been doing recently is looking in the
halfway at the organisation of feast police and coal selectivity and what we see is that weird
double Conway and Russell bevel in rose I have previously shown that on the lateral surface in the monkey you have three bands of selectivity
so it goes face selectivity and selectivity play selectivity in three bands on the side of the temple open monkeys we find as in human
the same organisation in the same but it's rolled around on the ventral surface of the brain in the same order face colour place on the bottom of the brain
southall bright region is homologous between monkeys and humans it just rolled around the bottom he got pushed
not exactly another argument actually been record of people suggesting this a while back and I think you're starting to see those two mollog's and the reason it's important is it is it all the
questions we desperately want to answer about the inner causal role conductivity population codes interactions between
developments Oliver that we can't answer very well in humans and answer in monkeys and after a break people tell you fat